Heat.
[Music]
Heat. N.
Heat up here.
Well, hello, good evening, good day
everybody and welcome to this special
session of Askabit.
Maybe an 8 hour session. Let's see how
it goes. First time I'm ever doing
something this long. I hope everyone is
doing great. Let me see who is there on
the live chat. I've got my screen over
here. I'll see you all over here. So
let's see who is there. I can see Suraj
Johawan Ajinti Arand Hensi Penguin
Geopolitical Dubai Binit Abu Singh Suhas
Reddi Aayush Singh Iistic Saga Torat
Ashish Singh Dave Shivasai Vladimir
Putin Mama Baket VFX Duv Durya Shashank
Koshik Jak Shri Krishna Vishwendra Singh
Mystic SK Satish Chawan Nutan Roshan
Random Shorts Shri Jawahar Lal Nehu
Ashwani Dur Singh Sagar Toat Hensy
Penguin
Suman Shakar Sarangi Mayang Monk random
shots Achinti Anand Geopolitical Dubet
is here. Satish Chawhan who else do we
have? Rudra Pragya Niranjan Ajintaran
Pratik Vora Rudra once again Dave Dark
Knight 5:30 a.m. Where Dark Dark Knight
is Aush Singh, Mayang Binit Abijit M
Shivasai, Arouch Rana, Kotilia, Rishi
MK, Ashish Singh, Muhammad, Faison,
Shatish, Johawan, UC Dib, Kumar, Minit,
Yadav, Brlavin,
Shanks, Konicha, Konicha, Bender, Upada,
Adwit Meta, Dakshia, Vil, Na, Sharas,
Mitra from Moscow, Moscow. All right,
sir. Satellite from Goa. Swami Nathan
Ayar Kula Oji Nutan Roshan Vikash PJ Tox
Dharma Anahita Gorabka Priyanka Javalia
Shrih Hari Arun Mahi Shishta Archan
Vikas PJ Pratik Tagare Vnav Dates
Swaminatan Shrihari Amish Mishra one of
two LR ng RWRP
Suraj from Bangalore
and untriggered Mama Bakit Tanesh Pandi
Namit Nabarita Das
Kichi Shanks Wada GRS Vin Yadav
everybody else everybody else all right
uh Sam Puskar
okay I guess everyone is here
untriggered Alan J Victor sentin SP
Tarun Beneath Priyani Sud Mayank
Samulkar from Twitter from X
okay so today let us discuss everything
anything and everything everything goes
You can ask me anything. I'll discuss
anything you want. You want to talk
history, you want to talk geopolitics,
you want to talk science. It's been a
long long time since we did any science
live streams. I used to do a lot of
those, but these days we doing that that
uh Niha from Xinping Ashwani says, "Are
you working on any physics research?"
I'm working on writing a book on black
holes. So that you can say is kind of
physics research. And I get a lot of
questions in the comments at least about
physics, about black holes and stuff.
But because I'm not doing live streams
about physics these days, that's why I'm
not able to take the questions. I
remember there there's this gentleman
called Rahul Dunaki who asks about black
holes. I mean uh uh what's it look like
when you fall into a black hole? That
sort of thing. So I'll be happy to
answer questions like that. Would you
like me to take a question about black
holes? So for example, okay, let's start
with black holes. I'll take everybody's
questions 8 hours. So no hurry. Let's
answer the question about what does it
look like? How does it feel when you
fall inside a black hole? Black holes
are the most extreme objects in the
universe. What's it feel like when you
What do you see when you fall into a
black hole? Right? Have you ever thought
about it? The effects are incredible. So
if you So let me read out from my book,
The Astronaut's Last Journey. What does
that look like? Okay, let's let's read
out and then we'll take other questions.
So
let's read this out. The astronaut's
final journey. What follows isn't
fiction. The physics is precise. The
calculations exact. The predictions
absolute. No dragons are here. Just
mathematics which might be worse. So
while physicists argue about frozen
stars and coordinate systems, while
mathematicians debate singularities and
infinities, Dr. Singh, our brave
astronaut falls towards the super
massive black hole Sagittarius A star
and he translates their equations into
experience. The universe's ultimate
revelation written in light and time.
Looking back at the cosmos that he is
leaving behind, not forward toward the
darkness, but backward towards the
stars, he witnesses reality itself
violating every rule evolution has
taught us to expect. The stars don't
simply recede. They begin to burn with
impossible colors. This isn't the
peaceful stargazing of a summer night.
This is the universe revealing its
capacity for extremes, showing how the
gentle starlight that once inspired
poets becomes near a black hole
something altogether more fierce. As Dr.
Singh falls deeper into the black hole's
gravitational well, the stars above piff
towards blue like a cosmic symphony
climbing towards higher notes. That red
super giant that is studied in graduate
school, it now blazes white hot. The
yellow star that resembles our sun, it
burns with the blue flame of the hottest
stars known. This isn't an illusion. The
light truly gains energy as it falls
into the gravity well behind him. Its
wavelength is compressed and its
frequency rises. The process that
physicists call gravitational blue
shifting transforms the entire
electromagnetic spectrum. Radio waves
become in become visible light. Visible
light becomes ultraviolet. The cosmic
microwave background that faint echo of
the big bang that baits the universe at
a tiny 2.7 Kelvin warms and brightens
until it glows like sunset. Dr. Singh is
watching the universe is baby picture
develop into something unrecognizable.
All because gravity has compressed the
light's wavelength. But the
transformation of color pales before the
transformation of time. Through
gravitational time dilation, Dr. Singh
watches the outside universe accelerate
like a film with its speed control
broken. The stars wheeling overhead
complete orbits that should take
millennia in what his watch calls
minutes. Stellar nurseries birth new
suns between his heartbeats. Red giants
exhaust their fuel and collapse while he
takes a breath. He's not traveling to
the future. The future is racing past
him. The universe aging rapidly while he
falls for what feels like hours. This
isn't science fiction's time travel.
This is time itself re revealing its
flexibility, showing that it flows at
different rates for different observers.
The black hole has made Dr. Singh the
sole witness for the universe's
accelerated history. The view itself
shrinks with every passing second,
compressed by aberration. The same
effect that makes raindrops streak
toward your windshield when you drive.
The entire observable universe once
spread across the sky in magnificent
panorama crowds into an o ever smelling
smaller circle above him. Stars that
were separated by vast angles now
clustered together. Constellations
collapse into bright points. The Milky
Way's grand spiral compresses into a
brilliant disc. It's as if someone were
slowly closing an iris above him. The
universe visible through an increasingly
narrow aperture. Around this shrinking
window, darkness spreads. Not the
darkness of empty space with its
scattered scars, but the absolute
darkness of spaceime curved so severely
that light cannot traverse it. The
universe is becoming a spotlight, then a
flashlight, then a laser pointer aimed
from above. Dr. Singh crosses the event
horizon at 10:16 by his watch and
nothing happens. No barrier stops him.
No sensation marks the transition. No
alarm sounds. The event horizon, that
boundary that seems so dramatic from
outside, passes without the slightest
recognition from inside. He can still
see out. The event horizon only pre
prevents departure, not arrival. Light
from the universe continues streaming in
after him, following him down towards
the singularity. The shrinking circle of
blue-shifted stars still blazes above,
now compressed into a tiny disc of
impossible brightness. Dr. Singh has
crossed history's most irreversible
boundary, and he did not feel a thing.
The event horizons drama is entirely for
external observers. For those who cross
it, it's as unremarkable as walking
through a doorway. Inside the black
hole, still looking outward, Dr. Singh
becomes the sole audience for the
cosmos's greatest and most extreme
transformation. The entire external
crosscossmos, every galaxy, every star,
every photon that will ever fall toward
the black hole, compresses into a
brilliant point directly over overhead.
This isn't metaphor. It's the literal
geometric consequence of how light paths
bend in the black holes interior. All of
external spacetime, all of history and
future appears through a pinhole that
shrinks towards nothing. The light from
this cosmic pin pinpoint blue shifts
beyond blue, beyond ultraviolet, beyond
X-rays. In principle, he is seeing the
entire future history of the universe
compressed in his final moments. Every
event that will ever happen outside
playing out in accelerated time, blue
shifted into a single point of infinite
brightness. Around this brilliant point,
absolute darkness reigns. Not the
darkness of night, not the darkness of
empty space, but the darkness of
spacetime itself funneling towards the
singularity. He is inside a region where
every direction leads to the same
destination, where the future itself has
been geometrically redirected toward a
single point. This darkness isn't empty.
It's full of curved spacetime, of
geometry twisted beyond recognition, of
physics pushed to its breaking point. In
a stellar mass black hole, tidal forces
would already have torn him apart,
stretching him into a stream of atoms in
a process physicists call with rare
whimsy spaghettification.
But in Sagittarius a star, massive
enough that tidal forces remain gentle
until near the singularity, he has
minutes to contemplate the view that no
human was ever meant to see. That
profound paradox crystallizes in these
final moments. While outside observers
calculate that he takes infinite time to
reach the event horizon, within he
experiences perhaps an hour from the
horizon to the singularity. He carries
the image of the external universe with
him to oblivion, watching it evolve at
an ever accelerating pace until that
final point of light represents not just
the stars he knew, but everything that
will ever be in the future. The black
hole doesn't hide the universe from the
following astronaut. It shows him
everything all at once in an
overwhelming crescendo of light that
ends in absolute darkness. This is how a
journey ends when spacetime itself has
torn not with a wall or a barrier but
with the universe compressed to a point
time accelerated to infinity and physics
pushed beyond meaning. Right? That's the
deal. That is the final passage of book
two of volume two of my black hole
series. I hope it throws some light on
what it feels like. what it what what
you see when you fall inside a black
hole. I don't think anyone has thought
of this question or or has answered this
question beyond equations and
mathematics. So that's what I have done
in this book. So the book that I'm
referring to is this one here. It is
this one. This book here it's the second
volume in the series that I'm writing
the black hole chronicles. The first one
is called Dark Stars to Black Holes. So
this is available on Amazon Kindle right
now. When all the entire series is
complete, I would publish it as a p as
as a physical book. Right now it's
available only as uh Kindle ebook. So
the links are in the description. If you
want to check it out, do check it out.
I'll be very pleased if you do. Right.
So that's about black holes. We start
with a question about physics and black
holes. Something that is always fun for
me. Now let's take some questions. Uh
that okay, Dnur Singh is active and lots
of people active. Okay, let's take some
questions. Uh, Dimnor Singh says, "Why
why is the Russian emblem the same as
the infamous Rothschild family emblem?
Exactly the same with no difference."
Interesting question. Let's let's check
out what the Russian national emblem is.
Uh, let me see. Um, let me let's let's
let's find out. Let's discover this
together. Let's go to our friend Google
and let's see the Russian emblem.
Okay. Russian emblem.
The Russian emblem. The Russian Russian
National Court of Arms. It's an eagle
holding a skepter in its right claw and
an orb in the left claw. So this is the
Russian national emblem. And Dnour says
that the Rothil family emblem. Let's
see. Rothfield
family
emblem. What is that? Oh well. Oh well.
There seems to be a significant uh
similarity of some kind. It's very
similar. But one could perhaps argue
it's not the exactly the same thing. But
it's an interesting question that Dnur
Singh is asking us. Sir, I I don't know.
See, I have not really studied the
history of the Roshield family, the
Roshill dynasty. I've heard a lot of uh
talk about this this family that it's
supposedly the most powerful family in
the world. the richest family dynasty in
the world and apparently they control
the entire world. They may be the deep
state or something. I'm not entirely
sure. That is one part one portion of
history that I'm not really dipped into.
So can't say uh it is said that the
Bolshevik revolution was also
orchestrated perhaps by the Russians.
That's what I've heard. Uh but I haven't
personally studied it myself. So I don't
really know the answer. But you are
quite right. If you look at the two
there seems to be a striking
resemblance. So yeah, maybe there is
more than than meets the eye here. Who
knows?
Okay, Richard says, "Was the Russian
drone incursions into Poland's airspace
a test for some future plans? And what's
the NATO response going to be like?"
So a few days ago, uh there was all this
news on social media that Russia has
attacked Poland. Russia has launched
drone strikes in Poland, which is
obviously misleading. It was all
incorrect. Uh but it looks like some
Russian drones may have crossed into
Poland's airspace for some time. Uh that
may be possible that may have happened.
Uh was this a test for future plots? If
if it if it did indeed happen then this
could possibly been have been a test or
to see the kind of reaction that you get
from Poland. Poland a member of NATO.
What's going to be the reaction like
from Poland and what's going to be the
broader reaction from NATO? So that if
you if you test that then it kind of
gives you an the ability to gorge future
actions depending on the response time
and the kind of response the severity of
the resp response how high does it go up
the escalation chain and all of that
what's the NATO response going to be
like nothing they'll talk they'll do
some saber rattling but because there's
been no uh strike on Polish soil on
Polish territory or on Polish assets
there's nothing really that that NATO
can do beyond perhaps doing an incursion
by air into Russian airspace possibly.
So that's about it. Until you actually
attack physically a member of NATO,
nothing really happens. I mean, nothing
should happen. A violation of airspace
which is brief is is it can be looked
upon as an accident and it doesn't
require uh an escalatory response. So
yeah, I think the situation is in under
control.
Tanmayesh Pand says that feminists claim
that Einstein stole the work of his wife
Mleva Marik but there's no proof of this
of her even helping him. Matilda effect
is real but is this but this is false.
Look I haven't looked into his his his
personal life history. His wife was
indeed a mathematician or physicist and
she did help him it is said with some
proofreading and and and verifying his
papers while they were still married.
Eventually they got divorced and
Einstein remarried. So there are claims
there are these persistent claims that
maleva marit should played a significant
role in Einstein doing all the work that
he did. 1905 was his anus miraabilis in
which he published five groundbreaking
papers that totally totally
revolutionalized the world of physics.
For example the photoelectric effect
that he that paper that he published in
1905 before he published that paper the
world did not believe that atoms
existed. Today we take atoms for granted
right until Einstein published the paper
on the photoelectric effect in 1905
nobody believed in atoms right so
so to what extent was she responsible if
at all for his work I suppose look I if
she was that good then she would have
published on her own independently after
they after they got divorced right if if
she was if he was that good but how is
it that she was only a good physicist
This is as long as she was married to
him and she was apparently helping him.
How come she did nothing after that? So
I don't know the circumstances that she
went through after the divorce. I
suppose that once he got the Nobel
Prize, he gave a substantial part of the
money to her in exchange for her her
agreeing to the divorce, that sort of
thing. So it's not like she would have
been in poverty or anything. So I am not
sure. Look, there are all these stories
that go around especially when it comes
to famous people. And uh I personally
have seen no evidence that Einstein
stole her work or it was all her work
and it was credit credited to Einstein.
I don't think that's the case. I don't
know if it's something to do with
feminism or what. But as far as I
understand from whatever I have read and
studied, I haven't seen anything that
leads me to the kind of conclusion that
these people are drawing. So yeah,
that's what I can say.
Godliness says, does the fear of regime
change allow the government to stay
blind to vandalism? Central cabinet
under the constitution is blind is bind
is bound to maintain law and order.
Desecration of for red of the red fort
was heart wrecking.
The desecration of the red fort that's
2019 when some individuals climbed the
red fort and and brought down the Indian
flag and put something else up that sort
of thing. Um does the fear of regime
change? Look, isn't it important that
this government stays in power or is it
important to give give vent to emotional
um to to let off emotional steam? So I
know it's it's very unfortunate that
somebody climbed the red foot and and
pulled the Indian flag down, but it's a
symbolic gesture, right? Did it hurt the
country in any way?
Ask yourself whatever would have
happened if the government had taken
strong action like you want like many
people want many people were really
upset. I think the whole country was
very upset. So I completely agree what
you agree with your sentiments. I
understand totally your sentiment. Now
imagine this imagine the government had
dispatched the police. The police was
there but imagine the government had
ordered the police to take action
physical action and stop these people
from doing whatever they're doing. So
there's a bunch of people there at the
red ford in that area maybe 100 to maybe
thousand or whatever the number was they
were trying to create a problem and if
if the police goes and does a lat charge
and these people have come with
bulldozers and they try to bulldoze the
police then the police may have to
resort to tear gas firing they still
don't stop then what do you do you know
fire fire bullets what if someone gets
killed the moment someone gets killed or
even shot and injured and bleeding then
the entire world's media will portray
India
as a fascist nation
that is not allowing people to
demonstrate and then because these
people claim to represent the farmers
protest and they represent supposedly
represent farmers then it will alienate
farmers across the country because
Indians are illiterate people Indians
don't understand anything they will
think that the government is anti-farmer
that's the kind of propaganda that will
be spread and then you may have genuine
farmer revolutions coming up or or
protest coming up coming up across the
country is Is that what you want? Do you
want the whole country to be in chaos?
Sometimes you to swallow the insults.
This is something that everybody has to
understand in life. Not just the
government of India, every individual.
Sometimes people will try to provoke
you.
Sometimes they will try to provoke you
by insulting you and by by by trying to
hurt your honor, your sense of honor and
and self-esteem.
And the objective is to make you act in
a way that is detrimental to your own
interests. So, what should you do?
Should you just give vent to your
emotions and do what you feel like
because yeah, they they've insulted me
or should you just tell them to
take a hike. I don't care. Keep doing
what you want. I'll not respond. Who who
wins ultimately? You win, right? So, I
think the government did the right
thing. The all the heartbreaking blah
blah is all fine. But the country is
doing well, right? Imagine there was a
godamned color revolution in India
because Mr. Modi said take strict strict
action against these protesters. That's
what that's that was the objective. The
Dilly Ray, the Shahinbug thing, all
these protests and blocking roads for
months and all. They wanted the
government to make a mistake. This sort
of mistake and the government did the
right thing by not giving them what they
wanted. All right.
Teen Talks Dharma says, "What does
Chernobyl taught today's nuclear
scientists?" What did what did Chernobyl
teach today's nuclear scientists? See,
Chernobyl was an engineering accident.
It was not a nuclear physics accident.
See, when when let's say you have a
vehicle, you've got a car and the engine
explodes for for whatever reason. Is
that a physics accident or is there an
engineering? Who who will you call a
physicist to come and fix it or will you
call a car mechanic to fix it?
Engineering is applied physics. A
nuclear reactor is an engineering
problem. It's not a physics problem.
Okay. Of course that is very high
cutting edge engineering which means
that you will have physicists who are
available in a nuclear reactor to look
at various parameters and all that. The
question is what did Chernobyl teach
you?
It taught that
it taught nuclear engineers nuclear
reactor engineers that you need to have
very high standards of safety. You
cannot have uh laxity of standards. You
cannot cut corners. uh you need to have
redundancy and safeguards and all that.
So the reason what was the reason why
this happened? There was a series of
escalating failures and these failures
were detected but they were disregarded
right and the engineering the design of
the reactor itself had some issues. So
all of that is what caused the
catastrophe. It was a series of events
that put together led to a a situation
where the where the reactor had no exp
had no choice but to explode. Uh so the
lesson to be learned is that don't make
those engineering mistakes and the
reactor safety design has the reactor
safety standards have to be improved and
the Soviet Union learned from that.
Russia has learned from that. You have
not seen a single accident in Russia
after that or the USSR. Uh you had some
nuclear accidents after that. Fukushima
was a great example, a terrible example
actually what 2011 but that was nothing
to do with the the kind of thing that
happened in Chernobyl. That was because
of the earthquake and the and the and
the tsunami. So Chernobyl teaches you
that you have to be really serious about
your safety standards and you need to
have well-trained staff who will
recognize the earliest signs of danger
and shut the goddamn thing down.
Divor Singh says should India have its
own conservatives, liberals,
libertarians? Why do we need to copy the
US? Why do we have to do to ape
everything the west does? So because the
west has a right wing and a left wing
and a center wing, why should we also
have it? Why don't we have our own
system? Right? We had our own system.
Look, I'll tell you historically what we
had historically going back to the Vic
age, we only had even in the Vic age.
See we are told that we had Hinduism and
then Janism and Buddhism and Sikism and
whatever other isms came as different
religions. The truth is that during the
Vic age you had lots of different
traditions in India. Lots of different
traditions, lots of different gods,
goddesses which were not originally Vic.
But after the victory in the battle of
the 10 kings, everything was brought
together into one single uh tradition
and that was the Vic system. All gods
were welcome. You may have your own
local village god or goddess. You may
have your mountain spirits. We're going
to welcome them all into the Vic system.
So that's what was done several thousand
thousand years ago. And then because
India was a very pluralistic diverse
society, lots of different philosophical
schools of thought thought emerged.
Naya, mimmansa, vdanta, sananka, yoga,
um charvaka, all of these they are very
very different schools of thought with
very different worldviews. Each of these
represents a certain model of the
universe and its workings. Right? And
for example, Charvaka is pure
materialism. There are certain schools
of thought that that don't believe in
the existence of God. There are some
schools of thought that believe in the
existence of a supreme god. Some believe
in the existence of the of the immortal
soul. Some don't. So we had our own
super pluralistic system which was then
smashed by the Abrahamics. And the past
thousand years the Indian society and
and and system was not allowed to
function the way it does. So all of this
Abrahamic super simposition happened in
the past 1,000 or so years. And now
because we are so mentally brainwashed
and colonized. That's why we want to ape
everything the west does. The western
system is a very crude inferior system.
It's binary. It's a binary system. Good
versus bad, black versus white. Yeah.
That sort of thing. Left versus right.
And sometimes to make to to port that
they're not binary, they put us
centrist. So it's like conservatives,
liberals, libertarians which are
different flavors of of of the same left
and right thing. Why do we need that? We
need to go back to our civilizational
system which will take time. Maybe it
will take a couple of centuries but
that's what needs to happen. What's the
point of us adopting inferior systems?
So I am these are inferior systems you
know what what the Americans have the
the west has. The thing is that when
someone is super wealthy and powerful
everyone thinks they are the best and we
want to ape them. And that's the mindset
Indians have today. That's why India
also wants to have our right wing and
our left wing and that sort of thing. I
don't think we need to have that. We
need to have our our own system, our own
civilizational system.
Uh MX says what are your thoughts on
vasu numerology etc. I have no thoughts
on this. I am ignorant about this. Okay,
very honestly I'm telling you I don't
know anything about it. So I'm not the
right person to ask any of this.
Divor Singh says can we can have another
universe inside a black hole.
Mathematics adds up. Neil Degrass Tyson.
Okay.
Is it possible that our universe exists
inside a black hole? Yeah. So, how do we
assertain whether that's the case? What
what are the what are the facts that we
know of that are undisputable? Our
universe has a certain size. Not the
universe but the observable universe.
The observable universe that we can see
it has a diameter of about 90 95
trillion light years.
Is it billion? Is it trillion?
That's billion. It's billion. 95 billion
light years. Okay. Beyond that there is
a universe out there but we can't see
beyond that. So we have an observable
horizon of about 90 95 billion
lightyears in diameters. So it's like we
are at the center of a sphere and all
around us at a radius of of about 45 47
billion lightyears we can see. Beyond
that we can't see. But clearly there's a
universe beyond that because the
universe as we know is expanding and
every day certain galaxies are going
beyond the observable horizon. So that's
what we know that we live in a sphere
that we can observe and beyond that
there's something out there but we have
no access to it because of the
limitations of light speed. Now we know
that the universe is expanding. There is
observational evidence that demonstrates
this. Nobody can dispute that. Okay. red
shifting and so on galaxies. We can see
that the universe is expanding and the
expansion is accelerating.
We also know that a big bang happened an
initial singularity or or compressed
point was there from which everything
expanded outwards. It was not an
explosion. It was an expansion of
spaceime. And we know this because we
have the cosmic microwave background
radiation which is the afterlow of the
big bang. Right? That faint radiation
that's that permeates empty space which
is not really empty. So the question is
inside a black hole can you have a
situation when the where where there is
expanding spacetime
and cosmic microwave background
radiation is it possible to have that
inside a black hole well if you look at
the Einstein field equations and what
they say you'll find that that kind of
doesn't add up okay the Einstein field
equations that's what Albert Einstein
came up with in 1915 and the field
equations say they have two sides the
left side is talks about geometry the
geometry of the universe and right side
is about the matter matter in density,
matter in energy composition of the
universe and these two balance out. So
matter tells spacetime how to curve and
the curvature of spacetime tells matter
how to move that sort of thing. Now if
you look at the Einstein field equations
and you factor in other things it
doesn't look like a black hole should
have this sort of stuff inside a black
hole you can model it as a bag of
photons or or a bag of fuzz balls or
whatever but still you don't have the
situation of an expanding spaceime
inside a black hole and all. So I would
say it is rather unlikely that we may be
inside a black hole but who knows it's
not like we know all of physics. We know
we actually know next to nothing of
physics despite whatever advances we
we've made. So anything is possible at
the end of the day. We don't quite know
what's inside a black hole, right? We
can only describe what's inside a black
hole using the equations and the
theories that we have. The best theory
is general relativity. We also have
quantum mechanics and quantum field
theory. But they don't give you all the
answers because something is missing.
Some pieces are missing. So I would say
at the end of the day it's possible but
from what we know it looks somewhat
unlikely but we don't know everything so
it's possible. Okay. All right. Dark
Knight says how can wealthy or powerful
Hindus world over call create a dharmic
deep state? Would they have a strong int
incentive to create one the way another
much smaller group allegedly has?
You see Hindus aren't political
creatures. Hindus play little politics
here and there in in India you have the
you have the politicians and all but
Hindus don't unite right see trying to
unite Hindus is like trying to herd cats
you can herd sheep together it's very
easy to herd sheep sheep have the sheep
mentality but have you tried hering cats
have you seen ever have you ever seen in
your life 17 cats together going in the
same direction you won't see that cats
are super individualistic they're like
no me I'm different I'm not like you so
Hindus are like that Hindu Hindus
prioritize.
Hindus don't prioritize their
civilizational identity. Hindus
prioritize their subnational identity. I
am so and so language. I speak so and so
language. So I will I'll hang around
with people who speak the same language.
Or I belong to so and so pa. So I'll
hang around with people who belong to my
punt and I'll ignore everybody else.
That's how Hindus exist in isolated
groups in silos.
Okay? You go to the US, you'll see a
perfect example of this. All the people
who speak Telugu will be in in one
group. All the all the people who speak
Tamil will be in a different group. All
the people who speak Bengali will be in
a certain group. The people who speak
Hindi will be in a different group. They
all at the workplace they all together
come come together as Indians. But
outside the workplace in the social
groups, they're all in different silos.
That's how Indians are. And when it
comes to the various uh subdenominations
of of dharma, whether you're Vishnav or
you this or that or whatever you Iscon
or whatever it is. So there also you
have your subdivisions.
So Hindus don't unite and Hindus when
they leave India all they want to do is
make money and and live a peaceful quiet
life and have their little social groups
and that's it. Which is why Hindus
simply can't unite. Hindus don't have
the unity. You will need some tremendous
leader to come up to really unite Hindus
and make them see past their little
petty mindset of sub subivilizational
identities.
How can Hindus unite? Only if there is a
truly transcendent leader who emerges
from somewhere that's the only way
Hindus can unite. Who can some someone
like Lord Krishna or or Sriam that sort
of leader has to come or even like some
of the greats like Chhatrapatwishi
Maharaj or whoever someone of that
caliber in stature has to emerge only
then will Hindus unite. Even during the
time of Chhatraati Shivaji Maharaj and
the Marata Empire, you still had people
within India who were fighting the
Maratas or opposing the Maratas, our own
people. I'm not talking about the Turks
or the British. I'm talking about our
own our own people. We've always had
this problem, right? So, we need a a
transcendent leader. Only then will
Hindus unite. Hindus love to talk talk
talk all day. I have been to enough of
these gatherings. This congress in that
congress and what not in which city in
the world? What city in the world? They
come together have all these have all
these discussions on the stage on the
panel discussion right they'll talk nice
things then they will have a buffet
lunch and then they go back oh yeah what
happened what's the outcome what's the
outcome of the 20 crores you spend or
whatever for the event what's the
outcome
nothing so that's the deal with Hindus
you know you need a a leader a
transcendent leader otherwise this is
never going to happen people are just
going to keep talking Hindus love to
talk Hindus love to argue
They love arguing from morning till
night. Watch the TV debates. Talk talk
talk. Watch India's think tanks. Talk
talk. What do they achieve? Nothing.
Sad.
Divor Singh says, "Amazing." Well, thank
you, sir. Very nice uh to have you on
the on the live stream. Thank you so
much, sir. And once again, Dignor G, why
are all the richest dark entities
running the west from one place? Dimnor
Singh G wants to get to the bottom of
the black hole.
He wants to reach the singularity. He
wants to go past the event horizon.
Look, I'll tell you what.
The West has done something the world
has never done before.
Let me explain. Historically, okay,
historically we had empires. We know the
US is an empire. It masquerades as a
democracy and human rights. Blah blah
blah. The US is an empire.
But how is it different
historically?
Whether it's the Roman Empire or whether
it is Alexander's empire, whether it's
the Seucid Empire, whether it is
Napoleon's empire, whether it is the
British Raj, whether it is various
Indian empires, the whatever
historically empires have always
prioritized displays of wealth, opulence
and power. The Persian Hakamanish
Empire, the Aminid Empire,
every empire
would prioritize displaying these
opulent displays of wealth, grandeur and
power.
Show off, flaunt your instruments of
power. Display it to the world so that
the world understands how powerful you
are and they learn to respect you
through fear or whatever through either
through fear or through awe that how
rich these people are. Right? Every
empire has sought to do this. What the
US empire has done is that they have
very successfully concealed their
instruments of power. They pretend to be
just another country. We respect the UN
charter. We will abide by the WTO rules.
We believe in a free and fair uh global
uh order, the rules-based world order.
We will abide by the rules. Blah blah
blah. That's what they claim. They claim
that they are just another ordinary
nation like everyone else. The truth is
that they have more than 700 extr
territorial territorial military bases
and they have so many countries they
have totally vasalized and and
essentially finished. But they hide all
of this and they also hide where the
real power lies in the US or wherever in
the world like you say. Sir, where does
the real power lie? They have created
this facade of democracy. Every four
years there's an election electoral
process and every state has a governor
who's also elected.
The the thing is that the US president
serves a very specific purpose and role.
The role of the US president is to make
a lot of noise and and attract all the
media and the world's attention to
himself or her or himself so that nobody
looks at where the real power lies. That
stays hidden.
So that's the deal. That's what they
call the deep state. And one classic
symptom and very clear example of that
is the Fed, the Federal Reserve Bank of
the US, which is the national
essentially the the national bank, which
is privately owned. It's not owned by
the government and no one knows who
really owns the bank, who are the real
shareholders, stakeholders. They claim
it is various other US banks that own
it. That's all blah blah blah. It's it's
a bunch of people who own it and they
are the people who own the US. Now, who
are these people? We don't know.
So uh where do these people reside? Do
they reside in one place? Are they
decentralized? Are they distributed? I
don't know that how do we know right?
How to know such things? Yes. Uh DNU
says do the same people control Russia
and the west?
Well, there have been tales or or claims
that uh the Bolevik revolution was done
by the ro shills or whatever. they
financed it and maybe they financed both
sides of the world wars and all. If
there is some truth to that, then there
could be some truth to perhaps some of
these stories that the USSR was just one
part of the global order. The same
people created in order to extract the
maximum benefit for themselves, whoever
they are. Uh today, do do the same
people like the deep state for example,
whoever they are, do they control Russia
in the west? Not really sure. Not really
sure. Can't really say. But clearly
Russia and the West are on opposite
sides. and the and the west is trying to
destroy Russia which has failed
obviously miserably but they have tried.
So from whatever we can see on the
surface at least it doesn't look like
that but who knows what lies below the
surface like I always say take your
analysis subsurface do don't be
satisfied with surface level analysis
but I haven't gone down this rabbit hole
personally so I can't really say
teen talks dharma says why is Vlad the
Imperial called Draula he wasn't called
Draula he was called Draula Draula what
does the word Draul mean in Romanian
Draul. Draul means dragon, dragon,
dragon. And uh Draula means someone who
is of who belongs to the order of the
dragon.
So it was Vlad Draa
and then a guy called Bram Stoker
converted that into Dracula.
Okay. It is not something that means
vampire. It means somebody who belongs
to the lineage of the dragon.
So Vlad Vlad tipes
he was a freedom fighter for Romania and
when you are up against the Turks you
have to fight the Turks in a way that
will scare the Turks. So Vlad would do
frightful things to the Turks because
the Turks were absolute barbarians. They
did the most horrific things things to
the natives of Europe. So when you're
it's like
why does think of our goddesses
Mali Machamunda
what do they look like? Do they look
like the epitome of maternal love? Mali
and Machamunda.
Well you could think of them as the
epitome of maternal love if if you're on
their side. But they they have this
fierce r. fierce uh nature that they've
adopted because their job is to fight a
dharma and when you're fighting demons
you have to be so frightening that even
demons will be frightened of you. So
that is the kind of thing that Vladesh
took to his heart and he said that in if
I'm going to fight these demons the
Turks I'm going to become even more evil
than them. So he would then he would
defeat the Turks and he would create a
forest of impaled per impaled Turks. He
will plant a spear in the ground and
they will have he will impale Turks on
the spears. So when the next invasion
wave comes they will come across this
entire forest of several thousand
impaled Turks and even the Turks got
frightened of that. So that's the kind
of guy he he was he was he was an
impaler. That's why he was called Vlad
the Impaler. And because he belonged to
the family uh that called itself the
dragon family, the order of the dragon,
that's why he was called Vlad Dracula,
not Dracula. Okay, sir. Okay.
Um Dr. Dimnat says, "Did the CIA create
Nepal riot igniting India China shift?"
Looks like looks like this is a regime
change operation. Now there's a lady who
has come to power, Dr. Sushila or
Madame Sushila Kharki or something her
name is uh and she seems to be the
interim prime minister of Nepal. People
are claiming that this is proof that
this is not a CIA coup. It's not a
regime change operation. We'll have to
wait and watch. We have to wait and
watch whatever happened in Nepal the
past few days at the classic hallmarks
of a of a color revolution. The same
template the same playbook right so it
so we'll have to wait and watch. Uh
and who really who really is going to
hold power in Nepal now? See this lady
who's the interim caretaker whatever
prime minister she's the figure head she
will not really have the real power
please understand this people power and
position are different just because
somebody gave you a seat it says prime
minister doesn't make you the prime
minister it makes you the prime minister
in name in position in title
you have the seat but who has the power
you heard of the term kingmaker
have you heard of the term power behind
the throne there are such things too in
world. So let's wait and watch.
Let's wait and watch how things evolve
in Nepal.
Literally officer K says, "Is the Indian
land blessed? Almost all religions have
benefited here. Even at our expense, a
bunch of homeless Usuzbcks and Brits
managed to create prosperities for
ourselves for the for themselves."
Well, the land whether it's blessed or
not depends on the people. If you create
a land of prosperity and a land of
abundance and a land of culture and
civilization and if you continue that
for several thousand years, everybody
will consider that land to be blessed.
If a lot of great literature and
philosophy and and culture and
civilization all of and and all of that
emerges from your land because of the
kind of people who live here, then
everyone will look at that land as
blessed. And if it is a land of great
prosperity and abundance then even
barbarians will come here settle down do
all kinds of hor horrible things and
they will also benefit from it and they
will say the land is blessed. Ultimately
a land whether it is blessed or not
depends on the people
on their on the people and their
lifestyle and their culture and
civilization.
So if we want our land to remain blessed
we have to reclaim recover our
civilization.
Right now we are going in in a different
direction. We are becoming increasingly
derinated. We are losing touch with our
ancestral culture and civilization. We
are becoming more and more superficial.
Right? If you see our entertainment
industry, that is how foreigners see
Indian culture today. Bollywood
dingchuck dingchuck dingch that if you
look at the if you listen to the kind of
music that comes out of the Indian
entertainment industry is that culture
that's not culture. So very soon the
land will no longer be blessed if this
continues. So that's the thing. It was
blessed because of our ancestors. But
will it remain blessed because of people
like us.
Do we have the same standards to
continue making this land a blessed
place? That's what we have to ask
ourselves.
Dru Singh says why does Mossad help
India in many cases Hindenburg but it's
still involved in project K etc.
Ah look, every country has their own
national interests and no country, no
two countries are 100% aligned with each
other. Not the case. Impossible. For
example, right, right now the Israelis
did um an air strike on Qatar on DHA and
they took out some Hamas terrorists,
right? So the Israelis did an air strike
on on DHA Qatar and what did the prime
minister of India do? He tweeted that we
strongly condemn the the violation of
Qatar sovereignty blah blah blah
whatever he said he made a very clear
diplomatic statement without naming
Israel.
Okay. So some people would interpret
that as an anti-Israeli move. Right? But
you must remember that Qatar when the
Pahelgam attack happened Qatar had
condemned the attack
without naming Pakistan.
So in response we condemn the attack on
on on DHA without naming Israel. You see
this is how it works. Now we have
interests
in various parts of the Gulf region,
West Asia region. India supports the
rights of rights of the Palestinians for
alleged self-determination or whatever.
That's our official stance that kind of
goes against Israel. Right? There have
been many instances where in the United
Nations we have voted in a certain way
and Israel has voted in the opposite
way. So it's not like we are always
handin glove and always in the same
path.
India has its own set of interests.
Israel has a whole different set of
interests. Wherever the interests
converge, we work together and there are
lots of areas where our interests
converge. Which is why India and Israel
have a robust relationship. But there
are areas where they have divergence of
interests. No question about it. For
example, in India's far east, you have
these cookies who have crossed over from
Burma. Now the cookies someday some
sometimes they will claim that they are
animists. Sometimes they will claim that
they are Christians. Sometimes they'll
claim that they are Jews. They eat pork
but now they some of them claim that
they are Jews. That we have we are
descendants of some lost Jewish tribe.
And the Israelis have welcomed these
people and they have converted them
officially bapt not baptiz baptized but
whatever it is to Judaism and many
cookies now live in Israel and from
Israel at least from the quarters of
these cookies you have support for the
terrorism that's happening in Manipur
against the indigenous manipuries
and recent not recently but last year
somewhere a bunch of Indian influencers
or whatever had gone to Israel and the
Israeli authorities had the Indian
influencers meet a cookie rabbi. So
there is some Israeli government
involvement in this and so on. So Israel
has its own interests which it will
pursue. India has its own interests with
which India will pursue. But ideally you
don't want the pursuit of these
interests to to infringe upon each
other's sovereignty or interests. But
Israel may perhaps be on the borderline
with that. Maybe they they may regard
that maybe India is on the borderline
with something else somewhere else. So
that is how it goes. See international
relations are complicated. It's not
always 1 plus 1 equal to 2. It's very
complicated. There are all kinds of
complexities below the surface level
which are not visible to to people who
may not be aware of these things. Right?
So that's how it is.
Okay. Muhammad Faizan says, "I follow
your and Prashand Davan's geopolitics
and analysis and opinions. Have you ever
checked Prashand Davan's content? How do
you find?" I am not aware. I'm not aware
of Prashand Davan his content and
analysis. I don't watch any geopolitics
channel. It's nothing to do with
Prashand Davan or anybody else. I simply
don't have the time to watch YouTube uh
or or podcasts or any such thing. Before
I became active on YouTube, I used to
sometimes watch Joe Rogan. It was fun to
watch. But ever since I started uh the
channel, I have not been watching
anyone's content whether it is
geopolitics, whether it's history,
whether it's anything else. I simply
don't have the time to do it. With all
the work that I'm doing, especially now
that I'm writing books and all, I simply
don't have a minute of spare time. So I
am not aware of Prashand Davan. I've
heard a lot that people keep speaking
about him. I'm sure he's great, but uh I
personally don't have any opinion
because I haven't checked out his
analysis. I'm sure he's a great guy
because he has such a big following
apparently. Right. That's that's all I
can say.
Shashad Jenna says, should India do
something in Bangladesh before the US
puts up a military base and creates more
instability in the region and probably
extract minerals from Burma also? What
will India do? Look
what the question is. What can India do?
We should do something. Okay. Take very
nice. What specifics? We need specifics.
What are the options on the table?
Can India do a regime change in
Bangladesh? I think it's unlikely
because Bangladesh has become super
radicalized. Right. Um
today I would say that most people in
Bangladesh have the same kind of
approach and attitude and feeling set of
feelings towards India that the average
Pakistani has.
So it is a failure of India to
to uh approach Bangladesh the right way
since 1971.
In 1971 there was a tremendous amount of
goodwill towards India in Bangladesh
and we completely frittered that away
decade after decade. Today Bangladesh is
like East Pakistan. The average
Bangladeshi has the same feelings
towards India as the average Pakistani.
I'm sure there are some Bangladeshes who
are really good and who love India. I'm
sure some Pakistanis also are like that.
But the average person
it's a different story, right? So India
can't really do a regime change
operation in Bangladesh because no
political party will want to align. You
had Shasina who was favorably inclined
towards India and she has been ousted.
So let's say a regime change is not
possible. So then what do we do?
Military operation. If it was that easy,
why doesn't China take Taiwan military
operation? It's right there next door.
Just like Bangladesh is next door. It's
not that simple. Right now we have to
think of Bangladesh as East Pakistan
the way West Pakistan is and that's
that's going to be the situation. It is
now a US vasal. You don't tangle with US
vasals. You wait it out. That's what you
do. And Burma, yeah, there's a there's a
civil war happening in Burma. It's a
proxy war between the US and China. At
the heart of the issue is minerals. You
like you rightly say, Shana, what
minerals? Rare earth minerals. Would you
like to
see?
Okay, let's let's find out, shall we?
Let me bring the map on the screen and
we shall go to map and we shall discover
what's going on in Burma. Yes. What is
going on in Burma? Let give me a second.
I'll put the map on the screen.
Okay, let us put that on the screen.
Where is map? Here is map. Let's take a
look at Burma.
Okay, here we have it on the screen. So,
we have Burma here. Now, um if we zoom
in, take a satellite image
and one second. This is Arunachal
Pradesh. We're talking about Burma.
Let's talk about this region here. So,
if we zoom into some No, this is the
snowy region. That's too That's too far
north. We need to One second. Let me
orient myself. Let's Let's go somewhere
here.
Okay. Now,
if we zoom in, zoom in, zoom in, zoom
in. Do we have any settlement here? Give
me a second or two.
very ex uh Pangoir.
Okay. Now, this is on the by the way,
let's zoom out. This is on the border
between Burma and China. Okay.
To the right you have to the right you
have China. To the left you have Burma.
So, let's zoom in and let me show you
something.
For example,
uh
here
you can see there are these these little
ponds and what whatnot. One second. I'm
sure I'll find something very quickly.
So you have all these rare earth mines
in this region.
You'll have to give me a second before I
can Ah, there we have it. Check it out.
These are lithium mining operations.
tremendous reserves of rare earths in
this region right across the border with
China. Look everywhere you will see
these these little pits and wells that
have been dug and you have all these uh
uh you know what you what you do you
take lithium and you liquefy it or you
mix it with water over here and then you
let let the whole thing dry and that's
how you extract lithium. You can see all
across the place. These are all rare
earth mines strewn across this entire
region. All across the place. If you
take the time and look around, you will
find mine after mine after mine after
mine. And these are all right across. It
even says rare earth mines here.
See this rare earth mines. These are
extraordinarily valuable. And all of
this is going into China. and the
Americans want it.
Okay? And that is one of the driving
factors when it comes to this civil war
that is going on in Burma.
The China is benefiting from all of this
and the US would very much like to have
it. So that sort of thing. So the US
wants that, the Chinese will not want
this to happen. So this is a tugof-war
contest between the Burmese and the
Chinese uh between the Chinese and the
Americans. And Burma is the victim of
this.
Vnor Singh says, "Why is the Indian
defense minister praying at the wailing
wall?" A symbolic gesture. You know, it
doesn't cost you anything to do it.
Maybe it helps, maybe it makes the
Israelis happy.
See, see, we are not an Abrahamic
religion, right? That certain things are
are haram to us. We can go and pay our
respects anywhere. I mean we have Hindus
who go to all kinds of places of
worship. Hindus go to Dargas and mosques
and churches and whatnot. So what's the
harm in going to a Jewish uh thing the
the west wall of the former temple of
Solomon that the Romans brought down?
Yeah. So because India and Israel have a
robust relationship maybe the defense
minister thought let me go and make this
symbolic gesture of friendship towards
and respect towards Israel. I suppose
that's about it. Beyond that I don't see
anything deeper than that. Uh when an
Indian minister goes and does it it
generally means nothing. It's just a
symbol. Indians love symbolism. Indians
love symbolism. Indians love gestures
and words. A few nice cho chosen nice
words and Indians are they'll all melt.
So Indians love to do it and they love
to reciprocate in this matter. But when
someone like Trump goes and does it, it
may have a different meaning. Right? So
okay
Ravi says how can India crush kalistan
movement there is no kalistan movement
there's nothing there may be attempts to
create recreate this movement in some
parts of India especially punjab and all
uh just starve the funds that's all
whatever so-called kalistar movement
exists it only exists in Canada and the
US and the UK and stria
and maybe New Zealand and maybe some
other vasal countries of the US nothing
in India. I I'm sure that we should not
take it lightly. The the the external
forces will try and create trouble in
Punjab and other parts other such parts
of India. All you have to do is starve
off the funding. That's about it. That's
all it takes. Uh and of course when it
comes to Punjab, there's been this
tremendous drug problem because right
across the border of Pakistan, they
would love to have Punjab abortion
drugs. And another issue in Punjab is
the is the industrial scale
Christianization of Punjab. Six are
becoming Christians. I mean what on
earth? Don't you have any self-respect
guys? What are you doing anyway? Yeah.
So all these all these means are being
used to create trouble in Punjab.
Cautilia says territorial and future
impact of 1967 Indochina war. But
whatever future impact was to happen of
67 war, it's already happening now
because we are what 60 years down the
line almost. There was no territorial
impact. Uh territory was not exchanged.
the Chinese wanted to take some
territory probably of India's territory
and we thwarted that we defeated their
their attempt and uh after that the
Chinese became a little wary of India
that this is no longer the India of 62
even 5 years after 62 they they faced
this defeat in this localized uh you
know u war that that we had so after
that India and China the Chinese become
a little more wary of India and you also
had some other clashes the sumong chu
clash and etc in ' 87 or whatever
in which again India came out came out
on top. So after 67 the the Chinese were
were more careful when dealing with
India.
Swastik Mahesh says after the US backed
regime change operation in Nepal is
there going to be rapid increase in
Christian conversions and religious
demographic re-engineering. Wherever the
US has an advantage they do all these
things. The classic example is South
Korea. South Korea
historically a Buddhist kingdom
historically Buddhist no Christianity
today Buddhism is a minority the
majority people are Christians or
atheists
Buddhism is regarded as backward so
that's what the Americans have
engineered in in South Korea
South Korea is under US occupation in
case you're not aware
okay ever since the Korean war ended or
paused
South Korea has been under rigorous
robust American military operation.
South Korea is run by the US,
right? The South Korean military
essentially comes under the US. So when
the US is the dominant force, they will
destroy your culture. They tried the
same with Japan. It's not succeeded that
much in Japan. Japan is still not well
there is there is a certain Christian
population in Japan. Let's let's quickly
look at the Christian demographics in
Japan. Just just figure it out what's
what the deal is. And since we are doing
it, we may as well see for South Korea.
South Korea religious demographics
Christian. Okay, let's see. So, look at
this. 51% is no religion. 31% is
Christianity. 17% is Buddhism. My god,
they've destroyed South Korea. Now let's
look at Japan. So South Korea has been
destroyed.
Japan religious demographics. Now this
is going to be different.
Oopsie. So Japan has been more robust.
They have resisted. As you can see, 46%
of Japanese are still Buddhists. Uh
what? Where is Shinto? What is this
nonsense?
They're not showing Shinto.
Okay, Shinto is 48% in Japan.
Buddhism is 46%. This is all Wikipedia.
So it is not necessarily reliable.
Remember that. But Christianity is just
1% in Japan. So Japan has somehow
survived uh what the Americans have
attempted. They have been very
successful in South Korea. Japan, it's
not really worked out. So Japan has been
more resilient because their culture
maybe is more deeprooted. Um but yeah
but Japan became very prosperous very
rapidly after the second world war ended
and that's why it was hard to to
and and South Korea was horribly
povertyridden.
That's the difference. So when you have
a nation that's ridden with riddled with
poverty it's very easy to Christianize
it. When you have a prosperous nation
it's very hard to Christianize it. Now
consider Nepal. It's a poor nation. If
the US has a puppet government in Nepal,
it means that conversion efforts will
will reach sky-high limits. So yeah,
they will try and create a Christian
country out of Nepal.
Divor Singh says, "What is the wailing
wall? Why does every political party
pray that except JFK of course?"
Well, did JFK never pay his respects?
I wonder what happened to him. Um, well,
so what is the Whailing Wall? The
veiling wall was the I think the west
wall or whichever wall of the temple of
Solomon
of the rebuilt temple of Solomon not the
original temple of Solomon. So Solomon
had a temple. Solomon lived about 900 or
so BC. It is said around 900 or 1,000 BC
around that time roughly give or take.
We don't quite know for sure. So he was
a he was a king of the of the Jews.
Solomon Sullean Sullean and he had built
a temple in that in that in that same
location and after the Assyrian invasion
I think it was destroyed don't quote me
on that but it was destroyed
and then the Persians
liberated the Jews from the Assyrians
under the great uh emperor Kurush
and Kurush was a very respectful and
like the westerners say tolerant emperor
emperor and he repatriated the Jews back
to Judea and he gave them the funds to
rebuild the temple that had been
destroyed. So the second temple was
built
and the wailing wall is what remains of
that temple because after the revolt of
the Mcabes or whatever whichever revolt
it was against the Romans the Romans
destroyed the temple but one wall
remained and that is the wall that's now
called the wailing wall. And why does
every political party pray that well
only those politicians can answer the
question
I don't know
okay says is Nepal facing the US
playbook like Bangladesh protests seem
orchestrated not organic aimed at
destabilizing India after failure regime
change operations Nepal
look everything that we saw that
happened it it had the clear hallmarks
of a color revolution of of an American
regime change operation
Now we'll have to wait and watch as to
who is the real power in Nepal. Right
now they have appointed some person this
lady Supreme Court justice Madame
Sushila Kharki
um she her husband was the politician
who was a hijacker of a plane and all
that that sort of thing and uh let's see
what role she plays but she is merely
the caretaker prime minister the person
who sits in the chair but where does
does the real power lie that's the
question and who's going to really run
the show from behind the scenes that is
going to tell us everything as to what
has really happened uh so most likely
this is an American mediated regime
change operation to uh get rid of a
pro-China government because Mr. KP
Sharma was a Chinese agent. Uh and these
protests look the protests protests that
are widespread and super organized.
They're never organic. There's always
some organizing force behind the scenes
that is taking care of all the logistics
of of all the coordination and all these
things. So uh the objective of all of
these efforts that the US is doing is to
encircle India with a fence of thorns.
Our strategic experts like to talk about
even today about the Chinese string of
pearls strategy right of encircling
India at sea in the in the Indian Ocean
region through all these ports that the
Chinese are building. Well the Americans
are building a fence of thorns around
India. There is West Pakistan where
there was a regime change in 2022 and a
pro- US government came to power. Then
there's East Pakistan, Bangladesh where
you had a regime change operation in
2024 and now you have a US wasal regime
there. Now and Burma operation K project
K cookie land for Christ that is a US
project right and it has caused so much
bloodshed and so much suffering for the
indigenous people of Manipur. Then now
we have Nepal. So they want to
completely encircle India. The objective
is to contain India, not let India grow
to its full potential. Keep India down,
suppress India, create all kinds of
problems, internal problems, external
problems from India so that India's
economy doesn't grow in India doesn't
become a threat in the future.
Achintia Anand says what about western
theft of our knowledge contribution to
advanced sciences like surgery yoga
surya sedant
uh being 0.3 second difference with
current system look they have stolen all
of that but they will never give credit
to it to us right for it they won't
that's how it works you take all the
knowledge you digest it you build on top
of it then you claim it was yours all
all along so that is well known I mean
whether Whether it is the concept of the
decimal system, the concept of the
decimal point, whether it is the concept
of zero itself, whether it is uh
algebra, whether it is trigonometry,
whether it is uh infinite series,
whether it's uh calculus, all of this
originated in India. Uh astronomy,
tremendous astronomy data was taken from
India by the Arabs. Then it went to the
west and the westerners claimed it was
all ours. when Kepler Johannes Kepler
needed astronomical data he acquired
astronomical data from Brahmin and
Banaras and it's on the basis of that
those detailed copious astronomical
observations that was he was able to
formulate the three laws that he's
famous for Kepler's law planetary motion
so all of this is known
everyone knows it but nobody
but it's not recognized you will not see
a single western
historian of science write about this
but Indians are writing about this which
is good. So it can no longer be swept
under the carpet and today you have all
these western um researchers whether it
is in Princeton or Harvard or whatever
who are claiming that meditation has
been a global practice. It doesn't
belong to any one culture or community.
Meditation came from India. You little
I don't have a polite word so I shall
not say anything. Uh so they are trying
to steal everything and uh and and
rebrand it. So
that guy Hubberman or whatever his name
is he is one of the big culprits. So we
have something called pranayam. Pranayam
is a very ancient age-old practice in
India. Hubberman and his and his friends
they call it cardiac coherence
breathing. Some other people call it box
breathing. So they are rebranding it and
trying to pass it off as something they
have discovered themselves. The Wimhof
method of cultural theft.
The Wimhof method is an Indian method.
It is called bastrika in Kapalabati
but he has rebranded it the Wimhof
method and ice bats. That's what Indian
yogis do in the Himalayas.
Everything is stolen from India but it's
rebranded and he has made a fortune this
Wimhof fellow. So that's the deal with
the west a bunch of thieves. I'm not
saying that all of the scientific
advances the west has done are Indian
advances. No, they took the knowledge
that we had developed until about 11
1200 AD and then they built on top of
that.
Right? So, no one's taking any credit
away from Einstein or or whoever
but the foundations mathematical and
scientific foundations came from India.
Divor Singh says do bankers run the
world essentially? Well, the entire
economic financial system is run by
bankers. No question about that, right?
And since you are running the entire
global economic system, you are super
powerful. And therefore, whoever whoever
owns the banks in the banking system,
they run the world because not only do
they have money, they also apparently
have a lot of lot of power. So whoever
that is, they could be super powerful.
Maybe they are running the world from
behind the scenes. Vim Singh says, "We
saw rot shells at the Amani wedding.
Aren't Roshills supposed to be
anti-India?"
Well, I am not aware of this. First of
all, rot shields at the Ammani wedding.
Well,
let's say hypothetically the rot shells.
Hypothetically, I I don't know. Okay,
since I've said this, I I am not aware
of the history of the rot shells and
what they're up to and all that. I've
never studied these people, so I can't
really say. But let's say hypothetically
that the these people are empty
hypothetically.
Then it doesn't mean they will never
come to India, right? Let's say you are
anti-India. It means you don't like
India and you want to let's say destroy
India.
Then maybe instead of staying away, you
will make trips to India and find out
what the scene is like and make
connections everywhere and then in the
future perhaps try and operationalize
some of these connections. So that's a
better strategy than staying away,
right? So
so maybe that could perhaps
explain why someone whoever it is who
hypothetically may be anti-India would
visit India. I'm not saying the rod
shells are or are not. I don't know. I
don't know. Okay. I'm like I said, I've
not studied the history or or their
present also.
Cotishi says, "How and why is Israel a
sovereign country? How come the US
always bows down in front of Israel? Why
does it seem like Israel is the master
of the UA of the US?
Why is the Israel a sovereign country?"
So I have this
hard power index in which I also have a
sovereignty ranking and I have said this
for several years that there's only a
small number of sovereign countries in
the world. All other countries are
sovereign only name only technically the
truly sovereign countries are the US,
Russia, China, India and Israel.
France isn't fully sovereign. The UK
isn't sovereign at all. Germany isn't a
sovereign nation.
Turkey isn't a sovereign nation.
Japan, South Korea, Australia, these are
not sovereign nations. Only five nations
are genuinely sovereign. So why is
Israel a sovereign country? See, ask
yourself, is Israel a member of NATO?
If you are a member of NATO, it means
that your armed forces
can and do come under foreign command
under the command of a foreigner who is
generally American or whatever. Right?
So if you are a nation that's a member
of NATO, you will have to contribute
contribute to ar your armed forces and
put them under a foreigner's command at
various points in time. That is directly
a contravention of sovereignty which
this means that you don't have military
sovereignty.
So Turkey is a member of NATO it means
it is not militarily sovereign.
Is Israel a member of the EU?
If you are a member of the EU then you
have no control over your borders. Your
borders are open. Secondly, you don't
have any control over your economy
because you're using the EO which is
controlled from Brussels, not from your
capital. So, you don't have territorial
sovereignty. You don't have economic
sovereignty and you don't even have
legislative sovereignty because the laws
are being passed in Brussels and you
don't have any control over that. So, if
you're a member of EU, you don't have
sovereignty. If you are a member of EU
plus NATO, you're done, fried, finished.
Israel is neither a member of the EU or
NATO. But Israel is a small country,
right? If you are a small country, you
are by de facto not sovereign because
you are so small that you are dependent
on others for all kinds of things and
anybody and a big power can anytime take
you out. So by being a small country,
you are by just def factor not
sovereign. Israel is a very small
country. So why is it still sovereign?
Because it is a nuclear weapons power.
If you're a nuclear weapons power, it
augments your sovereignty multiple fold.
Right? And then there's the special
relationship Israel has with the US.
Yeah. The US is an unconditional
supporter of Israel. No matter what
happens, we will always support Israel.
Well, in in such a situation when you
are such a special country, obviously
you are sovereign. All right. How come
the US bows down to Israel? Why does it
seem like Israel is a master of the US?
Well, that's a long story. There are
lots of American politicians who are
Jewish people and they consistently
advocate excellent relations with Israel
and unlike Hindus they are united which
is why they are so much more effective
that's one factor there are many other
factors right all right
how influential was Harry Truman as the
US president true man true man Harry
Truman what did he look like a second
let me just see his face so that I
recall who who this guy
Truman.
Harry Truman. Harry Truman.
Okay. So, Harry Truman was the US
president during the during the cold war
during the World War II and cold war
periods. And when he stepped down, he
had given this very
precious speech about the the dangers of
the military-industrial complex. I think
it was pretty influential. pretty
influential and people still quote that
speech that he gave at the end of his
term. So yeah,
why does the UN have the same emblem as
the Roman emblem? Divor Singh has very
interesting questions. Let's find out.
Let's find out. Uh UN emblem. Um emblem.
Ah, you mean the laurel wreath?
The laurel wreath. Yes. Yes.
Laurel wreath.
Yeah, this was a symbol of triumph,
right? The Romans, this was a symbol of
honor for the Romans. Even the Greeks
used it. And uh see
the Greeks had something called the
Olympic Games, right? The Olympic Games.
And then they were discontinued for
discontinued for more than 2,000 years.
And then we have restarted in the 1900s.
So in the Olympic games, the original
Olympic games in Greece, uh the winners
were not given gold medals or whatever,
they were given a laurel wreath. And
somehow this tradition influenced Rome.
And in Rome also whenever a victorious
general returned to Rome after carrying
out a great victorious campaign, he
would have what was called a triumph
which was a parade with his legiance on
the streets of Rome where all the
citizens would come out and applaud him
and you know bless him and all that.
And the parade was interesting because
he would also display
the enemies he had captured. So when
Caesar did a triumph in Rome, he paraded
who was the leader of the Gauls and he
was paraded in the triumph. At the end
of the triumph, he was strangled human
sacrifice.
So the Romans used to have this
triumphs, human sacrifices and the
victorious generals would wear a laurel
wreath which was a continuation of a
Greek tradition and somehow it's become
this thing, you know. So the UN also has
it. I'm not sure why it has it, but it's
a very interesting observation you made.
Most people would kind of not see it,
right? But it is indeed the case. It's a
laurel wreath that they have around the
globe. Why is it so? I don't know. Maybe
we can maybe I can look into it at the
future time. But interesting
non-coincidence. It's not a coincidence
for sure.
Okay.
Anonymous says, "Namaste Gurud. I hope
you're doing well, sir. I'm doing very
well. I hope you're doing well, too,
sir. Thank you so much.
Okay, AKS says, "What are thoughts about
the second B-21 raider revealed
yesterday at the Indonesian Defense
Minister meeting under Secretary of
Defense in the US just after the
protests?" Second B-21 raider. What was
that? Let me Google it. I haven't I'm
See, I'll tell you something people.
First of all, before I answer the
question, I at any given point in time
am never aware of the latest news. I am
not someone who scrolls the news 24 by7
and I have to know the latest thing
that's happening right now. I take my
time. I never do knee-jerk reactions.
That's why when the Nepal thing
happened, I did not speak for 2 three
days. I do not even tweet about it
because I like to take my time before
something happens and it it and and the
patterns become visible then I speak
about it after I have some understanding
of it. So I'm not aware of the second
B21 raider thing but let us Google it
together. What is this B21 thing? Let's
let's find out together. B21
radar. What is this? Is there some news?
America's new stealth B21. Okay. Takes
the N next step with a second bombber's
first flight.
Okay. So, this is a new strategic uh
bomber that these Americans are uh
developing
and in development. Okay. And this thing
is now undergoing test flights.
Understood. Understood. Okay. So, this
is the next
generation uh strategic long long range
stealth bomber. Stealth bomber that the
Americans are developing. It's now in
the test flight phase. And yesterday a
second test flight happened. It looks
like that's what the news just told us.
So, yeah, good for them. They they will
have even more teeth now. and they will
have a new generation strategic stealth
bomber. So, it's going to be great for
them to bomb any country they want and
anywhere in the world with a with a
better aircraft, perhaps with uh with
better stealth characteristics and
better electronics and avionics and
maybe uh more augmented payload
capacity, whatever it is, right? Um
so, yeah, see that's what the Americans
do. They keep on innovating. They keep
on developing new weapons and new weapon
systems and new aircraft and that's how
you stay on top of the game and that's
how you remain the superpower. So that's
something that India can certainly learn
from. Now Indonesian defense minister
meeting under secretary of defense. Once
again I'm not seeing the news but not
surprising. Recently there were student
protest in Indonesia also right
the US is unhappy with Indonesia. Is
Indonesia a member of bricks? Let's
let's quickly find out. Let us quickly
find out. Is Indonesia a member of
bricks? Has it joined bricks? Indonesia
bricks.
Indonesia joined bricks. Very
very naughty very naughty Indonesia
joint bricks. Now let's let's Google
this also.
Indonesia SEO is Indonesia member of
SEO.
Let us see Shangghai cooperation blah
blah blah. Indonesia
Indonesia is an observer. It looks like
Indonesia is not a member state.
But when the SEO summit happened,
Indonesia was represented at the highest
level. So Indonesia has been naughty
enough to join bricks. They also
participate in the SEO summit. I mean
how naughty. So naturally they the
students will be displeased with that
because students understand geopolitics,
right?
So uh after all this happened there have
been student protests in Indonesia
and because of that I'm sure there there
are panic stations in Indonesia because
student protests are usually uh the
threat of a color revolution. If you
understand the playbook the color
revolution playbook the regime change
operation playbook you will understand
it starts with student student protests.
generally universities that have
infiltration by the US and US agents. We
have such universities in India many. So
when these student protests happened
clearly the Indonesians had to go and
speak to the Americans. Sir, please
please we we made mistakes. What what do
you want us to do? Please tell us we'll
do it. That sort of thing. So it's a
it's a natural reaction to the protests.
Uh Rohan Suja your views on confusing
today's teachers with gurus.
So today we are told
your teacher is your guru. Worship your
teacher.
Go and touch their feet in the morning.
Your teacher is your guru.
That is nonsense. Let me explain why.
A guru was something was a term a title.
that was not applicable to everybody
historically.
Guru was the highest title somebody
could have
and you have to understand the nature of
the Indian education system, historic
education system to understand why
today's teachers are not gurus. India's
indigenous education system has been
destroyed. It is a loss that you don't
even feel today.
We had an education system that was
based that was decentralized and it it
had it had several levels. The lowest
level was the temples.
You had temples all across the length
and the breadth of the country. Every
town, every village, every locality had
a temple and temples were places of
places of basic education.
So the so the pujari there was not just
a pujari. There was also a shikshak who
would give basic education to the kids
of the locality. basic education 1 + 1
equal to two kaga that sort of thing
basic arithmetic and mathematics basic
grammar basic itas puranas all that
stuff basic stuff simple then if you are
were a bright student and you wanted to
do higher education you would go to a
vihara you would go to you know a
greater temple somewhere and eventually
if you are a really great student you
would go to a wish vidyal like
nalandanda tilhara takashila vikramila
Tapuri, Shardit, Walabi and so much
more. So we had so many of these. So
that's where you would have the highest
education available in the universe
in ancient times.
And even there not every teacher was
called a guru. You had adhyakas, adhyak
and you had whole higher grading system
and the highest level was guru. And no
matter what level of teacher you were,
maybe you were not a guru level teacher,
you were just a dhapak or or or uph
whatever it was,
you never charged fees from your
students. Education was universal and it
was free. Until the 19th century,
education in India was universal and
free. Read the beautiful tree by Dar Pal
who collected data from British
statistics and he has proved that that
education was universal. It was not
restricted to only males. Females got
education. It was not restricted to
certain casts like people alleged today.
Everybody got education using British
records and statistics. Damal has proven
it 19th century records. So education
was free universal and education was
free. It was free.
Your guru
would not stop teaching you if you did
not give the next month's installment.
Why was it like this? How how did they
work for free? Because all education was
state sponsored. The king or the emperor
would pay for the upkeep of the temple
or the vihara or the visha vidyale.
Everything was paid for.
The king or the emperor paid for the
salaries and upkeep and everything of
the of the staff and the teachers and
the gurus and administration and
whatever else. And they also ensure that
all the education because of this was
free. So and and your relationship was
with your guru was a lifelong
relationship.
It was not like okay 3 years done and we
out. No it was a lifelong relation rel
relationship. Today the moment you don't
give next week next week's fees your
your teacher will stop fe will stop
teaching you
and the the level the caliber the
standards of the teachers are abysmal
today on average some are good but most
are average most are abysmal. There's no
connection between the gurus of ancient
times and today's teachers. Today's
teachers are service providers. You pay
them, they'll provide you a service and
that to a substandard service. And the
moment you stop paying them, they will
not look at you in the face.
You call that a guru? Are these people
worthy of respect? Some of them are
really good people. And because the
system is like this, they have no choice
but to take fees from you. Some of them
are really good, but most are useless.
So you can't call these individuals your
gurus. Come on, they are service
providers.
Dipam Mukapadia says I have the
opportunity to work in a US tech firm on
the latest technology and pro possible
PhD also which I'm not getting here. I
feel bad that I will have to leave my
country. Why are you feeling bad? Why is
your country going to miss you?
Look, if you're feeling bad that you're
leaving the country and you want to
serve the country and so on, don't feel
bad. I'll tell you why.
Anybody who gets the opportunity to
leave the country for better
opportunities and prospects out of
India, my advice is take the
opportunity, go abroad. Here's what you
should do. Go there, work there,
learn everything you can, get your
degree, get your PhD, get more job
experience, and work another 10, 15, 20
years there.
become very prosperous, very wealthy,
very rich. Then come back to India when
you're in your 40s. You want to serve
your country, right? Will you serve?
Will you be able to serve your country
when you have no salary? When you have
no skills, no knowledge, no expertise,
no experience. What will you do? How
will you serve your country? If you want
to serve your country, become rich.
Become rich on US dollars. Then bring
those to India. become wealthy on on
knowledge and experience
and skills and bring all of that back to
India when you can. Why are you feeling
bad? Great opportunity for you to serve
your country. Work outside for 20 years
then come back. Then you will be in a
much better position to actually
genuinely and more impactfully serve
your country. So dip mukad all the best.
Go for it sir. Go for it.
MK says, "What are the objectives of the
US in the Russia Ukraine war? If a
ceasefire takes place, how and where and
when would the US create problems for
Russia
in the future?" So, what's the situation
is is the question. Give me a second.
What's the objectives? Look, what are
the objectives of the US? The the
How did the war start? First of all, the
war happened because the US crossed
Russia's red lines, which was regime
change operation in Ukraine. See,
imagine Russia does a regime change
operation in Canada or Mexico. Will the
US tolerate it? They will never tolerate
it. When the Russians when the Soviets
put miss put missiles in Cuba, the
Americans didn't tolerate it. Kennedy
did not tolerate it. The Soviets had to
pull the missiles out again. So when the
US is so touchy about nations in its
periphery, how can they expect Russia to
tolerate any any kind of nonsense in
their periphery? So when the Americans
did a regime change operation in Ukraine
in 2014, the Euromaidan coup, that was a
red line for Russia. That's why Russia
immediately grabbed Crimea which was
anyway Russian territory. Okay. And then
they have been systematically
essentially doing ethnic cleansing in
the Donbas region. the Ukrainian
government, the puppet government for
several almost a decade they did this
and that's why in 2022 the Russians
eventually realized that now very soon
the UK Ukrainians could become a NATO
member state. So it's time to do
something. So the Russians should
actually have done this in 2014 but they
did it in 2022. So the Americans knew
that Russia will have to do something
about this from a military perspective.
They knew it. They were waiting for it.
They induced Russia. They provoked and
goded Russia into doing this. So
eventually when this happened, the
Americans took the opportunity to to
dump every imaginable sanction on Russia
and they thought that it would it would
crush the Russian economy. They were so
wrong. And the Russian economy has
rebounded. It is it now it is now
stronger than it was before than in 2022
and it's growing at a rate that's higher
than the European nations. So Russia So
the objective was to crush Russia. It
was to destroy Russia and they thought
that if if if the Ukraine war will go
badly for Russia then Russians will get
frustrated with Putin and they will do a
regime change operation or they will
overthrow Putin and then we can take
Moscow itself. So the objective was to
destroy Russia to defeat Russia and to
take over the the overall great dream is
a regime change in Moscow. That's the
great dream of the US. Okay. Uh so yeah
that's the deal. If a ceasefire takes
place now takes place, how and where and
when would the US create problems for
Russia in the future?
Um,
how do you create ceasefire? We'll see
about that. How can the US create more
problems for Russia in the future and
well, they've already created all the
problems problems they can.
>> They could perhaps then operationalize
Poland and create trouble with Poland
perhaps. So they you can always use a
disposable vasal state to create more
trouble for for Russia. And before you
operationalize Poland, you turn Poland
into a military superpower, which is
what's happening right now. It's
happening quietly. But Poland is being
turned into a military superpower in
Europe, more powerful than Germany now.
Okay. And at some point, I suppose they
will operationalize Poland against
Russia.
Okay. Divor Singh says Kirk's death was
very serious here in the US. Yep. What
do you think about the private plane
which flew from a nearby airport after
it got shot? Well, I am not aware of
this priv private plane. I have not been
really paying attention to this in great
detail as to looking at everything
that's happened. Uh it is said that
somebody has been turned in. Some guy
some young young guy 20 22 years old.
He's apparently the shooter and his own
father turned him in. And apparently
people were claiming that other
countries were involved in all of this
is in the in the assassination of this
person Charlie Kirk and uh
so I am not aware of this private plane.
Now what in case this private plane
thing is significant what could it be?
So
let's say some some important person
gets shot and then right after the
person is shot a mysterious private
plane takes off from a nearby airport.
What could that signify? It potentially
could signify that the person or persons
involved in this operation, the
assassination operation.
They decamped. They escaped the region
in their private plane. That's what it
could perhaps potentially mean. It
doesn't mean it it necessarily means
that. But in case that is the correct
situation in case
then why has somebody been turned in?
That's that's that's a question that
arises. Is that person a pathy?
Is that person a scapegoat? Who knows?
Look, anything is possible. The US
especially anything is possible. I mean
1963 happened everything was covered up.
So you know who knows.
Shashad Jenna says who was the actual
victor in the battle of Jalum I don't
know what is this battle of Jalum look
we've had so many battles so I don't
remember let's let's Google the battle
of Jalum I don't remember which part of
Indian history it is let's see who was
the actual victor battle
of Jalum
or the the battle of the haspes or jalum
do you really have to ask me this
Alexander was defeated
it was purush Cham who won. The Greeks
called him Porus
but the Greek historians supported it as
a great victory for Alexander and then
who he magnanimously forgave Porus and
and reinstated him as a vasal king and
that sort of nonsense.
It was Porus who was a district level
chieftain
of a small district in western India who
defeated Alexander the Great. Okay. And
the wounds that Alexander incurred in
this battle, they killed him. He limped
back to Babylon which he had captured
and he died there. And he also lost his
great horse Bucifalis in this battle.
Come on. Do we have to believe Western
propaganda?
Anan Fimat Anand Ray Fimate Fad or
whatever. I'm sorry if I'm
mispronouncing your name. I'm sorry
about that. What was the 2008 financial
crisis which what was the corruption
which led to such an event? Can this
happen again? Been watching you since
episode 7. Really? Thank you so much.
Well, you've got a long time you were
here. It's been a while. It's been a
while since we did this episode. Since
we started. Well, good to have you, sir.
Thank you so much for being a longtime
watcher. What was this 2008 financial
crisis? It was called the subprime
crisis. Um housing crisis, all of that.
So there was all this speculation on the
on the market rates of property in the
US
and uh that sort of thing. The details
are murky with for me right now. This
question has come out of the blue. I
don't remember exactly what it was at
that time. I was not even that much of
an observer of of I was at that time
more of a student of history still. So
it was called the subprime crisis crisis
and a lot of these uh financial
institutions had made all these bad
loans on the basis of hyperinflated fin
property rates and all of that and once
the bubble burst all these investments
turned bad and entire institutions like
Leman Brothers etc they went under and
that causes gigantic
um readjustment of the market lots and
lots of people who had invested in in
the subprime and all that. They they
lost their savings and all all of that.
And u
all the all the
bosses and and managers of these
speculative
investory uh companies and all they got
bonuses and they got uh they they were
bailed out by Obama. But the little guy
who the the little guys the average
people they they lost a lot of money. So
that was a big uh earthquake kind of
situation financially economically in
the US and that is the point where China
decided that it is our time now. So the
2008 financial crisis was the the
turning point in China's behavior. They
decided it is now is China's time. The
west has finally
got on the back foot. Their economy is
no longer on good ground, strong ground.
Now is the time for China to step up and
that's where you start seeing a very
different China.
Okay.
Sharma says Cyrus or Kurush the great
similarities to Chingish Khan. How were
they different in the empires they
founded? Kurush did not found any
empire.
Yeah. He was the son of an emperor
and uh
Kurush was um the emperor of the
Hakshamanish or Hakamanish Empire. the
Akimerid Empire.
His ancestor was the great Haksham
Manish or Akamanish.
And uh so who was Kurush's father? Was
it Chespish?
Was it Let's let's quickly look into
Kurush's father.
Kurush the great father. Who was his
dad? Kurush the Great's father. Who was
his daddy?
Kambuja. His father was Kambujia. In
Greek Greek they call it Kam Kambis or
something. Kambisis the first Kambuia.
Okay. And Cyrus was Kurush. See they
were they wouldn't even mention that
name properly. They're always mentioned
in the Greek the Greek version or Kuros
or something. His name was Kurush.
That's how they distort names
that are not western. Anyway, he was the
son of Kamuja the first and uh Kamuja
was an emperor of the Kirid Empire and
Kurush was one of the greatest of the
emperors of this empire. So he was born
into power and wealth. He was born the
crown prince essentially if I'm not
mistaken. Uh but he did eventually
become the emperor. Chigis Khan was born
into no such thing. His father was the
chieftain of a small tribe called the
Bourjigan tribe, the blue wolves. And
Chingis Khan, well, his father died when
he was about 8 years old. And his
family, Chingish Khan's family, he was
born, his his birth name was Teujin. So
Teujin, his mother and his brothers,
they were left to die by his tribe when
Teujin was 8 years old. And if you are
abandoned by your tribe in Mongolia in
the winter, it means certain death.
Even today, even today, that's how harsh
Mongolia's terrain and climate is. But
somehow they survived. And Chigasan
spent the first after after his father's
death, he spent about 35 36 37 years
fighting fighting first just to survive
and then when he became more powerful,
he was he was fighting various tribe
Mongolian tribes to unite them all. And
it's only in his mid40s that he was able
to defeat and unite all the Mongolian
tribes and create an empire. And that's
when he decided that we need to invade
China and teach the the Chinese a lesson
for what they've been doing to us for
the past several centuries. Uh so that
is Chingish Khan. A very different
upbringing, very different background
from Kurush. Totally different. Kurush
was born into power and wealth. His
father was the emperor.
Right? similarities uh well I don't know
similarities both were polytheists no
kurush was zoroastrian so zoroastrianism
is is is well today it's portrayed as
monotheistic even zorostranism has
multiple divinities so not entirely
monotheistic and uh yeah they were both
visionary leaders kurush conquered much
of west Asia and he liberated the Greeks
from the claws of the Assyrians
uh and uh allowed them to go back to
Judea to present day Israel, all of
that. Um
and and obviously the Mongol Empire was
greater than the empire of the Akameids,
greater in size, in strength, in
explosive expansionist power, all of
that totally different. So yeah, that's
a comparison. Let's say Dnur Singh says
for someone who wants me to ask you
this, how does Ghar Raja have so much
power? What's the source of power of
Ghar Raja despite not being backed by
the US constitution? How does it
influence a deep state?
How does it have so much power? What is
the source of its power? Okay,
fundamentals, basics. Let's go back to
first principles. First principles
thinking what is power
in the simp in the simp the simplest
possible explanation is this power is
the ability to get things done.
I have this hill outside my building. I
don't like this hill. I want the hill to
be gone. Can I get can I make the hill
disappear? If I can make this hill
disappear, I have power. How do I do it?
Do I go and start digging it? No. I ask
a 100 guys who work for me to go and dig
it up. That's power. But what if instead
of 100 guys, I have a thousand guys.
Well, then I can have 10 hills
disappear. What if I have a million guys
at my disposal? And what if they're
armed to the teeth and they will obey me
unquestioningly? Well, that makes me
kind of a superpower now. So, that is
power. Power is always
based on the ability to get things done,
especially violent things.
The more capable of violence you are,
the more powerful you are. Even if you
choose not to exercise the power, the
ability of violence that you have. So
when you say that the Ghar Raja has so
much power, the deep state has so so
much power. It means they command so
much destructive power in their hands.
They have it at at their disposal. Now
which destructive power do they command?
The United States and its resources,
right? It means that they command all
the resources of the United States
including the economy, the military, the
nuclear might and the administrative and
governance mechanism. Then we understand
why they why they are so powerful. But
how are they so powerful when there's
nothing in the US constitution about a
deep state?
Well, what if
what if you are a small group of people
who have who know all the deep dark
secrets of all the politicians who are
part of the constitutional framework.
What if you know all the deep this is a
hypothetical situation. I am not saying
I know what's happening. I'm just saying
hypothetically.
If you are a small group of let's say 20
people and you know all the deep dark
deep dark secrets of all the politicians
who are part of the constitutional
framework then will they not will it not
give you complete control over the
politicians? What if you own the bank
that is the country's reserve bank? Will
it not give you control over the
nation's economy and by extension the
world's economy?
And if you control the the politicians
who control the military, do you not
control the military and the nuclear
arsenal?
And maybe it's not just blackmail power.
Maybe it's also economic power. Maybe
you have so much money you can buy
anybody off and they're all controlled
by you because you are drip feeding
money to them.
This is a completely hypothetical
scenario that I'm painting for you. But
such a scenario kind of works, doesn't
it?
And you don't need to be based in that
country. You could be based anywhere.
Once again, Dur Singh, I know you are
thinking in that direction. It's
possible you may be based somewhere
else. So, you see that's how it works.
Theoretically, hypothetically, I'm not
saying that's a situation necessarily,
but theoretically that that's how it can
work.
Nand Kishor says, why is the slave US
hostile to India but master Israel
isn't?
Well, first of all, you are putting
words in my mouth by making me assume
that the US is the slave of the of
Israel.
I am not saying it is. Do we have
evidence? Some people say there is
plenty of evidence. Some see when I
generally speak about the US or Israel,
I get two kinds of comments in the
comment section. One says the US is the
master and Israel is the vasal. That's
one category of comments about 50%. The
other 50% say Israel is the master and
the US is the is the vasal. So which is
which? Which is which? I don't know.
Right. Uh so the question is that look
first we can agree all agree on one
thing that the US and Israel have a very
special relationship they do right best
of relationship but the US is hostile to
India Israel isn't why is that well
is Israel entirely benign towards India
we we have a great relationship with is
with with Israel strategic relationship
strategic partnership you could say
significant convergence of interests now
tell me something my friends my friends
My friends, my friends, answer this
question
in the subcontinent.
Historically, the US has had one
long-term reliable vasal, West Pakistan,
also known as Pakistan.
So the US has Pakistan as its loyal
vasal mostly more or less loyal vasal
and Israel and US have a special
relationship
and some said that Israel is the master
of the US some say
so then
what's the relationship between Israel
and Pakistan in that case if
hypothetically Israel is America's
master and America is Pakistan's
who doesn't mean Israel is de facto
Pakistan's master.
Yeah. Doesn't mean that. Now Pakistan
officially you you people will many of
you will say no but Pakistan says Israel
does not have a right to exist. We don't
recognize Israel.
We don't have diplomatic relations. Okay
good. So when Aim Munir goes to
Washington and the Pakistani embassy
holds some kind of banquet or dinner for
in Aim Aim Mun's honor, why is why is
there the presence of Israeli
military personnel there?
So if you look at all these things, can
you really say that Israel is entirely
benign towards India? It's all
everything is well in the relationship.
Can you really say that
India and and Israel still have a great
relationship? Overall, it's one of the
best relationships India has. But like
any relationship between any two people,
there's always something or the other
which is not entirely congruent. You
see,
godliness says, can we in the future
build a nuclearpowered stealth drone
with AI as its pilot? Theoretically, it
can be done. a nuclear ramjet or a
nuclear scramjet.
It can be made. The Russians have a
missile that's powered by nuclear
uh energy. It's not a nuclear weapon
tipped missile. It could be, but the
source of energy, the source of
combustion is a nuclearpowered ram
ramjet. So this missile theoretically
has unlimited range. It can fly for for
months.
You certainly can. Stealth drone will be
a little more difficult because you need
a whole nuclear power plant in this
thing which is a little harder to do.
But theoretically even this is possible.
So you can have a nuclearpowered drone
or stealth drone potentially depending
on the technology you use with AI as its
pilot. Yeah, it is possible certainly.
Anonymous scientist is here. Bonjour.
What are your thoughts on the strongest
sign strongest signals of microbial life
detected near GZ crater on Mars? Really?
Let's discover it together.
Okay. G0 crater. G00
crater.
Uh Mars bios signatures. Interesting.
What is it? Na. Okay. 8 hours ago
something has happened or 4 days ago.
Let's see what NASA has to say. NASA
says Mars rover discovered potential bio
signature last year.
A sample collected by NASA's
Perseverance Mars rover from an ancient
dry river bed in Zero Crater could uh
blah blah blah potential potential bio
signatures. Okay. They published a paper
in nature. Let's say the paper in
nature. Okay. Redux blah blah blah
driven mineral
the perseverance
investigated all that stuff. Okay.
Detailed geological petrographic blah
blah blah.
Organic carbon bearing mudstones contain
subm scale nodules and millimeter scale
reaction fronts enriched by ferrus ion
phosphate and sulfide minerals like
likely vivvenite and grigite
respectively. The organic carbon appears
to have participated in post
depositional redux reactions that
produce the obser
at low temperatures. We review the
various pathways by which redux
reactions can involve organic matter. Uh
that
ultimately we conclude that analysis of
the core sample collected from this unit
using blah blah blah will enable the
okay so this paper is not claiming
anything conclusive but it is being
interpreted by NASA that it has
potential bio signatures
and then the times of India says NASA
finds clearest sign. So you can see how
each stage there is an escalation. The
nature paper says that we've discovered
this and there are certain reactions
that that uh the the the signatures of
certain redux reactions are visible on
this millimeter and submar scale nodules
and we investigated the various pathways
through which these reactions could have
happened at low temperature regimes.
That's what the nature paper says. It
doesn't draw at least the abstract that
I read doesn't draw any conclusions
about any bio signatures or potential
bios signatures and maybe if I read the
whole paper which will take half an hour
I there may be something some clues more
some more clues but the NASA press
release says there are potential bio
signatures and then the times of India
report which is quoting the NASA release
potentially it says this is the clearest
sign of life. So journalists
tend to overexaggerate everything you
see. So I think it's it's still too
early to make any such claims clearly
from the paper that we just saw
but interesting that you brought this up
and I did not I was not aware of it. So
thank you so much.
DNU Singh says do we even have an actual
uniting language? Well globally we today
have English which is a colonial
language which is a imperial language.
It's like the days of Pax Romana
when all the nations that had been
vasalized and conquered and vasalized by
Rome, they all spoke Roman to each
other, Latin because that was the only
common language they knew. So today the
whole world has been essentially at some
point in time either colonized or
vasalized by the Anglos. So we all speak
English as the world language today.
It's not something to be proud of but it
is what it is. Uh does India have an
uniting language? Well, it was always
Sanskrit. Today you see the British left
behind
divisions in society which they had
created. They created all kinds of
artificial divisions in the country in
in Indian society because they were
afraid of a unified India. They saw what
happened in 1857 when Indians united for
a change. So they wanted to ensure it
never happens again. So they created all
kinds of artificial divisions within
India. Religious divisions within
religion they they invented forecasts.
We had the verna jati system which was a
totally different thing. People cared
about jati not about vera or cast. The
British superimposed a four tire cast
system and officialized and legalized it
and we are still continuing that. So
there is that division. Then there's the
linguistic divisions. Then there's all
kind of aranidian divisions and things
like that. So because of these the
legacy of the British rule or India, we
have all these little divisions that
have cropped up in India and those are
being exacerbated by political parties
and foreign forces today
which is why Sanskrit is so
controversial. The one thing that can
that has historically united India today
they have made it controversial so that
India can't unite again. The unifying
language is Sanskrit. It is not a dead
dead language.
We use Sanskrit vocabulary and grammar
in all our languages today. North or
south India, wherever
you speak Harriani, it's a Sanskrit
derived language.
Most of the words came from Sanskrit.
The entire grammar structure came from
Sanskrit. Of course, there are some some
changes which are inevitable like
Italian from Roman, Italian from Latin.
There are some changes, but it's still a
language that came from Latin, right?
That way. So, the unifying language has
to be Sanskrit. It has been our
civilizational language but today it's
it's being turned into a gigantic
controversy where half the country will
not accept it.
Ankita says now that the name of the PM
candidate in Nepal is clear. What would
you say? Regime change operation in
Nepal successful or foiled
wait and watch. No knee-jerk reactions
because it takes time for the dust to
clear and for the truth to become
apparent. So right now we have what
looks like
somebody who was elected through a
discord vote. That's that's what
journalists and media outlets are saying
that the Jenzi students came together
and said that we will not our let our
movement be hijacked by opportunistic
external forces and they did a vote on
discord and they decided that this lady
Madame Susila Kharki will be our interim
caretaker prime minister.
Now who are they to decide? Who is Hami
Nepal to decide this thing? Is Hammy
Nepal a genzi organization?
Hammy Nepal is an NGO that has plenty of
foreign funding. There the head of Hami
Nepal is uh this gentleman called Sudan
Gurong. I think he's 34 35 years old. Is
that Jenzi?
There are plenty of unresolved questions
right now.
I am not making any I'm not drawing any
conclusions right now.
It is very tempting if you are in the
business let's say of YouTube or if
you're an influ influencer to make
immediate instantaneous knee-jerk
predictions. This is what I'm
predicting. This is what I blah blah
blah. I am not in that game. I'm going
to take my time. I have already put my
neck out and I've said that this is a US
mediated regime in operation.
Now let's wait and watch. This lady is
the caretaker, interim, de facto,
whatever prime minister, which means
that she is the lady who will occupy the
seat of the prime minister. The seat is
not the place where power lies. Power
lies somewhere else. Who controls the
the Nepalese armed forces and police
forces
right now?
Who controls them? Who will they support
politically?
That's where the power lies. So for that
to become clear, we'll have to wait and
watch.
But I have already said this that this
has all the hallmarks of a US mediated
regime change operation. So when you
want to obiscate that, you bring in a
non-controversial person and put them in
a ceremonial role.
So it looks no this is not regime
change. Look at this lady.
She has no connections with the US.
She was a Supreme Court person. her
husband was a nationalist politician.
She's the last person who would be this.
Well, because of that, she's the best
person. So, we will see. I am not going
to jump to any conclusions right now.
Let's wait and watch. In a few days,
things will become much more clear. It's
too early to start drawing conclusions
right now.
Okay, Mama Bucket VFX. Well, thank you
so much. Very nice of you. Thank you.
Divor Singh says we have 20 different
clubs for 10 20 different states in
India. No unity. Are we tribal in
nature? All humans are by nature
tribalistic. It's in our blood. It's in
our DNA. It dates back to the time when
we ran from predators on the savylvanas
and steps of Africa. Our brains have
evolved to be able to look far for
threats and unite in small bands and
keep moving, keep running, keep
foraging, hunter gatherers. That's what
we have been for the longest part of our
history, which is about a couple of
million years ever since we split off
from our closest cousins, the
chimpanzees.
Chimpanzes, if you look at them, they're
tribal in nature. They're very much like
us. So by DNA we are tribalistic
but the past 10 20,000 years whenever it
happened we have tried to transcend this
tribalism
by constructing something entirely
unnatural
civilization
and the oldest civilization is us.
the oldest known civilization, the
longest surviving civilization.
But the tribalistic nature is still
there in our blood. So civilization is a
civilizing force which makes us
transcend tribalism. But when
civilization itself weakens,
that's when tribalism resurfaces.
So this entire thing that you are seeing
this decentralization this feudalism so
not feudalism federalism
this this prioritization of sub
civilizational subnational identities
all of that this tells you that our
civilization is weakening. We are no
longer genuinely a civilization state
today. We are no longer rooted in our
culture. Our constitution is foreign in
nature. Our laws are foreign in nature.
Our institutions are foreign in nature.
Our system of governance is foreign in
nature. Our bureaucracy is a foreign
imposition. Our education system is
foreign in India. The language we speak
is foreign.
Our c culture in civilization is slowly
being erased. And when you start losing
your civilization, tribalism surfaces.
That's what we are seeing in India.
These are very alarming signs. It's not
happening in rapid at a rapid pace. It's
happening very slowly, very gradually.
So it doesn't look alarming.
But consider how India was 30 years ago
and consider how it is today. A lot has
changed and India has gone far
far more towards tribalism than it was
20 30 years ago. This is very alarming
for India. What the west wants is they
want India to fragment. They want India
to be balconized
then they can deal with the different
parts of India individually.
So this is being
mediated from outside and we are simply
living in La La Land and essentially
doing nothing about it. So we are tribal
in nature. We are not tribal in nature
as as a civilization but we are tribal
by DNA by blood. That's homo sapiens for
you tribal
but civilization it seeks to transcend
that. You see
satellite says how much of the world
will survive if any after a nuclear war.
What will happen eventually as 10,000
plus nuclear weapons won't just
disappear magically? I'll tell you what.
Um when the Cuban missile crisis
happened 1962 was it whenever it was?
Yeah. 62 most likely.
At that time the US had about 25,000
nuclear warheads. Only the US had about
25,000 nuclear warheads. The Soviets had
about 3,000 3,500 roughly, give or take
nuclear warheads. That's almost 30,000
at the time.
Today, you have about 10 11,000 warheads
in total officially. That's what people
say. I don't know what the truth is.
So clearly, we came down from that level
and we had all those treaties in the
1980s. Mr. Gorbachev and Mr. Reagan they
met in Geneva when I was in Geneva as a
kid I think it was 1985 and that was the
what's the start treaty or whatever it
was and they brought down the the the
stockpiles on both sides so that the the
level of potential
destruction could be lowered that sort
of thing. Um so today we have about
10,000 plus 10 11,000 nuclear warheads
in existence. That's the official stated
figure and that itself is enough to
devastate the world. So in case there's
a nuclear war, nuclear exchange in which
all of these weapons are used, what does
it do?
If you have 10,000 nuclear explosions,
okay, tens of kilotons, hundreds of
kilotons, some are megat tons of of of
yield in terms of kilotons in terms of
TNT.
And of if these nuclear warheads are
detonated over land and 10,000 of them
are detonated, it will
it will put out a gigantic dust cloud in
the atmosphere.
And this dust cloud will be dust which
has been pushed out and pulverized rock
and whatnot, vaporized rock, vaporized
forests, vaporized whatever. a gigantic
dust cloud will go up into the
atmosphere and it will surround surround
the entire earth. So the earth will be
enveloped in a thick cloud of dust. This
will this situation will persist for a
few years. There will be no sunlight on
the planet for for a few years. So
immediately temp global temperatures
will drop. So whoever has survived the
nuclear explosions
will now have to face a global winter.
So within a few hours you you would have
a situation where you will have snow in
Sri Lanka, snow falling in Sri Lanka
and in Mauritius
and there will be no sunlight for a few
years possibly at least a few months.
When there's no sunlight the plants die
because there's no photosynthesis. If
the plants die, animals die.
Well, then what happens to us? So in
this scenario, most of humanity will die
out.
Only those who have access to to to
stored grains
for and supplies that will last several
years. Only those people will survive.
Everybody else dies. So you may have a
few thousand or maybe a few tens of
thousands humans surviving at best by
the time the the cloud lifts. So that's
the situation. Yeah. Most of humanity
will die out. Most of the animals will
die out. It's like a an impact event.
The kind of impact event that killed off
the non-avian dinosaurs. That sort of
situation will will arise.
Vimnor Singh says, "Tell us about the
battle of Waterloo and how one family of
bankers knew the result even before the
British." Yeah, I don't know about that.
The battle of Waterloo was was obviously
famous famous right um Admiral Nelson
was it if you go to Trafalgar Square in
London whose statue it's Nelson there
right
um yes so Waterloo was obviously
Waterloo for Napoleon it was the defeat
of Napoleon at the hands of the British
who was it just the British or was it a
coalition it was mostly the British if I
remember I don't remember that part that
portion of history in great detail right
now. Um, did one family of bankers know
the result beforehand? I I don't know
about that.
Did they know before the British? Yeah.
Listen, my memory is a little hazy about
this part of history. And this one
family, I don't know anything about them
because I have not studied their
history. I think you're referring to the
to the rot shells, but I have not
studied the rot shells. So even if you
ask me further questions about though
about that particular angle of history I
won't have much to much to tell you
because I haven't studied the ro shells.
I think it is maybe time for me to study
them because I'm getting so many
questions about them. Uh
Dn Singh says JP Morgan almost owned the
whole of America at a point. How is
that? JP Morgan the banker right Morgan
Chase Bank and all that.
Yeah, the US is is JP Morgan. Now, what
was this guy's history? He isn't isn't
Rockefeller the oil baron. JP Morgan.
Yeah, I'm a little hazy about JP Morgan
also.
You had all these all these where am I
the Rockefellers? They Rockefeller was
into oil then he was into
pharmaceuticals
and uh he wanted a certain kind of
education system in the US. And JP
Morgan is also one of the great colossal
titans. But I don't really I'm a little
hazy about that that about the history
of JP JP Morgan. So not sure I can
really give you much details about this
either.
Okay. Godliness says create controlled
anarchy for a few days. Dismantle the
current government. Then magically the
sleeping army will intervene and
everything goes back to normal. Can this
happen to the master himself? The US
Can this happen to the US? It's very
difficult, very very hard to see this
happening in the US.
Um, why is it why is that so?
Because for something like this to
happen, you need a controlling force.
See, spontaneous protests and
spontaneous revolutions,
they are
disorganized and chaotic by nature.
and they are disorganized which means
they're not organized there isn't coord
you don't have coordination you don't
have logistical uh support you don't
have all of that so it can happen but
it'll eventually fizzle out and if the
governance machinery which is
coordinated very well if it just
you know bites it its time it can deal
with anything and and obviously if you
look at the United States it's a police
state anyone who lives in the West knows
this.
If you don't understand what I mean,
spend 3 months in India, then spend 3
months in the US, then come back to
India and you will immediately see the
difference. The US is a police state.
Cops all over the place. Go to New York
City, cops everywhere, cops with guns
everywhere. You take those cops away
from New York City for 15 minutes, there
will be riots on the street, on the
streets of New York City. The cops keep
the peace. So the US is a police state
and if you want to create anarchy there
well you will have to come up against
the whole full might of the US state and
all its various arms and branches. So
you have the straight you know you have
the the the cops you have the state
troopers you have the the the armed
forces the army itself the military the
the citizens can't stand up against
against that.
Um, so it's it's very hard for something
like this to happen in the US. And can
an external power do something like
this? Well, the most powerful power is
the US. So I think it's very hard for
something like this to happen in the US.
But what can happen is 1963 like
situation in which the US itself took
out its own president.
So the deep state essentially took out
JFK. That's what is alleged. And clearly
there's a cover up because clearly it's
not like there was one shooter. Clearly
he was not shot from behind. If you see
the Zapru Zapru film, it's clear he was
shot from the front.
But the official report says he was he
was shot from behind. Well, the head
shot when it happens, his head is thrown
backwards, which means the velocity the
the momentum is coming from the from the
forward direction. So it's clear that
it's a cover up. So the US took out its
own president. So that's sort of that.
So essentially 1963 was a coup against
the president. that sort of thing can
happen but a regime change is very hard
for for us to see happening in the US.
Anonymous says one of the retired wing
commanders of the IIAF tweeted about a
Nepal-like situation in India. She we
have a female wing commander retired of
the IIAF.
She even urged Indian Jenzi to replicate
what Nepalese protesters did to their
finance ministers against the Indian
finance minister.
>> Okay, I am not aware of this. First of
all, this is the first time I'm seeing
this news, but I'm sure what you're
saying must be right. So, in case it is
correct, well, that's that's horrific.
And it kind of tells you that there are
there are serious problems within India
and many Indians are compromised. It
looks like
especially people who are potentially
influential and who have had been who
have been in positions of power. It
looks like it's very easy to buy them
out. Some of them, not all, some of
them. I'm sure most are honest and
patriotic, but it looks like some of
them, these people can be bought out. I
am aware of some journalists who are
clearly foreign stooges. I'm aware of
some retired armed forces personnel,
some only a few who clearly work for
foreign powers or at least
are favorably inclined towards foreign
powers. So yeah, like I've said before,
there are many aspiring zalinskies in
India.
So I suppose the government of India
will have to keep these people under
observation and keep tabs on their
activities and keep tabs on where the
funds are coming in from. Yeah. But
yeah, it's terrible.
Right. Brother 8 says I am NPI.
I'm Nepalese. Nepal is Indian. Okay.
Some people in Nepal don't respect India
because of expansionist mindset.
Nepal is older than India.
India looks at its neighbors like
something lost from India. India's
expansionist mindset.
Sir, what are you talking about? India's
expansionist mindset. How many countries
has India invaded? Sir, how many?
Have we invaded some foreign country, a
neighboring country? When has India done
that? Does India claim someone's
territory? Does India claim that so and
so state of of of Bangladesh is our our
territory and so and so whatever do we
behave like China claims territory from
all its neighbors does India do that
does India have a hegemonic mindset
towards other countries
I I don't know why the Nepalese people
have been brainwashed into believing
that we are the enemy India we are the
same people Nepal is older than India
now what is Yes,
Nepal was created by Shri uh Priti
Narayan Sha the great Gora king who
created the kingdom. He was not the
first king of the lineage. It was his
great great grandfather or somebody like
that few generations before him who
founded the dynasty and Shri Priti
Narancha was the greatest of the kings
and who conquered the Nar Valley or
Nepal valley and created the kingdom and
it was an expansionist kingdom which
expanded that's why Nepal is the size
that it is. It was initially a small
kingdom. So Nepal so Shri Prasin Narayan
Sha was an expansionist king and he
expanded the kingdom. Then when the
British took over the subcontinent they
decided that they wanted to keep Nepal
as a buffer state between India and
Tibet where you had some Chinese
activity. So they wanted a buffer state
which is why they did not annex Nepal
and that's why Nepal stayed independent
quasi sovereign
um and then India was given some kind of
what dominion status in 1947 by 1950
India became a republic.
Now you see that Nepal is older than
India. Nepal was founded in the 1700s
by Shri Pratin Aaran Sha. Bhart Wash has
been around for 10,000 plus years and
Nepal is part of that Nepal the name
itself did not exist before 1700s.
Right? So I don't understand why this
attitude exists or maybe I do understand
because the godamned Mao have been
ruling your country for the past 30 plus
years and they have brainwashed all the
youth into hating their own people.
So that's why there is this hatred or
this fear of India and it is not the
please I'll tell my Indian viewers it is
not the fault of the Nepalese people
that they have this this this
view of India. It's not their fault.
They believe they genuinely believe that
India is is an is a evil aggressive
expansionist country. That's what
they've been taught since they were 3
years old. What do you expect?
So yeah, this is the situation where
where two peoples were the same people
have been alienated.
Uh India looks at this neighbors as
something lost from India. Of course
we were once a united subcontinent,
right? Under one civilization.
So how do I see Nepal? Okay, forget
about this that hypothetical. How do I
see Nepal? I see Nepal as a sovereign
nation. I see Nepal as another nation
state which is the same people and
culture and civilization as us. And I
would actually say that Nepal should
remain a separate nation. Many Indians
say that Nepal should be absorbed into
India, reabsorbed. I see that Nepal
should be should stay a separate
sovereign state so that it is not
secularized like India. I would like to
see the resurgence of of a Hindu
raashtra in Nepal. That's what you
should have.
I want Nepal to remain sovereign
independent and you need to return to
your civilizational roots. We have lost
our civilizational roots. You should
regain that. That's what I would say.
Okay. All
right, what do we have next? Divor Singh
says, "Why don't we talk about 60
million Christians killed in the
Bolshevik Revolution? Isn't West a
Christian empire? Am I noticing too
much?
The Bolshevik revolution killed 60
million Christians." Well, it killed 60
million
Russians
and Russians were Christians by that
time. They had been deaganized. I'm sure
it killed Tatars also. Tatars happened
to be Muslims.
But uh it is true that it killed about
60 million Christians or whatever.
And I think what you're what you're
implying is perhaps that the leaders of
the Bolsheviks weren't Christians. Is
that what you're implying, sir?
Are you noticing too much? Okay, let's
let's let us notice together. Okay. uh
Dnor G is saying that
uh let's just do a simple query uh who
were the top leaders
of the Bolshevik
revolution
Vladimir Lenin blah blah blah who are
the leaders
okay
who is a Safhonovich Yenjik Okay.
Um, da citizenship, political career,
career, Kremlin plot, communist party.
He was shot during the great purge. Oh,
that's tragic. So, what is his
background? That's what I'm trying to
find out.
It doesn't tell me about his background.
There's no early life situation here.
What about Khalen?
Mikail Ivanovich Khalin
and early life Georgia.
No, nothing special about his early
life. What about Bkharin?
Bkharin.
Bkharin was born etc.
Not sure. So is there anything special
about the top leaders of the Tomsky?
Okay. What about Lenin? He was a Tatar.
Was he was he a what was he
born children
orthodox Christian church Lutheran
Christianity
fuash mudwin kamlik
okay so I'm trying to look at the the
anticcedants of the leaders of the
bolshevik but I'm not really able to
find anything u
specific
so yeah I I think if you really want to
make a case for something, you have to
dig out the details and present the
details in a very specific uh concise
form. Then then we can have a more
detailed discussion about things. But
yeah, most of the people killed in the
ble revolution were Christians. That's
true. I don't think there there's any
dispute about that. Yeah.
Ah, our friend James is here. Well, it's
always good to see James. Good to see
you, sir. All Indian leaders will be of
low caliber and men of straw. They will
have sweet tongues and silly hearts and
they'll fight amongst themselves said
Winston Churchill. These are his words.
Now let's since James is making the
statement let us fact check it to
assertain the veracity of the statement.
Okay. Churchill quote. Okay. Let's let's
go here.
uh churchill
church
chill quote all Indians all Indian
leaders.
Okay. So this is the quote.
If independence is granted to India,
power will go to the hands of rascals,
rogues, freebters. All Indian leaders
will be of low caliber and men of straw.
They will have sweet tongues and silly
hearts. They will fight amongst
themselves for power and India will be
lost in political squables. The day
would come when even air and water would
be taxed in India.
Well, I would like to ask my dear
viewers,
look, I am no fan of Churchill. Son of a
[\h__\h] He was so
Churchill. But this statement that he
made Churchill,
was he right or was was he wrong, was
Churchill right
that Indian leaders will be men of
straw?
They'll fight amongst themselves.
They'll make the people fight amongst
themselves. They will even tax air and
water.
Yeah, that's what he said. They will
have sweet tongues and silly hearts.
There will be rascals and rogues and
free booters people of there will be men
of low caliber. They will fight among
themselves for power and India will be
lost in political squables. Is it true?
I think Churchill was absolutely right
about this.
Now how did he know this will happen?
It's because the British had created a
system in India, an environment in
India,
that the system can simply not produce a
leader. Let me explain the profoundity
of what James is pointing out to us over
here and the profoundity of Churchill's
statement. How was Churchill able to
make such an accurate prediction?
What Churchill said is absolutely true
of the vast majority of Indian leaders
and politicians today. Not all of them
but the vast majority.
So how did he know this
and how was it how did it turn out to be
true? It's because the British
instituted a system in India that is
designed to produce clerks and peons.
The British education system which still
continues in India today. The system is
designed to produce mass-roduce
lowquality lowc caliber people.
A highly intelligent super curious
bright child at 3 years of age goes into
the education system. By the time he or
she comes out of the education system by
the age of 21, 22 whatever that person
has lost every quality he or she had.
Everything has been smashed out of them.
They have been broken.
That's what is done. So the system it
identifies and destroys talent. If you
have leadership potential, it'll destroy
that. It'll turn up. It'll it'll
mass-produce so-called leaders who are
good at talking. Oh, I have won so many
compet so many so many debate
competitions. So, I'm a leader. I have
leadership quality.
That's not leadership quality. There is
blah blah blah. Leadership quality is
something entirely different. Just
because you know how to do a debate
doesn't make you a leader. So the entire
system is designed to mass-roduce
fraudulent
quality
fake leaders
mass-produce inferior citizens.
So such a system will will and and and
apart from that the system the British
designed was entirely based on
corruption
and they institutionalized corruption in
across the system only for Indians not
for themselves. So when a British person
would go to the uh Indian legal British
Indian legal system they would never be
asked for bribes. But the same legal
system if an Indian went there they
would be asked for bribes. So this was
another means of oppressing Indians and
keeping Indians down and this was
continued after the British left. So
this was guaranteed to produce
corruption in all aspects of society.
So Churchill knew exactly what was going
to happen because they laid the
groundwork for this situation to happen.
And because we did not dismantle the
British system after 1947, we continued
it and we built upon that. That's why
our foundations are rotten today and
that's why Churchill is 100% entirely
right. This is the system he and his
people designed and it still exists in
India today. So that's why it's
producing the results that he had
predicted. Do you understand all of you?
Well, James, thank you so much for
pointing this out. I appreciate that.
MK says post samurai Japan committed
atrocities before because they left
Dharma. Then why did ancient Greeks and
Romans commit horrific violence like
Alexander? They also left Dharma
were Greeks Dharmic people, sir.
Did they follow the Vic path?
Did they worship the old gods in the old
ways? They had left the Vic path. They
still worship the old gods with new
names in different forms
and their mythology also got distorted.
See for example in our Vic pantheon we
have Indra and Indra's father is Petro
Zeus
Petru became Zeus Peter became Jupiter.
Zeus Pet Zeus Peter is Greek Jupiter is
Roman. So they took Diosh Petru his name
and they gave it to the Indra-like
figure the hammer and thunder god and
they called him Zeus. And if you look at
the stories if you read the book by
Edith Hamilton for example about Greek
and western mythology you will see that
the Zeus in Greek mythology is a serial
philanderer.
He is a man he's a god of loose morals.
Do you see that as being very dharmic?
They corrupted their own gods
and the Romans took the whole system
from the Greeks and they they took the
gods and gave them new names, similar
names. So Zeus, Peter became Jupiter for
the Romans and so on. So a corrupted
pantheon was further corrupted
unknowingly by the Romans. So are we
surprised then
that the Greeks under Alexander
committed all kinds of horrific
atrocities? Burning people alive,
burning villages alive, crucifying
people just for fun, for example,
enslaving entire populations of cities,
thieves, for example,
or or or what he did at Akre was it?
Yeah, Akar, I suppose, before he went to
Egypt like crucifying people on the
seashore.
Would a dharmic person do that? The
Greeks were no longer Dharmic. My dear
friends, please think logically.
Your question contains the answer. Okay.
All right.
Harshai says, "How did ancient kings
used to manage polygamas relationships?"
Like Bindusar had 100 wives. How
practical is it in today's time? Should
go for it.
Bindusar. Bindusar had 100 wives. I I
don't know how many wives he had. But
look,
see our our religion, our culture is a
very accepting and tolerant and
respectful culture. It says do whatever
you want. As long as you don't do any
sins, do whatever you want. You want to
have three wives, go have three wives.
You want to have 17 wives. If the ladies
are willing, how do we care? You do what
you want. No one's going to stop you.
So, how do you manage it? Well, first of
all, do you have the means to sustain
such a large family?
Huh? You have the wealth, you want to
have 100 wives. Okay. And let's say the
ladies are willing. You have the means
to sustain such a large family. You can
have 100 wives. You will eventually have
100 kids or who knows how many
depending.
So, do you have the means to sustain
that? First of all, you to be wealthy,
right?
So, ancient kings were wealthy.
So then uh there's no logistical issue.
There we have it. How practical is it in
today's time? Let's let's say see hers
let's say you want to have five wives.
Okay, I have nothing against that. Let's
say you find five ladies who are willing
who are okay that yeah we're going to
have a marriage in which there are five
wives and one husband. No secrets, no
nothing hidden. Let's say they agree.
The question is hers do you have the
financial means to sustain this to
provide for a family in which you have
five wives obviously you will need
sufficient room for this extended family
right a 2 BHK will not do now even a 4
BHK will not do you will need a
multi-story bungalow or maybe multiple
bungalows especially once you have kids
do you have the funds to sustain that so
it's it's a question of practicality
this is not a question of morals or
ethics
It's a practical, logistical question.
Do you have the means to provide for all
of this? That's all. If you have, well,
I have nothing against it. You want to
go for it, you go for it. I'm okay with
it. I will not I will not oppose that.
Okay.
Uh AKM says, "What's your trick to focus
for 8 hours straight?" When you do
something you enjoy, you can focus.
when you are for let's say you are let's
say you are 15 years old or let's say
you're 12 years old and you are pretty
you're reasonably intelligent you're
intelligent enough to understand that
your your school textbooks are garbage
and and reading them is going to
actually corrupt your mind and and and
degrade the quality of your intellect
but let's say your parents tell you
every day you must study 8 hours a day
otherwise
so then you will have to go go to the
desk, put those goddamn textbooks in in
front of you and you'll have to stare at
them
and your brain rebels. Your mind rebels.
It is torture. It is mental torture for
you to do that. But if you go and play,
then your parents will punish you.
So you have no choice but to sit there.
So what do you do? Can you focus?
For a while you'll try to focus. Then
what happens? Your mind will drift off
here, there, wherever. So you will be
physically sitting there for 8 hours.
But out of those 8 hours, 6 hours,
you'll be mentally somewhere else. You
can't focus because you hate this. This
is torture.
But on the other hand, if you enjoy
something, if that's what you have
always wanted to do, why will you not be
able to focus? There are people who do
gaming, right? They they're obsessed
with gaming. They game for 12 hours
straight. God knows a whole day, whole
night straight. Why can they focus?
Because they enjoy it. It's their
passion. That's the answer. That's the
simplest answer in the world. There you
have it.
Okay. Dur Singh says the British used to
fight without clothes with colored faces
in Roman times.
So the Romans uh report wrote about the
British. Julius Caesar was a historian.
You know that
uh he wrote about he wrote he maintained
detailed records of his of his uh
military uh conquests. Mhm.
>> So his conquest of gold he spoke about
the different kinds of gold. You have
you have cis alpine and transalpine gold
which is the nearer goal and the further
gold from Rome from from Rome. Yeah. And
then about the British about the
conquest of the British territories,
British Isles which is pretty difficult
for him to do. Uh and he wrote about the
different kinds of tribes you have in
the in the British islands. you have the
pictish tribes tribe uh who are further
in the north towards present day
Scotland and various other Bretonic
tribes here and there and he spoke about
something the alleged vicker men
execution that the the the British used
to have perhaps it was an exaggeration
they would create a huge human figure
made of vicker which is wood thin wood
and the condemned would be put inside
and then they would be burned to death
it's called the vicker man execution so
he wrote copiously about the British and
he wrote that many of the British tribes
were utterly barbaric. They were naked
people who would paint their faces
either blue or red or whatever and they
would consume only one thing, milk,
cow's milk, no other food. And it's it's
plausible. So the Romans the Romans had
rather unflattering descriptions
uh of the of the people of the British
islands. Now we have to remember one
thing. the the British
natives that the Romans
uh came across,
those were the original Celtic
inhabitants
of the British islands of the British
Isles, the Celtic peoples.
After the Romans left around 400 500 AD,
there was an invasion of the British
islands
by the Angles and the Saxons who were a
Germanic people and they defeated the
Celtic peoples and they established an
overlordship over the British Isles
which is why the British culture is
called Anglo-Saxon culture. So the
angles and Saxons, the Romans, if they
came across them, they would have come
across them in Germany, in Saxony, in
Germany, not in the British Isles. And
around and in the year 1066, there was a
new invasion of the British Isles, which
was by the Normans,
William the Conqueror, and that's how
the French language dominated for a
while, and it eventually coalesed into
what is now called the English language.
So the British people, the Romans
encountered were the original Celtic
natives of
Britain, not today's British. Today's
British will have some of that ancestry,
but not fully that.
Anonymous says, "Ago you mentioned that
India needs some critical infrastructure
and pointed out that India doesn't have
a worldclass observatory.
Can you please name all the critical
infra India needs to build?" Okay.
critical infrastructure India needs to
build. An observatory isn't critical
infrastructure. It's nice to have if
you're a scientist, if you're a
physicist, if you're an astronomer, if
you're into cosmology, astrophysics, all
that. Uh critical infrastructure, roads,
high quality roads, roads, they don't
have to be reconstructed every year
to fill someone's pockets.
Road. Once you build a road, it should
last at least 10 years. High quality
roads, flat roads, not uneven, bumpy
roads. It's the least you can do.
So, India needs roads, highways all
across the country across the length,
length and the breadth of the country.
That's one. Number two, railways.
Uh you need way more railways than we
have right now. Third, airports. We just
have 150, 60, 70, whatever. We have less
than 200 airports I believe in the
country. Let's let's fact check that in
case I am uh mistaken. Let us fact check
that. How many airports does India have?
How many airports
does India have? 427 airports and
airirst strips. But proper airports is
about
so the airports authority of India
manages 153 of these and there are 160
additional air strips, helip ports
whatever. So it's actually about 150
that are maintained by the airports
authority of India which are the proper
airports only 150 airports we should
have a thousand airports why not so
that's one more thing because airports
have multiple uses you see not just uh
civilian use but also military use
potentially so airports are necessary we
need ports
we need ports lots and lots of ports we
need we need transshipment ports very
important what's trans shipment port.
Let's say you are a huge cargo ship
that's going from let's say uh for
example from Japan to Europe but you
need to drop off a whole consignment of
cargo to India on the way but to do that
instead of going south of Sri Lanka
you'll have to come all the way north to
Vishaka Patnam offload that then once
again go all the way south and cross Sri
Lanka and go then further on your way
it'll cost you 3 4 days it'll cost you a
lot of money to do that just to offload
offload some cargo cargo in India. So
what these ships do is that they stop at
Colbo Sri Lanka offload the cargo there
and and Sri Lanka gets the money for
that and then India has to do the trans
shshipment from Colbo to India. So why
doesn't India have trans shshipment port
so that we don't need to rely on other
countries even though they are in our
neighborhood. So that's why there is
this new trans shshipment port facility
which is going to come up in the great
Nikobar island in the Andermans and
apparently I hear there is some
political opposition to that. So India
needs to go ahead with these projects.
We need trans shshipment ports. We need
lots of ports. We need lots of um
airports. We need highways, highquality
worldass highways all across the
country. We need railway lines across
the country. What else do we need? What
other infrastructure? I think this is
great to start off with. You see
observatory and all these are not
critical infrastructure. These are nice
things to have from a scientific
perspective but critical infrastructure
it's it's all of this what else can I
think of I think yeah every every um
every city should have good roads not
see
you can have great roads that that
interconnect the cities but if you go to
a city and you find that it takes you
two hours to come from the from the
outskirts of the city into the heart of
the city that's a problem big problem
and there are so many cities in India
where it takes 2 three hours to to
transit the because of the congested
roads and all that in the city. So all
that needs to be fixed, right? Um and
then infrastructure that's good for
tourism, hotels, restaurants, clean
facilities, welcoming facilities, all of
that. Tourism, we need to really boost
tourism. So there's so much I can speak
about this for two hours actually. But
these are some of the critical things
that India needs to do on an urgent
basis, urgent footing.
Pratam Sony says why don't you clearly
say because I never clearly say I am so
bad I am so stupid I never clearly say
anything abijit is so bad why don't you
clearly say that NU and Gandhi was
British agent even if controversy
happened it will help more people to
know about what the blah blah blah about
what they had done by the way she was
I say things see everybody has a certain
style of saying if you don't like my
style of saying things then maybe you
can
perhaps see somebody else who has the
style that you like. See, I'm not going
to change
the way I talk. Right? I'll tell you
something. Everybody has a certain set
of characteristics. Do you understand?
We all have a certain core set of
characteristics that we are born with.
And that fundamental set of
characteristics doesn't change no matter
how old you become. I at whatever age I
am right now, I am the same exact same
person I was when I was 2 years old.
Nothing has changed at the core. I am
still the same person. I've learned
things. I've learned knowledge and
gained skills and what not, but I'm
still the same person. So, some things
don't change.
Certain ways of talking also don't
change.
If somebody has a certain amount of
diplomacy in the way they talk, then
that's going to stay.
Now it's up to you whether you like it
or not. If you don't like it, well, I
cannot force you to like it, right? And
and if you can't understand what I'm
saying, then well, what can I say? I
think I'm fairly understandable. I think
people do understand what I'm saying,
right? So when you talk about certain
historical figures and all you may
sometimes need to employ diplomatic
language because there's a difference
between somebody who somebody on the
street and using street level language
and someone who speaks at a different at
a certain level.
So I choose my words carefully
and there's a reason why I use certain
kinds of
language and that's not going to change
sir. All right and if it if if you if it
disappoints you then I'm very sorry
about that but uh I am not going to
change that approach. All right.
Okay. Next priest king says
what do you think about the Gandhi
Irvvin pact and the Bhagat Singh
connection. Now what was this Gandhi
urban pact?
Gandhi Irvin pact Bhagat Singh
connection I don't remember that. See
Mr. Gandhi is not some of one of my most
favorite
historical figures. So let's let's
Google what is Gandhi urban pact. See I
don't know. Okay I don't recall right
now what the Gandhi urban pact is.
Gandhi
Irwin pact what was this thing
a proven political agreement signed
between Mr. Muantas Gandhi and Lord
Irvin victory of India fifth march
before the second round table conference
in London.
What was this about?
What was it about? Agreed terms.
Discontinuation of the salt march by the
Gandhi faction.
Participation of the INC the second
national roundt conference. Withdrawal
of all ordinances issued by the colonial
government. Imposing curves on the
Congress. Withdrawal of all prosecutions
related to various types of political
rival act. Release of p prisoners
arrested for participating in the salt
march. Removal of tax on salt and
withdraw all ordinances and pro
prosecutions. Release political
prisoners. Except those guilty of
violence. Well, violence is very bad
which is why Gandhi was very good.
Permit peaceful picketing of liquor and
foreign cloth shops. Restore confiscated
properties of satag. Permit blah blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah. So
essentially it was the British agreeing
to all the peaceful nonviolent harmless
conditions of Mr. Gandhi.
Right? So everybody who participated in
a completely harmless way we will
release you as long as you did not do
any violence. Maybe if you had pushed a
cop let's say a British cop you will
stay in jail. But if you said sir please
to the cop then you can be freed. So
anybody who who was harmless
was freed by the British and the Indian
National Congress would be allowed to
continue its activities. No curbs on
that. Well anyway it's activities were
harmless right? So the British said okay
as long as you're harmless we will agree
to your conditions but any conditions
that are harmful which anyway Mr. Gandhi
would never give which would be harmful
to the British so those would not be
agreed to. So that was the Gandhi win
pact and that was the the prelude to the
1931 raund table conference
Bat Singh connection I don't remember
what was it when did Bhagat Singh when
was Bhagat Singh murdered let's see
first of all okay when was when did the
British barbarously kill Bat Singh Bat
Singh death date 31
31 Now let's see Gandhi Irvin pact first
of all this is 23rd March March. Okay.
Gi Gandhi Urban Pact. What date was it?
What date? 5th March. 5th March is the
pact. 23rd March. Aha. So the pact
between Gandhi and Irvin was signed on
the 5th of March and 18 days later the
British murdered Bhagat Singh.
And Mr. Gandhi,
the great saint of nonviolence,
did not exhort the British to
not commit the murder.
Yeah. Well, what can I say? What can I
say? Mr. Gandhi was a great man. Mr.
Gandhi was the father of the nation.
Apparently, Mr. Gandhi abhored violence.
Mr. Mr. Gandhi would have hated Shri
Krishna.
Mr. Gandhi would have hated Shri Ram
because Shri Ram was a violent man,
wasn't he? He participated in a war. He
participated in an invasion
of a neighboring kingdom,
Sri Lanka.
And and and and that's what Sri Ram did.
And Sri Krishna he exhorted he he tried
nonviolence first but then he exhorted
the the pandas to go to war with the
with the korovas war violence
so Mr. Gandhi did not believe in
violence and since Mr. Bhagat Singh had
engaged in some form of violence Mr.
Gandhi did not oppose his murder.
What can I say sir? What can I say? Uh
Mr. Gandhi was too high a person for us
to understand.
So yeah.
Yeah.
Vive Singh says how to get rid of this
babu in Indian society. Many government
projects are getting delayed because of
their lackluster attitude towards work.
Private sector is working hard though.
Look there's nothing we the citizens can
do about this babuom issue or whatever
it is which it is. It is
the change has to come from the
government.
India needs a few things
urgently on high priority. One is a war
on corruption
and secondly is a streamlining of all
these services.
I am okay with even more bureaucrats
being inducted
but no bureaucrat should have a job for
life
and it it seems that if if in case some
bureaucrat is caught doing some some
malpractice or whatever they're
suspended for a while and then then
brought back. that job is never
terminated. So all of these colonial
legacies that we are carrying as as
monkeys on our shoulder, they are
keeping us down. So yeah, we need
restructuring and and re deep reforms.
But who will do it?
See, the moment Mr. Modi tries to do
something against the the bureaucrats,
some kind of reforms, they will go on
strike, then the whole country will be
paralyzed. Then what happens? So that's
the kind of strangle hold the system has
over the country.
There are solutions to that but uh right
now they are not feasible.
Aman Kumar Dhankar thank you sir. Thank
you.
Teentox dharma. What is neo-Nazi
movement? Is it succeeding? Neo-Nazi
movement there is for a while there was
the the danger of a neo-Nazi movement in
in Europe in Germany. So neo-Nazi
movement is you know some Germans or
whoever or maybe non-Germans. uh there
are some people who apparently admire
Adolf Hitler and want to bring back the
the ideals and objectives of the of the
Nazi Tri U movement. So that's a
neo-Nazi movement. These are people who
believe in white supremacy in so-called
Arian supremacy. Arians is us you you
losers. We are the Arians, not the
Germans, not the white people. But they
have stolen that word from us and uh
that sort of thing. So uh so the
neo-Nazi movement used to exist in
Germany. to some extent it still may and
there are neo-Nazi movements in various
white countries
and it's all about white supremacy on
the supremacy of the white race and
hatred xenophobia hatred of people with
with darker skin color and uh
anti-immigration policy which to some
extent is understandable it's your
country you do what you want which is
fine is it succeeding it's not
succeeding
it's not succeeding at all and you may
even have neo-Nazi movements in America
for example some people who have
sympathies or or or who admiration for
the Nazi tuhik and Abdul Hitler. You
have people like that in various
countries. So these are the various
scattered new Nazi movements and none of
them is threatening to succeed at all.
Anonymous is how can we bring back our
culture and civilization? How can we
sustain it for thousand years? Education
system.
Education system.
Reform the education system. Everything
comes back.
Why did we have a culture that lasted
10,000 years? Education system. We had
an indigenous education system that was
deeply rooted in our indigenous values
and culture and civilization. Today we
have an education system which is
mediocre at best. It is rooted in
foreign values and western culture
and all it does is is it destinates us
and it it it puts this enormous
inferiority complex on Indians education
system. You want to bring back Indian
civilization and culture, education
system has to be reformed.
That's the long and the short of it.
Everything will flow from there.
Divor Singh says, "How did we get into
the Soviet arms when the post
independence government was
western?" Yeah, India is a weird country
the past 70 80 years completely mentally
mixed up country. I'll tell you how.
So we the first prime minister of India
was Shri Jawahar Lal Nehuji. He was
appointed prime minister, selected prime
minister, not elected.
Now Mr. Nehu was an angophile.
He spent a lot of time in England. He
was educated there. He was a lawyer. He
loved the English language. He saw him
culturally himself culturally as an
English man and only Indian by by blood
I suppose.
Uh so he was a great lover of England
and England's culture, language, all of
that.
But he was also a Fabian socialist. So
while studying in England, he he became
influenced by Fabian socialism which was
one of the flavors of socialism that was
in vogue
um in some quarters of of British
society. So Fabian socialism is all
about slowly slowly
socialism it's about making change very
slowly very steadily very gradually no
rapid change everything has to happen
gradually slowly gently gently
so Mr. Mr. Neu was an Angloile. He was a
Fabian socialist. He also visited the
USSR and he was greatly impressed with
whatever the Soviets had done. So he
said yes socialism works
but his brand of socialism was f was
Fabian socialism. So even though he was
ideologically a socialist and culturally
English
and by blood he was Indian apparently.
So he he he
made a combination of the worst of the
three and that's what he
operationalized.
So socialism if you look at USSR so USSR
style socialism it is massive
industrialization
massive rapid industrialization. How did
the USSR become a superpower
just a few years after it was almost
conquered by the Triik
through massive industrialization. That
was Soviet style socialism,
collectivization and massive
industrialization. Mr. Nehu could have
done that in India. Mass scale
industrialization. He chose not to do
that. He said poverty is great. Mr.
Gandhi is right. Secondly, I will do
socialism but I will have a strictly
controlled economy and everything and
any change if it happens, it has to
happen very slowly, very gradually. So
let's have a 3% economic rate of growth,
the Nehuvian rate of growth.
And he hated the Americans because the
Americans had won a war of independence
from the British. So they were bad guys
and they were the brash noish,
right? He didn't like them. He he
considered them to be imperialists. He
was not wrong in that.
So that's why he decided that he will go
with the USSR and he was very deeply
impressed with with the Soviets. So Mr.
Neu decided to align with the USSR
despite nominally being non-aligned
and that's how the whole thing happened.
So the US so the US tried to have India
on its side. The US and the USSR
together offered India on multiple
occasions the permanent the fifth
permanent seat in the UN security
council. Mr. Neu repeatedly said give it
to China first not to us. Give it to
China first. So he was almost like he
was advocating for China ahead of India
not almost that's what he did
and then Kennedy offered India nuclear
weapons and Nero said we don't believe
in violence
so because of all of these things the
Americans said to hell with it we'll go
with Pakistan and we went into the
Soviet arms like you say that is how it
all all transpired
Kingston Crystal says why don't we claim
merge land for our people. 1971 hurt a
lot.
Look,
I want to have so much land for example.
Let's say I want to have Alaska. I want
it. So why don't I go and take it,
right? That's what that's what we'll
say. Wanting something in being and
being cap capable of taking it is two
different things, right?
I want Alaska, let's say. But am I
capable of going and taking Alaska?
Am I capable of it?
China wants Taiwan. So why doesn't it
take Taiwan?
It has to be able to take Taiwan, right?
We are no longer 12 year olds right over
here.
Why don't we cla We can claim anything.
I can claim the moon is mine. Claiming
makes makes no difference. I will claim
the moon is my territory. Mars is mine.
What difference does it make me making a
claim? claims do nothing. You have to
create facts on the ground. Are we
capable of creating facts on the ground?
1971 hurt a lot.
We biseected Pakistan in 1971. Why does
it hurt you? I maybe you mean to say
something else. 19 1971 was an Indian
victory, right? Of course we did not
take we did not reintegrate Bangladesh
into India which was a huge mistake or
maybe not whatever.
Uh but if you want to claim land and
take land which earlier used to be yours
you have to be capable of doing it.
Right now we are not
because there are other powers more
powerful than ours than us who will
prevent us from doing it. Okay.
Uh DVN Singh says would you explicitly
say capitalism is superior to communism
and socialism.
The
communism and socialism. Socialism is
terrible. Communism is just an
operationalized form of socialism.
So communism and socialism are terrible
because it it gives you no incentive to
perform.
When no matter how high you perform, how
well you perform, you are rewarded just
just like everybody else. There's no
incentive to perform. So it it gives
rise to a culture of mediocrity.
Communism as well as socialism. Even if
you have a brutal totalitarian
government, people will work hard but
only up to a certain limit. They'll not
work hard voluntarily. They'll work hard
because of the whips at their back. So
communism and socialism aren't great.
Clearly they they you can't become great
through those. Um unless you're doing
slave labor and stuff. Uh capitalism
definitely has better outcomes than
communism and socialism. It is a dog eat
dog world. The the the fittest survive.
If you have the the the
capabilities, if you have the capacity
to work hard, if you are smart, if
you're intelligent, if you can outwork
and outthink others, then you will you
will become richest beyond your wildest
dreams. So, capitalis capitalism is
fantastic. If you have that cutthroat
attitude
and you can work really hard and you
have all those, you know, all the
qualities that a great entrepreneur has
and all that, you will be great. You'll
thrive in capitalism. Capitalism is
great for the individual.
Now, let's let's zoom out. We are
looking right now through the microscope
at single individuals. If you are if you
have the qualities, you will thrive
under cap capitalism. If you don't have
the qualities, you're going to have to
work three jobs to put food on the
table. That's also an outcome of
capitalism
because you can't have a capitalist
society and a welfare state at the same
time. So, some people will thrive, some
people will struggle and inequality
grows.
The US is a very in unequal country.
Now,
zoom out from the individual level level
to a to the collective level. Is
capitalism great for a country? In
capitalism,
everybody competes against each other
and the best ideas succeed. So you have
all these different companies, AI
companies and tech tech companies
competing competing with each other and
they're innovating. They're doing their
best to rise above the others and that's
why there is so much innovation that
happens so much innovation and the
country thrives as a consequence. So you
can out compete all the other countries.
So that's what the US has done through
capitalism. Now let's zoom out beyond
that to the global level. Capitalism in
capitalism every company needs to
prioritize profits.
Every company forever pursues quarter
upon quarter profits for itself and its
shareholders.
Not it's quarter upon quarter profits
which means quarter upon quarter growth.
So let's say you are a PC manufact a
laptop manufacturer.
It means you need to have more and more
sales every quarter. If you are Apple,
if you if you're manufacturing cell
phones or watches or whatever, you need
to have more and more sales every
quarter. The moment you stop doing that,
you are in the red. So so every company
is seeking quarter upon quarter profit
in growth. How do you do the profits? By
selling more. How do you sell more? By
manufacturing more. How do you
manufacture manufacture more? By
extracting more from the earth
resources.
Is it possible to have never ending
quarter upon quarter growth
on a finite planet?
Capitalism is going to end up destroying
the planet. That is the critical flaw in
capitalism.
Anonymous says what is the aftermath or
significance of indust script
decipherment other than RN inversion
theory getting debunked?
U the significance well the big
significance obviously is the RN
invasion theory, migration theory,
picnic theory, tourism theory is
debunked. Uh and it it proves that
Sanskrit is indigenous to India. It did
not come from some some some ragtag
nomadic band that came in from some
ragtag part of the world.
Now what's the other consequences of
that? The other consequence of that is
that it kills the theory that the Brahi
script was derived from the proto
protosemitic some script Phoenician
script. I I'll show you what I mean by
that. Okay. So let's go to Google
and let's see what Wikipedia has to say
about the brahi script or let us see
what Wikip Wikipedia has to say about
Dvagari script. Dva Nagari script.
Let us see what Wikipedia says about the
ancestry of the Dvanagari script.
See it says Dvagari comes from the
Nagari script which comes from Siddham
script which comes from the Gupta script
which comes from the Brahmin script
which comes from Aramaic
which comes from Phoenician which comes
from protosanatic which comes from
Egyptian heroglyphics. So, Wikipedia
claims and all western
uh scholars claim that the brahi script
came eventually from Egyptian
hieroglyphics
because the brah script was derived from
the Aramaic script. What is the Aramaic
script?
This thing here. So, they claim that
they claim that Brahi came from this.
Okay? Because this was a semmitic script
which came from the from Mesopotamia,
West Asia.
Now, once
So, so if the script is deciphered then
you can correlate the brahi script with
the um so-called industali or saraspati
synindu script. So that will eventually
also end up debunking this entirely
fictitious claim that the brahi script
was derived from the Aramaic script
which is utter nonsense but they are
trying to forcefitit their worldview and
their version of history on our history.
So that is the next big thing we have to
achieve to prove onetoone correspondence
between the letters of the saraspatist
sindu script and the brahmy script. So
that's going to be the next major
outcome and significance of the
decipherment.
Divor Singh says a Greek friend called
the Roman plagiarizers in case of gods.
I call the Greeks plagiarizers Indian
cause. Was I right though? You are
absolutely right and he's also right
your friend.
So when it comes to the U Roman gods,
the the most prominent god obviously is
Jupiter. Jupiter is the Roman version of
Zeus Peter. Zeus Peter and Zeus Peter is
the Greek version of Dors Petru, the
ancient sky god of the Vic times.
And of course Zeus
who is named after the Dospitru, he has
actually the attributes of of Indra
because he is the god of the hammer and
the thunderbolt. The vajra. What if you
look at the vajra for example? Okay, let
us Google vajra. It is both a hammer and
a thunderbolt. See vajra.
So the vajra is shaped like this. It is
this instrument. It is today depicted
stylistically as something you can hold
in one palm. But it is also essentially
a hammer-like instrument. It is said to
have been constructed initially from the
rib bones of of a saint of of of I don't
know I I don't remember who it was. So
today the vajra is shown as something
you can hold in your palm but originally
it was this dangerous hammer-like
instrument and vajra also means
thunderbolt of course. So the vajra of
Indra is both a hammer and a thunderbolt
but eventually among the later gods it
became two things a hammer and a
thunderbolt separately. So Thor has a
hammer. Molir, he also has the
thunderbolt. And uh was Zeus depicted
with a hammer? I'm not sure, but he did
have a thunderbolt and so does Jupiter.
So the Greek gods are continuations of
the older Indian gods. No question about
it. And the Romans acquired many of
their major gods from Greece. So the
Romans plagiarized from Greece. In the
Greeks you could say plagiarized or or
brought it from India. So you were
absolutely absolutely right in what you
said.
Scandium says what happened to the $45
trillion looted by the UK US. It was now
it's about 60 something. Uh
I think some scholar had said had given
a number a figure of $45 trillion but
eventually somebody has reworked it to
about 69 or 67 or something trillion
dollars looted from India. So what
happened to it? So first of all
understand it was not currency notes
that diluted. It was the total amount of
wealth they extracted extracted out of
India in today's dollar dollar terms. It
was not US dollar bills that was taken
from India or it was not simply gold or
silver that was taken from India. It was
extraction of value out of India. All
kinds of resources
whether it is silver, whether it is
copper, whether it is gold, whether it
is diamonds, whether it is teakwood,
whether it is uh
whatever it was,
whether it is various other other
resources, whether whether it was u
Indian farmers being forced to produce
cotton and indigo and opium and then
that was then taken by the British and
exported to other countries. all of the
cumulative
benefit and and value the British
extracted out of India if you put a
dollar amount on it in today's US
dollars then it's about 60s something
trillion dollars where did it go it went
all across the western world it was
invested reinvested it became the
foundation of various companies wealth
it became the foundation of certain
families wealth in some cases it was
just pure plunder of treasure from from
temples In some cases it was different
kind of value that was extracted out out
of India um and so on. So all of that
was redistributed that formed you could
say the foundation of a lot of the
wealth and power of the western
countries especially Britain and its
vasals.
Anonymous says why are Indian oligarchs
or billionaires not as powerful as their
western counterparts? Suppose someone
aspires to be a future oligarch or
billionaire. What steps should they take
to become powerful?
First of all, become a billionaire. On
the way to becoming a billionaire, you
will also understand how power works
because once you become more and more
prosperous, you will enter higher and
higher levels where you will where you
will inevitably come in contact with
people who also hold power like
politicians and so on, right? And once
you start moving in those circles, you
will understand how power works. It's a
process you will learn gradually and
automatically. Now it's up to you
whether you have the aptitude for
gaining power or not because power and
wealth are very different things and
wealth can to some extent buy power but
power can acquire as much wealth as as
it wants. So power always trumps wealth.
Now why are Indian billionaires not that
powerful?
Because India is not that powerful.
Right? When you are in a country that is
the most powerful country in the world
and you are a billionaire, you will
automatically be way more powerful than
a billionaire who is in India which is a
much less powerful country. Because when
you are a billionaire in the US, your
actions can influence things globally.
If you are in the tech sector, you can
influence actions of the US military
which can have consequences all across
the world in a in a military dimension.
But if you're an Indian billionaire and
you're selling Kaparamakan whatever what
what impact will it have
I can't think of any Indian billionaires
who are uh doing AI or whatever right
and some Indian billionaires you could
say are in investing in infrastructure
and things that are critical to India's
national interest well those could be
powerful and that's the ones who are
targeted the most by the west because
they are making India more powerful so
if you want to aspire to be a future
oligarch billionaire. What steps you
should you take to become powerful?
First of all, become wealthy. Become
wealthy. And if you want to be powerful,
invest in sectors that come naturally
with power like infrastructure, like
ports, like like coal and oil and gas,
ports.
Invest in the defense sector. Defense in
in you know, invest in the high-tech
sectors. create a business in a
high-tech sector like AI cutting edge or
missiles hypersonics
right but if you really want power in
the political sense if you if you have
dealings in the port sector in the
infrastructure sector if you're building
ports highways if you if you are um if
you have a business that has to do with
renewable energy oil and gas all of that
is naturally something that comes with
power right so that's what you would
Naman Chabra says, "Considering the
current circumstances, do you think the
Indian administration will be able to
avert this regime change operation?
America has come out all guns blazing
and can Osent be trusted?" I think the
US will will certainly attempt a regime
change operation or or or
make or take steps that go in that
direction in India. I think they are
already laying the groundwork for that
and some of their assets may already be
may have been operationalized in various
shapes and forms. I'm not I don't know
who the assets may or may not be but I'm
just saying
um will India be able to avert this?
It'll be I think India will be able to
avert this but it will be a tough fight
I think because see how do you how do
you start a regime change operation? You
start violence in the country. You start
destabilizing the country. You have mass
protests erupt all across the country
through people that you control through
resources that you are allocating to
them and so on. So you want a regime
change you can you have to create a a
you have to create an atmosphere that is
in the country that is destabilized an
atmosphere of unease the people should
should should feel like the country is
unstable
and they should feel like the government
is not doing its job so that's what you
do which means that they will have to
create a lot of disturbance in India and
you have to create narratives that that
make the people question the way the
government is functioning maybe they're
not doing their hub maybe they are they
are not a good government that sort of
thing so once you start operationalizing
all of this it it it's very problematic
especially if you have the right people
who are working for you but I think
India will be able to avert it and the
US definitely doesn't like Modi because
Modi has stood up to them nobody else
has stood up to them in the entire world
apart from Mr. Shi and Mr. Putin so the
US now cons looks upon Mr. Modi the same
way perhaps as Mr. Shi and Mr.
perhaps or similar to that. So yeah,
it's going to be tough for India. Can
OSENT be trusted to to a certain extent
but not not completely? You can trust
OSENT to a certain extent. Opensource
intelligence
can also be used to sow misinformation.
Okay. So you have to be cognizant of
that.
Okay. Putin says, I sent you the Brahma
security concept on Monday so and so
time. It's a serious proposal. Please
check the mail when possible. All right,
sir. All right. Brahma Yantra. I'll
check it out, sir. Thank you.
Okay. Nav sense AI says, "What's the
success and failure of the current
government over?" See, look, you can do
a whole Excel sheet and look at all the
different parameters and aspects and so
on. I would say overall
if you look at Prime Minister Modi, I
think he has been the best prime
minister we have had since 1949, 47,
whatever year it was. When was the first
election? Mr. Neu when he came to when
he became prime minister was selected
right uh he's been the best ever elected
prime minister of India that's what I
will say I think that should answer most
of the questions
how did Rockefeller monopolize American
oil once again I haven't studied the
American oligarchs so I don't know
exactly how it happened Rockefeller did
monopolize American oil and then he went
into the pharmaceuticals industry and he
monopolized that also and he turned
something that should have in well an
industry dedicated to healing he dedic
he he transformed that into an industry
based on it became a parasitic industry
right uh so yeah that's his legacy isn't
good at all Rockefeller but how did he
achieve this I am not sure I have not
studied Rockefeller's life history so I
won't be able to answer that question
I'm sure it's a very interesting thing
to study but I haven't had the time to
study everything right so yeah I'm not
I'm not aware of the specifics of how he
monopolized Sorry.
MK says, "What were Hitler's views on
religion? Did he have any plans to bring
back polytheism?" I believe I've heard
that he was an admirer of Islam
and he was also a Christian. I don't
think he had any plans whatsoever to
bring back polytheism in Germany. Uh
polytheism had been hammered out out of
Germany several centuries before Hitler
came to power. Right? And you still have
some some pre-Christian ideas and
concepts in German culture. The ring of
the neiling or whatever it is and
some of the themes that he some of his
themes vagner's music some of it has
those pre-Christian themes and all but
overall Germany is a very Christian
nation now and I don't think Hitler had
any plan of bringing back polytheism. Of
course, the swastika that he first saw
in his life was I think in a church or
outside a church or something.
Obviously, the swastika is a
pre-Christian uh symbol, isn't it? It's
it isn't it wasn't called the swastika
in Germany. It was called the hacken
kraut, but today they call it the
swastika to mallay Hinduism. Anyhow, so
that's what I have heard about Hitler. I
haven't studied his views in detail
about religion. I know about his career
from a military and political
perspective, but not from a religious
perspective. But as far as I know that
he he did not have any intention or any
plans to bring back polytheism
says how did the US maintain nationalism
despite them being English, French,
Hispanics, Germans and Afros.
Look the
today if you look at the US it's a multi
multi-thnic nation. They call themselves
a multi- multi-ultural nation. Yes. But
when the US began
it was a Puritan nation.
Who are the Puritans? They were
Calvinists. The French Puritans were
called the Hugenauts.
And the Calvinists were Protestant. And
they wanted a much stricter form of
Christianity than what you had in
England and in Europe. And they felt
that they were being persecuted back in
Europe, which is why they decided to
cross the Atlantic on a ship called the
Mayflower. But that's not the first
Americans. The first Americans were the
gentleman's and ladies who lived in
Jamestown. Those were the first
Americans led by the indomitable Captain
John Smith.
He of the gunboat diplomacy. Anyhow, I'm
going to old history now. The Americans,
the American nation was an English
nation.
They captured territory that belongs to
others. the the the browns, the the
non-whites, the the native Americans,
they killed most of them. Super
genocide. Then you had then the captured
territory where you had the French and
Hispanic people and all. So those people
came under the English.
Even when you had a nation that was now
multicultural,
which also had enslaved African people,
it was culturally English. It was
linguistically English. The English
dominated. It's only of late the past 20
30 years that the attitude has become
more relaxed that the Hispanics are now
being seen as no longer secondass
citizens. Yeah. For the longest time
Hispanic people were secondass citizens.
So it's it's been a long slow process of
change
and it's always even today it's an
English speaking nation. Right.
Okay. Vivor Singh says Ben Franklin
Hamilton to also Abe Lincoln warned
America about evil banks.
What banks? Why were so many powerful
people afraid of them? because
well I think there was a tremendous
amount of anti-semitism in in America
before the 20th century
and u it is said that many banks were
run by by people of Jewish origin and
there was this deepseated mistrust of
Jewish people in Europe
and the the Americans well obviously or
were all descendants of Europeans so
some of that may have been there and
People who run banks are often they
often have predatory practices. They
will you know be lone sharks. They will
lend you money but then they will own
your life. That sort of thing. And uh
America was the land of freedom. So the
the culture was it it was you know this
sort of behavior was anthemma to America
and I suppose that was about that was
the thing. So banks were necessary but
banks should should not become powerful
and uh that was the thing I mean Europe
has had a long history of merchants and
bankers becoming super powerful you've
had this pattern that you saw in Venice
you so seen this in the Dutch guilds and
so on so the Americans obviously since
they came from Europe they were aware of
the history and they do not did not want
bankers to be power to be powerful the
the elite should remain powerful so so
if you if you read Howard Zinn's history
of to the United States. It's called a
people's history of the United States.
It's a pretty leftist book, but it's an
interesting book. And Howard Zinn says
that the United States was not created
for the revolution was not for for
freedom. It was not that they wanted
people to be free. It's that they wanted
to create a group of elites who will not
have to pay tax to the U to to the UK
and they will control all the money and
power in the United States. And the
people the you know the people like
George Washington, Ben Franklin, Thomas
Jefferson and all the people around them
they were the the elites who control who
took the power in the US and the US
according to Howard Zinn has been this
sort of nation. It serves the elites. It
doesn't serve the common person. If you
see the US constitution for example, it
is said that the US constitution was a
democratic constitution. It was ratified
by the people of the US. Well, is it
true who was who was allowed? So the
constitution was drafted and then it was
put to a vote. That's how you ratify a
constitution. In India, the constitution
has never been ratified. Our
constitution is not a democratic
constitution by the way. So in the US,
they drafted the constitution. We the
people blah blah blah. And then it was
put to a vote. Now who was allowed to
vote on this?
It was wealthy landowning white men who
were allowed to vote. Everybody else was
ex was excluded from voting, disbarred.
So if you are if you were a white man
who was landless, you could not vote for
the constitution for or against. If you
were a woman, you could not vote no
matter whether you were wealthy or not.
If you were a black person, no question
of you voting. If you were native, the
natives were savages. Have you read the
Declaration of Independence of the US?
How do they refer to the natives?
Savages.
So that's how it was. So the US
constitution was voted for by a bunch of
wealthy men and so on. So yeah, that's
the kind of history you have you have in
the US. But yeah, they were always
suspicious of bankers.
Any southern language is part of the
Indo-Uropean language family or are a
separate family?
Um, one second.
any southern languages part of the
Indo-Uropean language family or are they
a separate family? Well, they're
classified as as as a Dravidian language
family as members of of the so-called
Dravidian language family. I think what
we need to do in India is we need to
revisit this the entire linguistic
makeup of India a priority without any
western a priority worldview. That's
what we need to do because all the
languages are interconnected whether
they are south Indian languages or north
Indian languages. There are so many
interconnections. There are so many
words that are common to the languages.
Even if you are speak Tamil, you have so
many Sanskrit words in Tamil. If you
speak Mallayalam, I don't know about 60%
of malam vocabulary comes from Sanskrit.
So how can you say that these are this
is a separate language family. So all of
this needs to be looked at
a prior once again reformulated a
priority without having those
preconceived
uh europ euroentric notions
uh in mind. Kithan WHMA says seems Shri
Vlad embodied by bin ho naprit a truism
bred out of Indians by years of
socialism and Gandhiism. No questions
just a comment. I would say that I have
to agree with you sir.
Okay. Vek Gada says please explain the
origin of the country Israel.
The origin of the country Israel. Well
that's a tremendously long history.
very ancient land about 3,000 years old.
Uh the first kings of Israel were Saul
and Solomon etc. Their prophet was
Abraham. Um the first Hebrew
uh presence of Hebrew language or
whatever in the archaeological record
goes back about 2,900 or almost 3,000
years. And uh they had this land called
Judea. there are a couple of Jewish
kingdoms there and then there came under
occupation by I'm going to very old
history but um in in the 1900s there was
this demand for a land for the Jewish
people because they had no country of
their own and naturally they wanted to
take back the land that their ancestors
had lived in about 2,000 years ago. So
in 1917 there was the Balur declaration
and so on and uh the British started uh
settling um Jewish people in the region
uh in the 1910s, 1920s, 1930s and there
were clashes between Jewish people and
the local Arabs who were living there
who had taken over the land in the
previous several centuries and
eventually in 1949 it was that Israel
was was created as an official country
and immediately all the Arab ne
neighbors attacked Israel but Israel was
able to uh defeat them because of
western help and so on and eventually
Israel developed its own very powerful
army it's very powerful intelligence
internal and external intelligence the
internal one is the shinbeth the
external one is the Mossad and they
developed a nuclear deterrent and they
became a very powerful country and they
have excellent relations with the US and
so on
dark knight says the question then
arises why did those brahmans of vanaras
provide our civilizational knowledge to
Kepler.
Indians are super innocent people.
We had lost
what they call shatbod.
They did not provide it to to Kepler.
They provided it to some Jesuits. See,
Jesuits are Christian missionaries who
work for the Vatican who who have a
scientific background
and their job is to steal knowledge from
other countries. So they they will come
to your country and they will pretend
like they are extremely aruck and
impressed by your culture and by the
wealth of your knowledge and learning.
And they will come to the great learned
acharas and brahinss with folded hands
and they'll say swami g achar guru g
please allow please bless me by by
tolerating me in your presence. Let me
sit at your feet as as a poor student
and please please bless me with some
knowledge. I am a deep deep and profound
seeker of knowledge and you are so wise
and so knowledgeable. Your culture is so
ancient. Please help my poor poor
backward culture with some of your
knowledge.
Then the Indian brahinss will feel pity
for these people in their backward
culture. They'll say okay let me help
you with some of this knowledge that we
have. You want to learn about stars?
Well look at all this data that we have.
Would you like to copy it? Please copy
it. It will be very hard for you to
understand but copy it. So slowly you
gain trust. You take the knowledge. You
transmit it back to the west. Then you
claim it was yours all all the time. See
how it works? Indians are super
innocent. Indians assume the best of
everyone.
Well, I hope now at least we learn.
Anonymous says this one is from old
Askavij. There's nothing called the
oldest religion. There is only oldest
attested religion. What? Old Askabid?
Really? There is nothing called Yeah.
Okay, I know what you mean. We have no
idea what the religion was of old homo
sapiens. See, the best evidence that we
have says that
there was a migration out of Africa
about 80 or 70 or 60,000 years before
today
and eventually the migrants came and
settled in the Indian subcontinent where
it became the settler zone and from the
Indian subcontinent they went in all
directions and that's how the
non-affrican world was populated by homo
sapiens.
Now the question arises
when they first settled in the
subcontinent what language did they
speak and what religion did they follow?
They would have spoken some language
obviously. What was that language? We
have no memory of it. We have no record
of it. And they would have had some
religion
because that's in our DNA, right? We are
we we need religion. Humans wherever you
have humans, you have some kind of
religion. Even atheism is a form of
religion today. It's a belief system.
So humans are a religious species. So we
would have had a religion. So some
religion would have existed 60,000 years
ago. We have evidence of homo sapiens
surviving the Toba eruption
in the subcontinent. The Toba eruption
happened in in Indonesia but it was a
super volcano eruption. It affected the
entire region and you there is
archaeological evidence of a cloud of
ash that settled in the Indian
subcontinent and that was a devastating
event. It would have it could have
killed off a lot of people. But there is
evidence that humans survived in India
before and after. So we had humans in
India about 80,000 years ago. Homo
sapiens.
What was their language and religion at
the time? It's lost.
So
So we don't know what the oldest
religion was, right? But all we can
speak of today is the oldest attested
religion
which is the oldest religious tradition
that we know of today. We have old ones
that disappeared. We have no idea what
they even were. But which is the oldest
one that we are aware of today? That is
Hinduism.
Rice query says really miss geostrategy
and Indian interest episodes are one of
a kind. and visit Geio Strategy once
daily for updates. Love your channel.
Thank you very much. Geost Strategy
became problematic. The the the the
platform started uh uh started
demonetizing all those things all those
episodes and after that my channel has
also been affected views and subscribers
going backwards. So I thought that it is
prudent to stop that because uh this
platform is not an Indian platform and
uh they don't like my geio strategy
episodes. I don't want to lose the
channel, right? We don't want to be in a
situation where that happens. It won't
affect the rest of the world. It will
affect me. I mean I would like to keep
talking to to you all. Right? So that's
why I have stopped it because it was
clearly problem problematic. My my
analysis is not like other analysts
which is why even initially the views
were were were more and then the views
very quickly declined.
It's like the the even if people had you
know done the subscription and put the
bell hit the bell bell icon or whatever
they were not getting notifications and
the videos were not being recommended to
people which is why they were getting so
few views. My analysis is very different
from other Indians and which is why I
think it's a problem. So that's why I've
stopped it just out of prudence.
Teen talks Dharma says why what caused
the Korean War and why did the North
become a dictatorship? Um the Korean
War.
What caused the Korean War? Well, it was
see Korea is this small, it used to be
the small kingdom south
east of China and the Americans already
had this nation called Japan that was
under their occupation. Now the Soviets
and the Chinese wanted to
gain supremacy in Korea and the
Americans wanted Korea to be under them.
So that led to a ci to to a to a
to a war in Korea. It was not a proxy
war, it was a direct war
between the US and
China essentially and China was
supported by the USSR.
So the northern part of Korea was
supported by China. The southern part of
Korea was supported by the US and you
had US troops in South Korea fighting
the North. So it was kind of a proxy war
but kind of a direct war. The US was
directly involved. China was involved
kind of indirectly but to some extent
directly and the USSR was involved
indirectly.
So the the Korean peninsula became a
battleground of the cold war between the
US and and the USSR essentially and
China was the proxy and South and Korea
was the proxy and eventually it ended in
a stalemate. There was no official
ceasefire. The war still hasn't
officially ended and North Korea ever
since then came under the the Kim
dynasty and it's it's supported by
China. Okay?
And if you're supported by China, you
need a dictatorship. So that's how that
happened.
Um
big brother says row and real analysis
of Agnir system in army if I am I I have
no idea.
No I I haven't studied the Agnir system.
I don't know what the detail what the
details are. So I don't know. Sorry.
Sorry.
Shaswat Jana says I am 19. I'm going to
enter MBBS first year soon. But seeing
the toxic work culture of doctors in
India, I am deeply depressed even though
I really want to be one.
Well, that's a decision you're going to
have to make, sir.
Is the work culture for doctors always
toxic? I suppose it depends on the
the environment you're in. If you have
your own system, if you have your own
clinic, let's say,
then you control the work culture. But
to have your own clinic and start your
own practice, it takes a lot of time,
effort and money. The easy thing is that
you become a doctor, you get your degree
and qualifications and then you join
some hospital. But if you join a
hospital, you're part of a big machine
which is a very bureaucratic machine and
the only objective of the machine is to
make as much money as possible and their
doctors are just tools and patients are
just resources. So in that system you
may find it very toxic for sure. Yeah.
Well, the option is you either create
your own your own clinic, your own
practice and you can consult in
hospitals at your discretion but that
you can only do if you're a senior
doctor with a lot of patients then the
hospitals will be happy to entertain
that otherwise you will have to be in a
hospital or something and if it's a
government hospital I suppose it's even
worse and even in a private hospital
they will be you'll be really
overworked. I think doctors if they work
in big hospitals no matter where in the
world they have this this this problem
of being overburdened and overworked.
So um at the end of the day it's a
choice that you're going to have to
make. Is that something that is okay
with you? If that's not what you want
that sort of toxic work culture then
maybe MBBS is not for you. Maybe you can
go for something else. So u you will
have to make the the decision for
yourself. So all the best sir make the
right choice for yourself.
Okay. Divor Singh says, "What do you
have to say about the Babylonian
Talmud?" Trust me, everybody read it.
I haven't read it. I haven't read the
Talmud. Talmud, whichever Talmud.
See the the the Jewish system has the
Torah and the Talmud, right? The Talmud,
I believe, is a very
extensive document. Is it like thousands
of pages or is that the Torah? I don't
know, sir. I don't know. I haven't read
it. I have nothing to say about it
because I haven't read it. So, if I
haven't read it, I suppose I should stay
quiet about it because I don't know
anything about it.
Uh,
Divor Singh says, "Why do we call the
Catholic Church Roman and why does Tsar
and Kaiser come from Caesar?"
Well, interesting history here.
Catholic Church. So the church
see Rome was the great seat of the Roman
Empire and eventually the Roman Empire
kind of became divided into two empires
which was the Eastern and Western Roman
Empires. The Western Roman Empire the
original one was based out of Rome. that
was the the the center of gravity the
capital and the eastern empire Roman
Empire was based out of Bzantium or
Constantinople which is now called
Istanbul.
So that was the Eastern Roman Empire and
long after the Western Roman Empire fell
the Eastern Roman Empire continued until
1453.
Now it was the Eastern Roman Empire
where where things have things changed
because the emperor Constantine in order
to consolidate power and gain more power
he made Christianity the official state
religion of the empire because
Christianity is a monotheistic religion.
It's a religion of control. That way you
can control more people. So he said why
not? Let's do it. Why is this
polytheism? Polytheism is like hurting
cats. Christianity means you convert
everybody into into sheep and you become
the shepherd. So he made Christianity
the official state religion. Eventually
it spread like wildfire across the Roman
world and soon enough you had the the
the the seat of the Christian church the
global seat of the Christian church
based out of Rome. Eventually it became
Vatican City. So because it was based
out of Rome because the popes were based
in Rome that's why it was called the
Roman church.
So I think that should explain it. Now
Caesar, Julius Caesar, his name was not
Caesar, his name was Kaiser. Julius
Gaios Kaiser or Gaos, Julius Kaiser. But
because it is C A E S A R, that's how
the Romans wrote it. That's why we call
it Caesar. The actual pronunciation was
Kaiser.
And he was such a colossal historical
figure that everybody in the west
whoever became a strong powerful king
they wanted to model themselves in the
light of the great Julius Kaiser. So
that's why um the the the term the term
Kaiser K a I s a r or k a i s e r comes
from caesar and also tsar the Russian
word tsar. What does Kaiser a hind mean?
It means the same thing. Kaiser Hind
Caesar of Hind. It's because Julius
Julius Kaiser was such a well pivotal
figure in western history.
Ganesha Koshik says how to read history
in a chronological manner while covering
simultaneous events across the world.
Some books that cover Kushan Empire in
detail. There are no books that cover
Kushan Empire in detail. You will see
some details of of the Kushan Empire in
various RC Majunar books but little bit
nothing much I haven't found a single
book that covers the Kushian Empire in
detail unfortunately how to read books
in a chronological manner while covering
simultaneous events across the world you
don't
you have to read history in a profoundly
undisiplined manner
read whatever captures your imagination
if you try to grow go chronologically
you will get
disillusioned
You'll get bored because there are
periods of history that are really
boring. If you try to read everything
chronologically, you will get bored and
you will lose interest. If you want to
maintain interest in history, read
whatever captures your imagination. Do
it in a in the most
wanted
in manner you can think of. Read
whatever interests you. No matter what
the chronology, read something from 1700
AD, then read something from 3,000 BC.
Fine. Why not? Over time you'll all the
knowledge will interconnect. You can't
read history chronolog chronologically.
At least it doesn't work for me. Okay.
So what doesn't work for me? I cannot
give you advice for that.
Okay.
Kingston Crystal says why do spy
agencies unclose mission to public after
decades? Open up. See there are some
there are certain
um documents that are not disclosed
after decades. I mean the Kennedy files
still classified
the Bose files, Subhashundra Bose files
still classified.
There so many documents that are
classified beyond a century.
It's not like after there's a rule that
after so and so years we'll open up
everything. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Only they'll declassify only whatever
stuff is no longer important, which is
now irrelevant. That stuff you can
declassify. And even when you declassify
stuff, there will be things that are
redacted with black ink, illeible ink.
So nothing is it's not like there's a
rule that spy agencies after a certain
number of years, they have to put
everything in the public domain like
copyright free. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Absolutely not. There are things from
the Second World War that are still
classified. There are things from the
First World War that are still
classified. There are British records of
the Brit of the occupation of India that
are still classified.
I would love to go to the British
archives in London
and and read about the dispatches of
various British administrators in South
Africa reporting about Mr. Gandhi.
What did the British administrators in
South Africa when they reported to
London through telegrams and letters?
What did they write about Mr. Gandhi? I
would love to read that. That will never
be declassified.
Imagine if they declassify that. What
was their own assessment of Mr. Gandhi?
Well, that would be a goddamn bombshell,
wouldn't it? But they won't declassify
that.
Protect your own.
Sandy 97. Thank you so much, sir. Thank
you.
Divor Singh says, "Can Elon Musk buy
Pakistan?" If he wishes to, I suppose he
can. I don't think Pakistan is worth
$300 billion.
I don't think it's it's worth that much.
I suppose he if he wants to buy it, if
he wants to waste his money, he could he
can do it. Yeah.
Yeah. So theoretically he can if he if
he is so inclined.
Anonymous says I'm sorry for this
question. How to learn to think
critically and develop critical thinking
like you sorry for this question. It's a
good question. Can you recommend any
courses or books? Will you make a course
on this in the future? Um how to think
critically? I don't think there's any
books available textbook for critical
thinking. I'm not sure there's any such
book available. How to think critically?
The first step of the way in thinking
critically is to question everything.
See most Indians, most people in the
world, they are afraid to question
certain things. Even even privately.
Okay, I'm sitting let's say I'm sitting
in this room alone. Nobody here. Mommy
not here, daddy not here. By behone
here. Even sitting alone
many most people are afraid to ask
certain questions to themselves.
So the first step in thinking critically
is ask questions.
Why is this the way it is?
Right? Why is India called India? Simple
question. Get to the bottom of it. Why
is India otherwise called Bat? Get to
the bottom of it. What does Bhat mean?
Why do we say Bat Mata?
Why Bat Mata? Because King Bat was a man
and Bat is a masculine name. So why do
people say Bat Mata when Bat is a
masculine name? Isn't does it make any
sense whatsoever?
Ask such very uncomfortable questions.
Ask questions
and then if you get the answer, oh this
is because of that. Then you ask why is
that so?
Then you get to the bottom of that and
you go deeper and deeper until you get
to the very roots of the matter to first
principles. So that's one way of
thinking critically.
I'm not saying be disrespectful. No, ask
questions because the only way to learn
is to ask questions. Right? So that's
how we do it. So that's one way of doing
it. I don't know if I'll make a course
on about this uh books. I don't know of
any books. I I have not
I have not learned critical thinking
from books.
Uh Dnur Singh says Trump was warned by
the CIA to appoint Vance as a VP or he
will be killed. Really reliable sources.
Well, that's that's news for me.
Uh so then the question is if this is
true, why is Vance so valuable?
Is he an insurance policy? I don't know.
Could be. I So I I have no idea about
this and it's the first time I'm hearing
this one.
But I suppose anything's possible in the
world. Yeah. Especially if it's coming
from like you say reliable sources which
I am not making fun of at all. So if you
take this seriously in hypothetically
you see you think why would it be so? It
would only make sense if if Wance is an
insurance policy by the CIA then in case
if if uh if Mr. Trump let's say what
he's in his 80s right? So once a person
is in is is in their 80s you need a good
backup because you know in old age
anything can happen. So it's always good
to have a a good backup and maybe that's
the case. So that's what I could
speculate but this is the first time I'm
I'm hearing of this one.
Um isn't palant the most dystopian thing
ever? Palanteer is this frightening
technology of super surveillance isn't
it? Let's see what Palanteer
technologies does. It has this suite of
surveillance equipment and surveillance
technology.
Uh Palantir
Palantir technologies.
What does it do? Big data AI software
company specializing in big data
integration platforms for government and
commercial clients. Uh Alex Karp. Let's
see. Uh Peter Theel is involved. Well,
that's great. What's it do? What's it
do? products talented Gotham defense and
intelligence software uh used by
intelligence. See this is all
surveillance and spying software
supports alerts. So you may have heard
of prism. You may have heard of prism.
Okay. First of all we have goautum. Then
you have foundry which is used for used
in what commercial and civil government
sectors.
I'm not sure what that is. Then you have
Palantir Apollo continuous delivery
system that manages Gotham and Foundry.
Okay, very good.
Artificial intelligence platform.
Obviously,
Titan tactical intelligence targeting
access node, a truck, mobile ground
station for AI applications, meta
constellation. It's all surveillance.
It's about surveilling your citizens.
It's about surveying the world. It's
about Yeah, that big eye in the sky, big
brother on the ground, that sort of
thing. It is super dystopian. You may
recall like I was saying Prism. So Prism
was this surveillance uh platform the US
had in the 2000s late 2000s and u what's
his name? The guy who defected to the to
to to Russia Snowden Edward Snowden he
was the whistleblower he leaked it into
the public and he became America's
person you know most wanted person but
he escaped to the to to to Russia and
that's where he lives today. Edward
Snowden and if you saw the screenshots
that he shared and all that the US were
doing realtime surveillance of the
entire world and India was probably the
most surveiled country so that was in
around 2009 2010 now this is 2025 that's
15 years hence so you can imagine the
kind the level of sophistication and
penetration American uh surveillance
technology will have and palanteer
obviously is going to be a critical
component in that.
>> So yeah, super dystopian. It's about 24
by7 surveillance of the entire world,
all its people, your own people, foreign
countries, subject, citizens, all of
that. Governments, leaders, agencies,
corporations, everything. Realtime
surveillance. AI is involved. So AI can
tell you exactly what's happening. They
can possibly even make futuristic
predictions that what's going to happen,
what this corporation will do in the
next six months, next quarter, what so
and so leader is going to do, what is
going to what's the next next so it's
like being able to foresee chess moves
like 10 15 moves ahead of time that sort
of thing maybe hundreds of moves if you
are an AI enabled uh technology. So
yeah, super dystopian no question about
it.
Ritik P says India has issued a no time
for the entire northeast for the tw for
22 days. Why air force exercises I
suppose
air force exercises and live firing of
missiles and that sort of thing. So if
you are doing military exercises which
involves live firing of missiles and you
have dog fights and stuff like that then
you don't want anybody to intrude in the
sector because you may shoot someone
down by mistake. So you give a notice to
airmen everybody stay out of this area.
So I suppose that's that's the reason
that's what one could speculate the no
time has been issued but there's been no
reason given why this no time exists. So
one can only speculate maybe there will
be some uh military exercises. Yes.
Yes. Rati says due to increased digital
infrastructure and individual data to
MNC's and governments change is there
any change in government espionage
tactics how this how deeply are we
penetrated solutions
solutions is to cut off to go back to
the analog age
if you want to not be under surveillance
you have to disconnect yourself from the
digital world you have have a cell
phone. Your cell phone can take voice
commands. Yes. What is it called?
AI has sorry Apple has Siri, right? And
uh Android will have whatever Android
has. So you can say, "Hey Siri, blah
blah blah, do this for me. Do do." So
the phone is always listening to you.
The moment you issue a voice command,
it's going to respond to you and and
it's going to do what you what you say,
what you command it to do. So it's
always listening to you. So right now, I
have my phone here. Okay? It's on silent
mode. It's here. It's listening to me.
I could be under surveillance. There's a
high probability I may be under
surveillance, right? And you all also,
it's not like uh we are all special. The
phone is always collecting data. It's
always listening to us. It's always in
our pockets. We're having the most uh
private conversations with our business
partners, with our spouses, with our
parents, with our children, with what
with our whatever with our tax guy, with
our do doctor, all the conversations are
being spied upon and whatever other
digital footprint you have your your
social media or or your email what
everything is under surveillance. What
can be done about this? you the only
solution if you don't want to be under
surveillance is to disconnect completely
which is obviously not practical in
today's today's world. Uh so yeah
definitely change in conventional
espionage tactics. Now a lot of
espionage is is digital. It gives people
it gives intelligence agencies way more
data way more granular data about
individuals. Your travel patterns what
time you travel on a regular basis.
Where do you go to on a regular basis?
What days of the week do you do? What?
Everything is known. Everything. So
super deeply perpetrated.
Divor Singh says Vance connects Trump to
Peter the all these billionaires the
leaked plan of CEO run cities which is
private owned cities. Well that's
interesting. All now
so Peter the is the guy from the PayPal
mafia isn't he? He's an oldtime
connection of Elon Musk. They worked
together on PayPal
and Peter Thiel has had a hand in
founding so many of these startups that
became mega corporations uh tech
companies in the US and uh yeah there's
a bunch of billionaires who are super
powerful super rich and they control
well you could say a lot of the tech
sector and other sectors in the US and
uh yeah if they have plan of CEO run
cities which is private owned cities
that is super super dystopian and uh van
himself is a billionaire.
So, yep,
it's plausible what you're saying. And
even Vive is a billionaire, isn't he?
I'm sure he will also throw his hat into
the ring at some point in time. Vive
Ramas Swami.
Ishan Mukji says, "How to get rid of 700
bases of the USA deter its global
dominance?
How
how
do you do it? Tell me. You want to go to
war?
Try and touch one of their bases. See
what happens.
They will jealously and zealously guard
their bases.
You dare touch one of the bases, they
will obliterate you to to the high
heavens.
How to get rid of it? You don't get rid
of it.
Unless you become a superpower without
touching their bases, that's a whole
different story.
Meet Sandhu says can the ASI
archaeological survey of India access
and research Mahendaro and Harapa which
are located in Pakistan? We can't. We
will not be given access. The good thing
is that the vast majority of
archaeological sites of the Saraswati
Hindu period and region are located in
India, present day India.
So the largest city that we know of from
that time period is Rakari which is
larger than Raki than Mojad and Harpa.
We have that in India. We have
Kalibangan in India which is another
major city and there are more than 2,000
unexplored
unexcavated archaeological sites that
exist
along the dry river banks of the
Saraspati and the majority are in India.
So it doesn't matter if we don't have
access to Mohind and Harpa. We have
access to way more sites than the
Pakistanis have. That's great, isn't it?
So yeah, that's good. That's good. Good
enough for me. I'll have to light
another candle. My candle has gone out.
Looks like we've crossed 3 hours. Oh, we
are reaching the 4hour mark and I'm
still talking. I seem to have quite the
stamina when it comes to speaking. Give
me a second. Let me light this. Check it
out.
Okay, let me light this. All right, here
we go.
Here we are. Here we are.
That goes in there. Okay,
let me take a sip of water.
All right.
And let us continue.
Sarak says
where Jotiba Foule Rajaram Monroy EV Per
told that backward and emphasized of
English education where the social
reformers of British agents.
I'm going to have to say no comments on
this one
and I apologize that you spent some
money on the question. If I could refund
it, I would refund it. But I can I will
not answer this question.
Best not to stay I I'll stay out of this
matter.
Uh I can speak about Ram moanroy. I will
and I suppose I can even speak about uh
Eevee Rama Swami whatever. Uh but the
rest of it I am staying out of it.
I can't fight all the battles. You can't
fight all battles. I I I'll stay in the
realm of realm of geopolitics and
history. I cannot fight every battle.
Yeah. Sorry, I I apologize. Divor Singh
says, "In a hypothetical full-blown war,
could the US defeat or stalemate the
whole world against it?" Look,
in this hypothetical full-blown war, if
you take out the nuclear factor
so that the world isn't destroyed
and if the whole world stands up against
the US, the US can still defeat it.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Totally. They
have that kind of power projection
capability and that sort of lethal
force, lethal force at their disposal.
So they have the naval force, the
tremendously powerful navy.
Their navy has an air force of its own
which is larger than the Indian and
Chinese air forces.
It's the fourth largest air force in the
world. The third largest air force in
the world is the US Marine Air Force.
And there's one more air force and then
then there's the US Air Force itself.
And they have tremendously powerful uh a
tremendously powerful navy. They have
expeditionary forces called the Marines.
And they have more than 700 extr
territorial military bases from which
they can uh rain down hell anywhere they
want. So even without nuclear weapons,
they can take out the rest of the world
combined I suppose. Yeah, that's how
powerful they are.
Uh Vidi Manar says is major chaos coming
from for India soon? Very anxious. There
could be see India has done the
unthinkable and stand and stood up to
the US right we have refused to cave in
we Trump was very clear and I saw this
coming and that's why I thought that
India will vasalize itself and that's
why I had said that if Trump comes to
power there's a very high chance that
India and the US will be dancing hand in
hand which means that India is of
American masal but to my great surprise
and great joy
Mr. Modi has stood up to the US. He has
said we will not vasalize ourselves at
whatever cost
that
is going to infuriate the US and they
will try regime change in India. They
already putting up the infrastructure
around India putting up a string of
fence of thorns around India and they
will operationalize their local
zalinskis in India now. So there could
be some kind of chaos coming in India
maybe protests
maybe whatever you had in Delhi Shahinag
and whatn not that sort of thing could
could start again farmer protests
student protest that sort of thing is
very much possible I hope it doesn't
happen but we should be mentally
prepared for something like that to to
be unleashed across the country by
foreign forces in collaboration with
local zalinskis or aspiring zalinskis.
So just be prepared for it. I am pretty
sure that the government of India can
handle this but we should be mentally
prepared for it.
Priojud Mandal thank you very much sir.
Thank you so much. Anonymous says how
can we make our education free again
without the help of the government?
Impossible. As of now 30 cr students are
here in India. The government will not
without the government help how will you
change the education system? You can't
see so much has to change the education
system.
so much. So for example, uh the
education system and the job market are
interconnected. Today if you want a job
in India, okay, they will ask you to
give us your CV and all your
certificates. What did you have in how
much marks did you get in 10th standard?
How much marks did you get in 12th
standard? What is your college record
like? What did you do your master's
degree in? You may be let's say you
you're applying for a programming job.
You're a great programmer.
But still they will require you to have
a 10th standard, 12th standard degree,
college degree, master's degree, minimum
college degree. What does all of that
have to do with programming? Nothing
really. So the the attitude everywhere
is this very backward colonial attitude.
If I was let's say running a software
company, I would not ask you for your
qualifications. I'll ask you to solve
some problems and if you can solve the
problems and you can show that you're
competent, I'll hire you. I don't care
whether you have a 10 standard degree or
not. I seriously won't care. But all of
these attitudes need to change. And then
the education system, it is a very
colonial system and it perpetuates the
attitude. So it's a two-way thing. The
people who are running the companies,
they came for the education system. So
so they think it's right and it should
continue and they and and it's so it's
it's a feedback loop, you know, it's
like the chicken and egg thing. So if
you want to free the education system
without the help of the government, how
will you do it? I I can't see. I mean
you can create your own own university
for example in which you teach things
totally differently but then when the
students go out of the of your
university or your college or whatever
that you created will they get jobs
the companies will say that you came
from a strange university where they
teach things differently we don't want
you then you will ruin those kids' lives
right so a lot of reforms have to happen
for us to be able to change the
education system the education system
really needs to change but but without
government help it can't happen. If
let's say I have 1,000 cr rupees to burn
so I create my own college and
university but at the end of the day the
people the students who study there they
should get jobs right otherwise what
will happen to them so that's also my
responsibility
and if if I create a syllabus and a
structure and a system where students
will do well but they won't have the
paper degrees to show to the to the to
the interview people then it'll be a
problem. So you know it's it's it's very
complicated. That's the problem. The
government has to be involved
but the government doesn't seem to want
to do it. So so that's where we are.
Naman Jabra says quantum computers are
thought of being extremely good at
simulating nature. Can they be used for
creating new artificial materials that
combine traits that are not usually
found in a single product?
Quantum computers are they can sim they
can simulate certain things that other
computers can't. So quantum computers
they they work on by by
see the concept be behind the concepts
behind quantum computers are
superposition and entanglement. In a
regular computer you have bits. A bit is
either one or zero. Right? It's one or
zero. But a cubit a quantum cubit can be
in a super superp position of more than
one and zero. It can be one or zero or
one and zero and so on. And you can have
entangled cubits that creates
hyperdimensional spaces in which you can
do tremendously complicated
calculations. So that's the difference
between a standard computer and a
quantum computer. And you can quantum
quantum computers can solve certain
problems easily that uh regular
computers will take decades or centuries
or thousands of years or millions of
years to solve. So that's the deal. So
what's the what are quantum computers
going to be useful for? They'll be
useful for solving certain kinds and
certain classes of problems. Like if you
want to brute force a password, a
quantum computer can do it super easily.
A classical standard computer which also
operates on the basis of quantum
mechanics, but that's a different kind
of thing. It will take a long time to do
a brute force attack on passwords. A
quantum computer will do it like that. A
quantum computer will potentially break
any cryptographic encryption, any kind
of encryption, that sort of thing. If
you want to create new artificial
materials and combine traits that are
usually not found in a single products,
I think AI is better for that. AI can
look for patterns and detect patterns
that will take humans god knows how much
time and experience to be able to
detect.
AI can do it brilliantly. So take a
hyper powerful machine like a
supercomput
combined that with AI technology and
then see what kind of new materials new
new molecules new drugs can be
discovered. AI is great at that. You
don't need quantum computing for that.
Quantum computing is good for certain
classes of problems. classes that uh
classical computers simply can't solve.
Priojit Mandal, thank you very much once
again sir. Thank you.
Caution world says why can't we stop all
wars and work towards human well-being
of everyone consisting everyone is going
to die and how insignificant we are in
the universe.
You see ideally that's how the world
would be. Wouldn't it be great if we
stop the wars? If we stop the fighting,
we think about the well-being of
everyone.
Everyone's going to die in a 100 years.
None of us will exist.
In 50 years, most of us will will be
gone. How many of us will be remembered?
How many of us? God knows. We are
insignificant.
In a thousand years, which is nothing,
there'll be no trace of our existence
left individually, right? So, what are
we doing? Why are we fighting? That's
the question.
This only works if everybody thinks this
way.
As long as there is injustice in the
world, there's going to be wars. Let's
say I don't want to fight. I'll say I
will not fight anybody. Just just leave
me alone. I I'll leave you alone. But
then they have to leave me alone. Right?
If I say I will leave you alone, I will
not bother you. I will not fight you. I
will do here sit here and mind my own
business.
But then my neighbor comes and bothers
me. Then what do I do? Should I take it
passively?
Should I just be a passenger in the life
or should on my life or should I then
take steps to defend myself? And that's
how war starts. And then there's the
matter of honor and prestige
that you did so and so things, your
ancestors did so and so things to my
ancestors.
I feel the pain of my ancestors what
they went through
and my duty my honor requires that I
will
I will I will extract justice from you
because you're still glorifying what
your ancestors did. That's another
problem.
And then there are people who want to
leave behind a legacy.
There are people who don't care who know
they'll die. That's fine. I'll die. But
I want to live a glorious life and I
want to be remembered for for for a
thousand years. And those people because
of that outsiz ambition.
Napoleon is a great example and there
are others. That's why you have wars.
So ideally there should be no wars.
Ideally we should all mind our own
business and be happy and work for
everyone's prosperity. But in the real
world there are complications. You see
sir complications.
Complications. We are a complicated
species
and
even if most of us want to be peaceful
that that small minority will be there
who will mess it up for us and that is
the story of human history.
That is the story of human history. A
few people want war and they'll mess
everything up. All right sir. Priyad
Mandal once again. Thank you so much.
Thank you sir.
AI productivity magnet says naki wanted
to support the axis during the second
world war why didn't that happen and
what would have happened had we fought
for the axis instead of the allied
forces nak wanted to support India sir
and because India was under allied
occupation
that's why niti said that I will then
take the help of the enemies of the
allies who are the axis naki had no love
for the Axis or the allies.
But the Axis was the enemy of the allies
who were occupying and brutalizing us.
India had been under allied occupation,
British occupation for almost two and a
half centuries and they had destroyed
India. So when somebody goes to war with
my enemy, I'll support my enemy's enemy
me. Right? That's the deal. Naji had no
love for the axis.
Naji was an Indian patriot. He was an
Indian nationalist. He wanted to
liberate India from the brutal
barbarians who were destroying India for
two and a half centuries. So he said
that if there are my brutal barbarians
have enemies, I'll go with them. And
that's was the deal. All right? And we
could have not fought for the axis
instead of allies because we were under
allied occupation. Understand that too.
Okay.
Viri warm says, "How long will it take
for the American?" I don't know.
I am not Nostra Damos. I don't know. Uh
what are the possible scenarios? How can
India have India should not even talk
about this? India should not even talk
about this. All right, sir.
Feminist Slayer says, "How to deal with
sorrow and accept the harsh realities of
life? By looking for joy in the smallest
things in in mundane life." There is joy
and beauty in life.
Life is a mixed bag. I'll tell you what,
when you are a small child, everything
is nice. You're learning new things
every day. You're discovering new things
every day. You're gaining something
every day. Every day something nice
happens to you. But as you grow older,
you start losing things. You lose a pet.
You lose a friend somewhere. You move to
a different school, you lose all the old
friends. Then as you grow older and
after you become an adult at some point
in time you'll unfortunately sadly
tragically start losing parents and
relatives. So as you grow older life
becomes more tragic.
But that is the nature of life. That is
the nature of the universe. There is
constant change. How to deal with that?
Firstly remind yourself every single
human being who has existed in the past
or today on the planet has gone through
all the same things. So you so we are
not I am not a unique case. Secondly,
despite all all the harsh things that
life does have, there is beauty and joy
in life. There is beauty in in a simple
meal that you can have. There's beauty
and joy in just taking a half an hour
evening walk. There's beauty and joy in
looking at the stars. That beauty and
joy in in being with your close
relatives.
There's beauty. There's joy in so many
small simple things. So it's up to you
if you want to focus on the positives or
the negatives. Both are present. But
which one do you want to focus on more?
You have to make a choice and a decision
for myself. You either tell yourself
yourself that I'm going to focus on the
suffering and the misery and I'm going
to be a sad miserable person. Or you
tell yourself that from today onwards I
know sometimes things bad things will
happen but I will be positive and I will
look for the silver linings. I will look
for the bright side of life and then
your life can be different. So it's up
to you. It's a choice that you to make.
All right.
Sedhart says I have studied eight
genetic articles on Iranian YDNA. None.
So no none show indic descent. Most
Indians are most Iranians are distant
from South Asians except some patans.
Even parses are diff distant. Just
curious how can they be of Indian
descent as I claim.
Okay. Who who has done this genetic
studies? Could you show me the genetic
studies? I have
um except some patam. The pashons are
obviously even genetic studies have
shown that they are an extension of the
north Indian population. Now look I am
not sure what genetic studies you've
seen first of all and secondly
uh most genetic studies that are done in
Asia they typically the the authors of
the studies are typically
westerners. So you'll have a bunch of
authors maybe 15 authors or 10 authors
with one or one or two Iranian names in
there who will be Iranians who will be
working in the west and the genetic
study will be done on a small sample of
Iranian people who are expatriots migr
who have migrated to the west. So we
will take a sample of Iranian origin
people in the west maybe 20 30 people or
maybe 50 people maybe 100 people and do
a and take their blood samples DNA
samples and do a genetic study. Well, is
that a representative sample of all of
Persia? It's not. Will the government of
Iran give access to Iranian genetic
samples to the West? No. Which first of
all immediately tells you that the
sample size that the these studies have
used is going to be not properly
representative of the proper genet
genetic diversity of Iranians. Now let's
say the the population group that this
study did was based on a sample of
people from East Ajarbaijan which is in
Iranian province. Those people will have
no Persian DNA.
No. And if there are eight studies they
still could have these issues. My my
thing is very simple. I would like to
see a genetic study of 10,000 Iranian
samples done in Iran itself by Iranian
scientists. I would like to see the
result of that. then you will have
clarity on what the situation is. Okay.
The thing is this,
today's Iran is not the Iran of 2,000
years ago or 1400 years ago. In the past
14,300 years, there has been a lot of
foreign immigration into Iran which was
done by the foreign occupiers of Iran.
They brought in foreign populations into
Iran into present day Iran.
people from the Caucasus region, people
from people of Azeri origin, people of
Arabic origin. Today only half of Iran's
population is Persian and even that
Persian is mixed Persian.
The Persian people of 2,000 years ago,
if they saw today's Iranian population,
they would not be able to recognize the
ethnicity to significant extent.
So please understand the nuances and
complexities. Sir, I would like to see a
genetic study done in Iran, 10,000
samples from across the geography of
Iran, proper representative samples of
Persian genetics and a study done by
Iranian scientists, not by American or
whatever scientists that I would like to
see then we'll talk.
Okay.
Divor Singh says why were a certain
DV Singh Dor Singh sir DVD Singh
I don't know I I don't know I was not
there
Europeans are very racist you see
very racist people very racist you see
how they treated the Romanis
have you seen how the Europeans treated
the Romani
I I suppose you were talking about the
Romani people, right?
The Romani people, they were of Indian
origin. They were Indians who were
enslaved by the Turks. They were taken
to the slave markets of Bkhar and Surma
Samarand. And eventually the Turks
realized that they have an excess of
Indian slaves. They have taken too many
slaves and they did not want to
slaughter them in in Turk territory. It
was okay to slaughter a few millions in
India but not in in their cities. So
they said get out. You can't go back to
India. Not allowed. You go back. You go
westwards. Get lost. So several thousand
maybe tens of thousands of Indians were
forced to get go into Europe from
Central Asia. Indians and they have been
wandering ever since. They are the
Romani and they have been treated
brutally horribly by the Europeans. A
thousand years roughly of oppression,
second class, third class citizen
status.
Right? Even today many of them are are
are are stateless people. They don't
have citizenship documents and so on.
They have been enslaved. They've been
massacred. All kinds of horrible
atrocities they have been have been
perpetrated on the Romani people, Indian
origin people. And still they have
contributed so much to European culture.
So if the Europeans treated the Romani
like this, I suppose a certain people
the way they were treated may also you
know fit the same pattern perhaps. I'm
just saying perhaps. Okay. They've not
Singh. I think you're not talking about
the Romani people here.
Okay. Viri Verma says, should Russia
occupy the entire Ukraine and teach a
lesson to US and NATO? Is it possible
for in the current situation?
What should Russia do? I think Russia
should decide. Okay. Russia should every
nation should prioritize its national
interests
and whatever Russia's per perception of
its national interest is, that is what
Russia should do.
So I am no one to give recommendations
to Russia as to what it should do. And
if I do that then I will be portrayed as
as a Russian agent, anti-West.
I am non-West. I'm not anti-West.
And I I mean I think Russia is the
victim over here. It's not the
aggressor. So I would say Russia should
prioritize its national interest and
whatever is its perception of the
national interest and what is the best
outcome in their in their perception
they should go for that and NATO and
Ukraine they should do whatever is best
in their interests and we shall sit here
and watch
okay that's what that's what I would say
let us not take sides sitting here
more or less
okay
oh one second I need to Yes.
Ah,
T is good. T is very good.
Okay. Uh, what's the question by MK? Did
the Japanese gods were these gods
created parallelly or due to Indian
influence like ancient Greece or Europe?
Japan is a very ancient land, very
beautiful land, beautiful culture.
The Japanese have indigenous gods
called kami.
Kami. Have you heard the term kamikaz?
Kamik kaz. It means divine wind. The
wind of the gods. The kami kaz was two
sets of of uh
typhoons or whatever it was that
thwarted two invasion fleets that were
supposed to invade Japan. who had
launched those the Mongol Empire Shri
Kubla Khan not Shir Chingish Khan Shri
Kubla Khan and both times Kami Kaz came
in the way and saved Japan. Uh so Kami
are the indigenous Japanese gods they
are the gods
the ancestral gods of the Japanese
people
um ancestor worship nature worship or
that sort of thing. The kami are the
gods that are part of Shinto, the Shinto
culture in religion of Japan. And over
the centuries, over one and a half
almost 2,000 years, Shinto and Indian
religion synretized beautifully into a
into a into a a single unified religion
and culture which was both Shinto and
and Indian at the same time. And all the
Indian gods they were given Japanese
names. So uh Saraswati Dvi becomes
Benzaitan in Japan and uh
and Lord Ganesha becomes Kangitan and in
Japan he loves radishes instead of ladus
and uh Lord Kuber I forget his name
there. Lord Shiva also has a name
Kalahav has a Japanese name. All Indian
gods have Japanese names and most of
these gods are Hindu gods not not
Buddhist gods. And of course Lord the
Buddha is also worshiped there in in
Japan. So u so the Japanese gods the
original Shinto gods were completely
indigenous to Japan and then we have all
the Indian divinity divinities that come
in and they are also given places in the
Japanese pantheon. So that was the deal.
So ancient Greece and Europe they have
the same gods as India and India was the
origination place. India was the origin
but Japan you got the same Indian gods
but they already had their own gods and
they coexisted and harmonized. You see
that was the difference.
Rohan Suna says Scandinavian education
fields worldclass. Harvard and Warton
grads seem mid but Scandinavian PhDs are
just brilliant. Best problem solvers I
have ever seen. Well, okay. Interesting.
Interesting.
H
see
people believe that Cambridge and and uh
Oxford are the best in the world. That's
what people used to believe. Now it's
all Harvard and Princeton and whatn not
Watton and so on. Uh but it's because
Britain Britain was the most powerful
empire for the longest time for for two
centuries two and a half centuries. So
whatever was their best universities was
those were regarded as the best in the
world. Then the Americans became the
world's premier supreme empire the
superpower. So now people think that
their universities are the best but
that's not always the case. The
Scandinavian countries they are like
they don't aspire to great power status
but it's possible that they may have a
superior education system. So yeah uh
I've heard a lot about the Scandinavian
education system. It's not based on root
learning and memorization and all that
nonsense. It's about you know you go
with your interests and learn as you
play and that sort of thing and maybe
it's a better approach and eventually at
a certain level you can formalize
education after you enter college or
whatever by the time you've acquired the
knowledge the basic knowledge that you
need so yeah I I would say it makes
sense what you're saying a lot of sense
rama 100 well thank you so much thank
you I was wondering what's the question
thank you very much for the contribution
sir okay Ankita sorry I'm sorry ankit ta
says
How to learn coding and AI effectively
to master it. Get your hands dirty. Get
down and dirty into it. You want to
learn coding, you can't learn coding by
reading a book. You learn coding by
starting stuff. Try hello world. Can I
write a program that can display hello
world? The first time it works, you'll
be like, "Wow, I did it. Now let me
write hello world and go away world or
something like that." Then you try to
expand it, extend it, then you try to
make it interactive. So you have to
learn coding, you have to do coding.
You have to do coding. You can only
learn something by doing it. You can't
learn something by reading a book. And
the same with AI. AI also I mean it's
it's a the basis is is computer science.
So you first learn by you first start by
learning one programming language. These
days they recommend Python. Back in the
day it was C. uh Python is a good enough
programming language to start off with
and then then you can go on to other
languages and so on server side back end
blah blah blah and you have to learn
computer science fundamentals algorithms
and whatnot if you want to go into AI
and all that and obviously you need to
learn statistics
um yeah so it's a long path but the way
to learn anything is to do it by doing
it by making a lot of mistakes and by
correcting those mistakes that's how we
learn things
um aurva ja says Please explain the
original jati vera jati system.
So it's something that evolved in the
past 1500 or 2,000 years maximum. The
jati system may be very ancient. The
vera system is more recent because uh 2
and a half thousand years ago when the
Greek ambassador was in India, his name
was Mastanes. He was in the in partra in
the court of Chandra Gupta. He wrote a a
a field report let's say called Indica
which was which was a description of
Indian society and the Indian cities and
so on and he said that Indian society
was was divided into seven classes.
So we think of four casts right today
four casts India had seven classes uh I
don't remember the classes but we can
look it up right now. Okay, let's go to
Google
and Megasan
Indian classes.
I think it'll give you the okay Indian
classes of society, philosophers,
farmers, soldiers, herdsmen, hunters,
artisans, traders, magistrates and
counselors or ministers, right? It's a
Greek filtered view of morian society
focus focusing on professions rather
than the he mentions there's no cast
system you godamned AI
look at look at look at the perspective
it's trying to put on on things
did not mention any cast system he said
there were seven classes of people in
India and still this AI overview thing
is trying to superimpose the cast system
see this is how they mislead Indians and
Indians are so docsile today they'll be
misled misled very easily. Anyhow, those
were the seven classes of society during
Morian during the Morian Empire. And
then you have the Jati and Vera. So the
Vera are the four major like those those
so-called casts. But the real system was
the was the Jati system. Jati is a
occupation based system. Let's say
someone's family is in the process is is
in the business of uh
being a goldsmith. You know you're all
goldsmith. You have a set of trade
secrets and skills that you want to keep
within the family within the lineage.
You don't want the secrets to go out and
be be you know be be stolen by other
families. So you keep everything
tight-knit and that is your jati.
Somebody else has a different occupation
and they also have the trade secrets. So
they will only marry among people of the
same community.
Same community means the same trade, the
same trade and same profession. And you
keep it strictly within that. And
because India was the first fully
industrialized society, you had so many
different occupations and professions,
thousands of these maybe tens of
thousands.
And because India is such an ancient
land, you had people connection people
to people connections all for like spans
of thousands of kilometers very ancient
connections. So you will know that you
know 17 generations ago one of my family
members went and settled in that city
2,000 km away. So if I travel there
today and I enquire I will still find my
my family people there my family members
there and then if it's like that then
you know you can have you can establish
trade networks and all or whatever and
you marry only among the same uh the
same profession essentially. So the so
the jati system was an occupation and
profession based system and you had
thousands of jatis in India and that's
how India was was was organized because
okay let's ask Google what are the
defining characteristics of a
civilization okay let's ask and let's
let's see it live what Google says
what are the defining
characterist istics of civilization.
Let's see. Highly organized society.
Does it say complex division of labor?
Advanced cities, specialized labor,
complex institutions,
social structure and stratification.
Societies are organized into different
social classes or roles with varying
responsibilities, influence. Every
civilization has that, right? But India
is demonized for this. You see, did you
did you see what Google says? Every
civilization has this characteristic.
The societies are organized into
different social classes or rules with
varying responsibilities
and influence. Every civilization, every
civilization has this characteristic.
But India is demonized for being a
civilization. This is the central
characteristic of a civilization. A
highly evolved and stratified society
with proper organization and division of
labor. That's the sign of a highly
evolved and ancient society and
civilization. But we are demonized for
that. So if you have thousands of jatis,
tens of thousands of jatis, imagine how
ancient our civilization is. And today
what exists? Nothing. Everything has
been smashed.
Okay. Sam Suba says, "Who is Nepal's new
lady prime minister and is linked with
the US and China? What is the potential
impact?" I have no idea at this point in
time. I have no idea. I don't I know
very little about this lady. She is a
former member of the Supreme Court. I
believe it's a former justice apparently
and she was married to a politician who
was involved in a plane hijacking in the
20th century. And beyond that, we don't
we don't know much. So, we'll have to
wait and watch what her potential impact
is going to be. uh ideally if you want
to run a puppet government and have the
real power hidden behind the scenes then
you have somebody in the front who seems
to have be of no consequence.
So we I am not going to make any any
remarks or any any
statements at this point in time. I'm
going to wait and watch for at least a
week.
But I have already said this. My gut
feeling is that this is a US mediated
regime change operation. Now, let's see
if I pro am proven to be wrong or right
about this. But I'm going to wait at
least a week to see the patterns that
that emerge out of things before I start
making wonderful great pronouncements
like an expert. A real expert will shut
the shut the hell up until things calm
down. So, I'm going to I'm going to wait
for the patterns to emerge. No knee-jerk
reactions, no premature reactions.
You have to be mature in these things.
Okay. All right. Uh, Retwik Yuani says,
"Your 10 trillion
dollar 10 trillion containment
hypothesis was spot on. US and China
encircle India via unrest. Can we manage
both adversaries at once?" Look, if you
are a Chanakian state, you can manage
multiple adversaries at once. You need
to know each adversaries strengths and
weaknesses. You need to know which what
each adversary seeks. You have to know
which what each adversary fears. You
have to know your strengths, your
weaknesses, your red lines, their red
lines. Once you have a clear
understanding of the entire scenario, of
the entire battlefield, let's say, then
if you play the game right, you'll be
fine. So, it's about clarity. It's about
clarity of understanding of everyone's
purpose, everyone's ambitions, and
everyone's needs, desires, wants, fears,
threat perceptions, red lines,
strengths, weaknesses, all of that. We
can manage both adversaries at once.
Serva Maya Ai, thank you, sir. Thank
you, ma'am. Sir or ma'am, thank you.
Kajoro Batthon says, "See being the
global left justify and celebrate murder
of Kirk and praise the Nepal revolution
as a righteous people's revolt. Will our
leftist lunatics be emboldened by this?
They're openly saying no more debate, go
for violent carry."
Yeah. The global left is like this. You
see, they claim to be liberal.
They claim to be liberal, but they want
to silence everybody who has an opinion
that that they don't agree with. And
violence is a is a form of silence
silencing someone. Assassination is a
form of silencing silencing someone. Now
this Charlie Kirk, whoever he was, good,
bad, whatever, he was a legal citizen of
that country and he had the right
according to his constitution to do
whatever he was doing. If he was
engaging in political activity,
everybody has a right to do that. But he
was silenced in the most ultimate in in
the most uh uh final way possible,
right? And we're not quite sure who did
that. Somebody has been arrested for
this, but we're not sure who knows if
it's a cover up or if that person is a
scapegoat, a pathy. Yeah, your own
father turned you in, so it must be
true. I don't know. Anything's possible
in the world.
And there are there are apparently
elements within India who are saying
that they're praising the Nepal
situation and they are saying that there
should be a Jenzi thing in India also.
If since the Nepal thing seems to have
succeeded, the Indian lefties will be
emboldened by this especially the ones
who have foreign funding who will be ged
to potentially do this in the coming
days, weeks, months, whatever. Yeah,
potentially. Potentially. Uh and they
are saying openly that we need to go for
violence. Well, yeah. So, like I've
said, there is there is a higher
probability of uh some such situation
that could potentially be engineered in
India by foreign forces in the coming
future sometime. Yeah, there is a higher
probability of this happening and the
objective is to destabilize the
government of India to to create this
impression that the that the prime
minister and his government are weak and
they are not able to to control the
country. that sort of thing that that
that is a great way of starting the
process of regime change. So that is
most likely something that has a higher
probability of happening in the coming
future whatever time it is. I hope it
doesn't happen first of all but we have
to be aware that this is a situation
that could perhaps happen and we should
be mentally prepared for that.
Geopolitical Dubai says, "Have the
bodies of men and women evolved side by
side and in which ways has this taken
place? Don't quote me. I'm not a science
guy." It's okay. It's okay. No, no
issues. One second.
Um, see, we are the same species.
We have two genders, two sexes. It's
called sexual dimmorphism, right? So, if
you look at frogs,
let's let's take a science examples.
You look at frogs, they look very
similar, but they have certain diorphic
uh characteristics between the two
genders or sexes. If you look at lions,
lion, male lion, female lion, they look
different. Tigers only only size
difference and certain very subtle
differences apart from that they look
very similar and so on. Cats, you can't
really tell sometimes, you know,
especially when they're kids. Uh dogs
all that. So, we we are the same
species. We haven't evolved side by
side. We have evolved together.
I mean males when they are born they are
born from their mothers from women
right?
So it's not like we are evolving
evolving separately as two separate
species. We are the same species and our
evolution happens simultaneously
together.
In what ways has it happened has it
taken place? It's happened in what ways?
It has happened through the process of
Darwinian evolution.
the survival of the fittest, the
evolution of the fittest. So if you look
at Homo sapiens um u fossils from
400,000 four lakh years ago, if you look
at the fossils that were found in Jabel
Hud in North Africa, you will see that
those fossils of homo sapiens, they
exhibit certain features that are pretty
archaic. They overall are anatomically
similar to modern human beings, but they
have certain features that are archaic
like the the ridge of the brow. It's
it's larger. It's like more pronounced
and and so on. Certain characteristics
that you don't really see in modern
populations. So you can see male and
female skeletons there which have the
same characteristics.
So the same charact because because
parents and children they share DNA,
right? A child let's say it's it's a
male child or a female child will have
50 50 cont 50% 50% contribution from
both parents
right so the evolution is happening from
both parents you know if if it's a girl
who is born she will not only have DNA
from the mother's side she will also
have 50% of the father father's DNA so
evolution is happening simultaneously at
the same time and you're getting
contribution from both your parents
so it's not evolving side by side or
evolving parallelly it's evolving it's
the species evolving the way all species
do.
All right.
Tarun says, "Do you think Indians in
Greece is credible?" It's full of pseudo
linguistics like Aditi. Aditi Athina.
Who says that? My god. I have never said
Aditi is Athena.
Aditi is Athena with different meaning.
The author wasn't a historian of I am
not talking about P and Oak. PN Oak by
God the kind of
PN Oak is not a credible author. My god
the kind of absolute nonsense he has
written in some cases.
My god P and Oak you can't take that as
a credible author unfortunately.
I have never ever referred to P and Oak
for anything. I have never said Aditi
Aditi is Athena Athena. I've never said
that. What I have said is this and
please pay attention. What I have said
is Zeus Peter is Dios Petru. It is the
Greek version of Dios Petru the name but
the characteristics are those of Indra.
And try and debunk this please.
That's all I'm saying. Right. Try and
debunk that.
try and debunk my claim that Jupiter,
the Roman Jupiter is the Roman version
of Zeus Peter. Jupiter came from Zeus
Peter and the Greek Zeus Peter came from
Dios Petru, the Vic sky god, the father
of Indra.
and also try and disprove the fact that
Zeus per the Greek Zeus per has all the
characteristics of Indra. The hammer and
thunderbolt the Vajger symbology
symbolism. The fact that
that Indra defeats Vitra, the great sea
monster who had encircled the world
ocean and he he defeated this great sea
monster Indra. And what does the Zeus
paid do? He defeats Typhon,
a Greek sea monster. Same story. Now try
and debunk this. I am not going the way
of P and Oak. My god, P and Oak is not
credible. I never said Aditi is Athena.
Come on. No, I am saying Zeus Peter is
Dio Pitru. And now try and debunk that.
All right.
Okay. Da Chandan Malik says, "What
happens if the US exploits? Why is there
no physics question?
Why?
whole history, geopolitics, no one
interested in science. It's so
disappointing. Anyway,
Da Chandan Malik says, "What happens if
the US exploits internal political force
lines in India to bring an inexperienced
leader to power leading to failures in
rising social communal tensions?"
Part one Chat. What happens if this
succeeds? India is
namu.
We're done. We're cooked. We're baked.
That's what happens. If they succeed,
that is what happens. We're done. It's
over.
Vnor Singh says, "So we were also
probably the first people to make
alcohol for consumption, madiraa or
mead, honey, wine in in Celtic history."
Um,
meid is probably an English old English
word. Honey wine madu. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We we I'm sure even
during the vic times people some people
would have had alcohol. It's not like it
was taboo or ferbothan.
Uh we do have the word madira. What's
the sanskrit word for al alcohol? Is it
madira? Let me let me just check it.
Check it. Okay. Okay, let's always fact
check ourselves.
Sunkrit
dictionary. Let's go to Sanskrit
dictionary. Do we have this? Okay, we'll
go here and uh let us say wine.
What was the wine? Wine. Madya.
Madya. Madira. Wine. Yeah. So, yeah,
that is the one there. There's so many
other words for wine. Sura, Maduri,
Kadamara,
Draaras, Draxaras, which which is which
is grape wine, grape juice actually, hal
and so on. So anyway, yeah, the word for
for the the first word, the madira and
madhya that comes from madu, which is
obviously honey. So it's possible that
we may have been the first. But I
suppose that wherever you had human
beings, the wine would have existed in
some form. I think it's a pretty ancient
phenomenon. I'm I'm sure that even the
out of Africa migrants may have known
why but perhaps the oldest word that is
in existence is ours. So yeah,
Priojit Mandal says the Hindus
themselves are pretty divided. I saw
many Shivbaks always insult Bhagan
Vishnu online and many more. It hurts
me. I don't know what to do. You know
what?
Ignore all this.
Ignore it. There are many of us who
don't do it. Right?
It is unfortunate that we are divided.
This community will will taunt that
community. That taunt community will
taunt this. Why do this? You do your
thing. Let them do their thing. Respect
what they are doing. They have a
different way of doing things. They
worship so and so God. You worship so
and so God. You do your thing. Let them
do. I don't understand why people
do all these things. If if only India
was a more literate society and a more
civilized society. this would not
happen. Now my point is don't take it
personally. You may follow whichever p
of of dharma. Please happily follow it.
There will always be some people who are
who are misled, who are misguided, who
have not got the correct guidance, which
is why they behave in ways that our
civilization would not have tolerated
and would not have recommended in the
past. But today we are less civilized
and all of this that we are seeing are
symptoms of us being in a in a less
civilized state. Today our civilization
is being eroded. Right? So that is why
these things are happening. Um don't
take it personally. Don't be hurt but
don't indulge in in counter stone
throwing. What's the point? Stay out of
all these unnecessary disputes.
There are many people who are very
respectful of of all the different uh of
all the different uh parts of Hindu
dharma. I mean Bhagwan Shiva and Bhagwan
Vishnu. Aren't they two sides of the
same coin? Part of the morti. So why
would you do that? I mean it's so it is
it is it is it's something that shows
that you have very little knowledge
about your own religion. Right? Anyway,
don't take it personally and uh ignore
all this nonsense. But that's what I
would say.
Data Chandan Malik says, "Could these
tensions enable the rise of a far right
leader backed by the US
who mobilizes large scale national
protests and eventually takes power?"
Part two. uh you mean in India
who a farright leader in India who's
backed by the US? The US will never do
it. The US will never back a right soft
right or farright leader in India. They
will only back left leaders.
Okay.
Um there's no chance of a farright
leader coming from US backed
nationwide protests in India.
Impossible. The US will never tolerate
farright leaders because farright
leaders are nationalists and
nationalists will never vaselize their
country. Do you understand why? It's
only lefties who will vaselize their
their country. Okay. Harsha Patel says,
"I've been following you. You're
amazing. Well, thank you so much, sir.
You you're also amazing for following
me. Thank you so much. Honestly, really.
Now, uh with all the insight you have,
it's frustrating you share. It's
frustrating not being able to act. How
can I help spread awareness
or join a movement? Can't be in if you
form a team. Well, as individuals, we
can't do a thing, you see. and spreading
awareness. I mean you can spread
awareness but um it's it's essentially
talk or or or or writing. Beyond that
what awareness can you spread? Yeah, you
can you can achieve more if you are in a
team as such. I have never thought of
forming a team.
Um
I don't know. Let's see if I ever think
of forming a team. I will invite all
like-minded people.
The question is if I form a team let's
say hypothetically
forming a team you need to have an
objective you need to have a clear
direction clear goal and when there's
where there's a team there's a
leadership structure you need someone
has to be the leader and that has its
own set of problems and all so it's
something you don't do lightly let's
form a team it's not like forming a
discord server then where everything
goes haywire right so let's see if I
ever decide in the future to form a team
I certainly will count you in and thank
you so much for for for following it for
everything else. Thank you so much.
Ryikani says, "There was a recent
congressional
there were recent congressional UFO
hearings. Are they a cover to distract
from the Epstein fallout and the alleged
Charlie Kirk assassination?" UFOs are
always a great smoke screen to cover up
things. Whenever there is something
inconvenient happening in the US, let's
have a spate of UFO sightings. So, the
media will say, "Oh, UFO, UFO, UFO, UFO
sighting here, UFO sighting there." and
the and the big news is covered up. It's
it's drowned out in this avalanche of
noise coming from UFO sightings. I
remember
during the last around the time of the
last presidential election in the US
which was last year, the second half of
the last year, last quarter of the last
year
at that time there was this big spate of
UFO UFO sightings. If you were in New
Jersey, my goodness, hundreds of UFO
sightings every day. And later the the
State Department, no, the the the
White House spokesperson, spokes lady or
whoever she is right now, she said that
these are all US government drones.
So she essentially admitted the US has
this technology that looks like UFOs,
right? Uh so these UFOs, I don't think
there's any alien involvement in this,
extraterrestrial involvement. I think
these are all uh American technological
programs that are classified and when
they are cited they are they look like
UFOs and they can be weaponized in this
manner. So whenever something
inconvenient is happening let's do a
spate of UFO UFO sightings. So all the
media attention can be and social media
attention can be focused on the UFOs and
what's happening the inconvenience stuff
can be quietly forgotten. So yes yes
it's I think it's a standard operating
procedure actually isn't it?
Nila Shivasov says your theory of
primordial black black holes as dark
matter candidate was given by an green
of from the University of Nottingham
without giving due credit to you. What's
my POV? She is doing independent
research. An green great lady.
She isn't uh see my theory is this
quantized bound states
stable quantum mechanical bound states
of primordial black holes as a potential
candidate for dark matter for the cold
dark matter that that seems to permeate
the universe. That's my theory which
first came out in the year 2002. That's
23 years ago. Anne Green has done a lot
of work on primordial black holes, but
she hasn't proposed a parallel or rival
theory of bound states of primordial
black holes as a candidate for dark
matter. She's doing different research
on primordial black holes. She has put
out constraints on primordial black hole
formation and so on. I haven't seen her
more recent research in case she has
done it. But I don't think she has done
research in which she has taken
something from me and not given credit
to me. That's not the case. She's a
great lady and she's a very good
researcher. So, as far as I know, that's
not the case. But if since you're
saying, I'll check it out once once
again. I I don't think uh that's the
case. But anyway, thank you for looking
out for me and thank you for letting me
know in case there's something. Thank
you.
Okay.
Da Chandan Malik says, "If such a
hardline regime deepens unrest, could
this trigger regional resistance strong
enough to push the country towards
fragmentation or bulcanization?
Um
if there's any deepened unrest in the
country whether there's a hardline
regime or a very weak regime
if there is deepening unrest and
especially if there is engineered
regional resistance to the union and all
that that can push the country towards
balconization and fragmentation and that
obviously is the ultimate objective of
anti-India forces more powerful
anti-India forces and countries
And they are they have been fund funding
this these movements for decades since
the 1950s and60s
the these movements the the roots for
which were planted by the British and
then the other powers have taken over so
yeah it is certainly a threat that's an
everpresent threat for India which is
why it is very important to clamp down
on all these foreign activities in India
or foreign funded activis activities in
India through through all legal means
possible.
Right? That that's what needs to happen.
If you have large scale industrial scale
religious conversion activities that
needs to stop and there are so many
other activities under under the guise
of NGO activities and god knows what
else is academic activities, seminars,
uh tourism, all kinds of stuff. So I
think we have been pretty lax in uh
doing this. Maybe there's pressure from
outside to allow this to continue
perhaps.
But yeah, it can certainly push the
country towards balkcanization,
fragmentation. Indeed, it's a big big
threat to India.
Uh
DVN Singh says big no go nose guys who
clip coins are demonized unjustifiably
or justifiably. Look, I haven't studied
the history of the big nose guys who
clipped coins.
I am look I I know what you're talking
about. You're talking about the Jews.
Are they demonized unjustifiably or
justifiably? I know about the the
allegations the Europeans used to make
about the Jews. The Europeans used to
accuse the Jews of blood liel. The
Europeans used to claim in different
parts of Europe they used to claim that
Jews allegedly according to the
Europeans they they poison wells. That's
what some Europeans used to claim. Other
Europeans used to claim that the Jews
abduct children and drink their blood or
something like that. I don't know what
it was. So all these accusations used to
be ba made against Jews. It's it's part
of the historical record. It's some of
it is called the blood liel against
Jews. And uh because of this, Jews were
persecuted in various parts of Europe.
There were anti-Jewish pograms in some
some places. There was there were
multiple occasions where this happened
in England. You had uh the expulsion of
Jews from Spain after the reconista
and Jews faced persecution in I don't
know Germany, Saxony, Romania, other
places. Was this demonization
justifiable, unjustifiable? Well,
I I haven't looked deep into the matter.
I may only have superficial knowledge on
this. And the superficial knowledge says
that these are all false accusations.
That's what I've read. Now, I can only
comment on this if I have gone deeper
into the topic, which I have not because
this is this this aspect of history has
not really interested interested me
much. So, I don't know. I can't really
say for sure whether this was
justifiable or or unjustifiable.
Um so I'll I'll leave it at that sir.
Okay. Godliness says are we postponing
the worst from happening? We don't have
a one party system. Someday the BJP will
lose and then what I fear all the hard
work and hope for 20 47 vit can derail.
Um
yeah perhaps
see a one party system is
well
it can happen actually see the US
doesn't have any constitutional mandate
that you need to have a two-party system
but it's become a two-party system so in
India also since even though there is no
constitutional mandate for a two-party
or one party system it can be made to
happen through constitutional means
um and the thing is that once you come
to power you have to the nature of power
is that If you don't hold on to power
and and entrench your power and augment
your power, you're going to lose power
at some point in time. So, is the BJP
has the BJP been um too too lax? Have
they not taken the opportunities they've
got? Have they not done enough? I don't
know. I think it's it's for you all to
decide. I don't really look at internal
politics. So, I don't know. But yeah, if
if someday the BJP loses and then
everything they did was is undone, then
it's going to be all have it will all
have been worth nothing, right? So I
suppose if there is a threat of that
situation occurring, then the BJP
should take it extremely seriously. Yes.
DN Singh says, "How was Yale founded on
looted money from India?" Ili Yahu Yale
was a British official of the East India
Company. Where was he stationed? Was he
stationed somewhere in southern India? I
don't recall where he was stationed. But
he was a British official of the East
India Company. Ilahuil or Ilihu,
whatever the name was. It's a very weird
name, foreign name to me. So I don't So
apologies if if I mispronounce it.
So this guy he served in India and then
he clearly amassed a fortune
uh that was plundered from India and
then he goes to the United States
and then uh he donates some money
eventually which founds which is the
seed money for the foundation of Yale
College which eventually becomes Yale
University. So the seed money that was
required for the initial founding of
Yale College came from money plundered
from India. No question about it. Yes.
And there could be many such more
instances that we are not aware of. Yale
somehow has come to light. There may be
many more because there was a time when
the what is today the United States was
a territory that was in the in the um in
the possession of the British and the
British also possessed India at the
time. So you had a flow of officials.
For example, the the the guy the the the
British general
or or administrator who surrendered to
the uh Americans when they finally won
their war of independence was Lord
Cornwallis.
He is the guy who surrendered to the
Americans and surrendered the country
and that led to the foundation of the
new country the United States. That same
lord the coronalis then came to India
and lorded over Indians. It's a pity
that we did not kick him out the same
way the Americans did but anyhow that's
how history went.
Uh Dark Knight says is Dnor Singh being
possibly funded by the US? Well only Dur
Singh G can tell us.
Uh Bharati says have you read the books
by Nilles Oak during dating Ramay and
Mahabarat using astrology? Your
thoughts? Um I have not read his books
and so I can't really comment on that
and he has not done this through
astrology. He has done through this
through archo astronomy that much I know
but I haven't studied his books so I
will not be able to comment on because I
because I've not read them so sorry
about that.
Ritik Yiddwanchi says will you be at
Jaipur dialogues on day one or two? Most
likely I'll be there. Yes.
Ritik Yuani says India faces more
threats from India from outside or
inside. I think equal
most of the internal threats in India
are funded from the outside.
So so the outside threats threat not
threats okay potentially outside
threats. So the outside threats want to
create aspiring zeal they want to
identify aspiring zalinskies in India
and fund the more capable ones and those
become the internal threats and they are
full of outside funding. So they have
resources that's what happens. So I
think we face equal
the the the we face 50% outside threat
50% internal threat but the nature of
the two threats are is very different.
The internal threats are very different
from the external threats even though
the two are intertwined.
Prashant says India vote for two state
in Palestine in UNG. What are my
thoughts? Okay. I have no thoughts. It's
all right.
It's okay.
I I am not angry or upset or anything.
That's just the stand we have. That's
all right. I have no issue with that. I
think there should be a two-state
solution. And to to be very honest,
Israel tried for a two-state solution.
They gave
a separate piece of land to the
Palestinians called Gaza. So, what did
they do there? They elected Hamas, a
terrorist organization. Israel tried for
a two-state solution, but the
Palestinians weaponized that. Anyway,
there still, I would say, should be a
two-state solution, and I suppose that's
why India has voted for that. Uh,
someday there should be peace there,
hopefully, whichever way. So, that's all
right. That's perfectly all right. I
have no other thoughts or comments
beyond that. Amisha says, "How do you
see the claim that Kilji saved India
from Mongols?" H
that's how I see it.
He Kilji was defending his sultanet from
Mongol parties that were passing ac near
the border and maybe they were curious
to see how how deep can we investigate
or do a reconnaissance miss mission into
Indian territory or or or Turk held
territory of India. It was not an
invasion of India by the Mongol Empire
and and Kilji was very very very
fortunate that he did not live during
the time that Shir Chingish Khan was
alive. There are many Indians, okay,
many genius level Indians who tell me
that Chingghist Khan was defeated by
Laen Kilji.
Okay. Now, now let's do some facteing
for the this is for those geniuses who
comment every day. Okay.
Pingis Khan
death. So when did he die? August 2027.
1227. Okay.
Now Allah admin
Kalgi
1227 Chinghan died. And this guy when
did when was he born? Kalji
he was he reigned from 1296.
That is almost 70 years after Chingish
Khan died. When was this fellow born?
He was born in 12 1266. So he was born
39 years after the death of Shir Chingis
Khan. Allahadin Kilji. If Allahadin
Kilji had been the Sultan of Delhi or
whatever during Chingish Khan's time and
if Chingish Khan had decided that I will
invade India,
Allah Kilji would have run back to
Turkey or wherever or he would have been
decimated,
obliterated, eviscerated.
Allad Kilji was no great ruler. He was a
fortunate guy. He was not he had he did
not have to face Chingishan's army. It
was just a marauding reconnaissance
party of a few hundred, you know, few
few dozen Mongol uh
scouts or whatever. That's that's all it
was. It's a joke. The some people claim
that Allahin Kilji saved India from
Mongols. What a joke. Absolute joke.
Surva Ai says how to tackle internal 0.5
and Hindu become Hindu ashtra. I don't
know. I I talk about geopolitics. I I
don't talk about these Hindu Muslim
issues and internal problems and all.
That's a whole different set of issues
that I don't look into. I look at the
external issues. I look at history. I
look at geopolitics. I look at science.
I don't know about this. This is not
within my my purview so to say. So I
won't be able to answer this question
sir. Sorry.
Uh Ritiki says some Nepalese like
Bangladesh see India as evil due to
foreign propaganda despite shared roots.
Have we lost them though they're part of
us? The past 30 plus years there has
been brainwashing. See there was a
regime change operation in Nepal in the
1990s. The Mauist terrorist insurgency
succeeded. The Nepales Rajat Tantra or
monarchy was thrown out. Their royal
family was wiped out and the corrupt
communists and Mauists ruled the country
ever since. And they were in the pocket
of China and other foreign forces. And
that's why they for the past 30 years
have been brainwashing the children of
Nepal into hating India. And that's why
most Nepales see India as an enemy
nation. Not most but many. I think there
are still many Nepalese who don't see
India as an enemy nation. You don't hate
India or don't fear India. But I think
there is a significant
population percentage of the population
especially young population in Nepal who
see India as as this aggressive
expansionist nation that wants to break
Nepal or whatever. So this is propaganda
and this is I mean whose fault is it to
some extent it's our fault our
governments that they did nothing to
counter this right
test user says how long do you for how
long will you do 8our study work live
videos I don't know I'll see as long as
it's fun yeahan
says what's the likelihood of putin
invading very
What's the likelihood of Putin invading
another country like the Baltics during
Trump's term? Would it be right to say
the chances are high? I think the
chances are very low. Very low. Putin is
not crazy. He's not a maniac. He's a
very rational person. No. What's the
point of doing that? What will he get?
What will he gain from this? Nothing. I
think the likelihood is very low. Of
course, I may be proven wrong, which is
okay. But I think the likelihood is very
low.
Okay. Godliness says, "Your view on the
Russian cancer vaccine, is it some kind
of pharma warfare against the West?" A
vaccine is not a warfare, right? A
vaccine is a good thing. So, if the
Russians have indeed developed a a
cancer vaccine, I would say
congratulations to Russia. Very
impressive job. Very well done. And if
if possible, do export it to India as
well because I'm sure lots of Indians
can benefit from that. I don't see this
as as any kind of warfare against
anybody. This is something they're doing
to benefit their own citizens. That's
how I see it.
Okay. Dana Chand says,
"Is there any hope the Indian judiciary
will be reformed? Is this something the
BJP is serious about? The judiciary
right now is part of the 0.5 front." I
look this is once again an internal
matter of India. I look at the external
matters. I don't know about this.
I can't I I don't comment about
everything in the world when it comes to
internal politics, internal issues. I
will talk about the education system,
the need for reforms and so on. But all
of these things I I see first of all I
don't really have deep enough
understanding of this. I have studied
things across the world. I've not
studied the judiciary and all that. So
yeah, I don't know about this. Sorry.
Dur Singh says does multiple gods in a
culture means multiple moralities?
Abrahamic people say they have one book
one morality. Well that's a that's a
hyper simplistic way of looking at
things. The world is complicated. The
world is super complex. The human psyche
is complex. Think about it.
A single person
can be seen as a superposition of
multiple personalities. You have some
good in you. You have some ambiguity in
you. You have some bad also in you.
You can be a nice person but be capable
of cruelty at times. You can be a good
person but be capable of violent temper
sometimes.
Then you can be a bad person and
sometimes do some good things completely
uncharacteristic. The human psyche
itself is so complicated.
And the root causes of all these things,
the good and the bad and whatever it
goes back to to deep roots, cultural
roots, uh philosophical roots,
childhood, the kind of childhood you
had, the kind of influences you had.
And when it comes to a culture, the
roots, especially when it comes to
India, our roots goes back go back
thousands of years. We have so many
superposed
um all of these, you know, all of these
memories, civilizational memories,
civilizational um influences, all of
that. So if you try to boil everything
and distill everything down to just one
morality, I think you're doing yourself
a tremendous injustice.
And if you have multiple gods, it it it
kind of honors the fact that divinity
also takes multiple shapes and forms.
It's like
it's like division of labor in the in
the in the realm of divinity. Some gods
will look look at learning, some gods
will look at, you know, wealth, some
gods will be the god god of whatever
whatever whatever, right?
And
when it comes to the major gods in in
our culture, we have the the trinity,
the morti, right? Brahma, Vishnu, Shiva,
and they also have their functions. Um,
Brahma is is the Vishnu is an is is an
eternal immortal god. Is it? No, I think
only Shiva is an immortal god and Brahma
is the is the god that is associated
with this particular universe and so on.
So, our culture is complex. The
Abrahamic people want to oversimplify
everything. It's it's fine. They like to
have a very simple life. We are a
complicated people and we we have a
different worldview and a different way
of looking at the universe. And uh
strangely enough, our worldview when it
comes to looking at the universe seems
to be sometimes coming true. I mean the
complexities
that we have in Hindu Dharma for example
multiple universes and all that kind of
sometimes emerges from physics
and so on. Yeah. So, so I think to to
each their own. Okay. I believe in live
and let lively. You want to have your
morality, one God, one book, one for
morality. Please be happy with that. I
have nothing against that. But don't
come and judge me for having my own way
of doing things. I won't judge you. You
stay out of my business. That's it.
UMX says, "I have a Bengali professor in
a Christian college. He calls Churchill
a great man. How manipulated are current
Bengales, especially the old ones."
Look, I would not say that all Bengales
or all so and so people from so and so
state have a certain set of attributes.
If you have a professor who calls
Churchill a great man, it tells you that
in his childhood, in his youth, he was
exposed to certain ideas that he deeply
embied and he still regards as correct
and he is trying to pass on the same
values to the pupils he instructs.
Perhaps he thinks that he is right.
Perhaps he is not an anti-inational
person. Perhaps he truly believes that
the British did good things for India
and Churchill was a great man.
Uh are all Bengales like this? I would
be very reluctant to say that all
Bengales are like this. Right? There are
many non-Bengales who have similar
ideas. Right? U so I I would not pass a
blanket kind of judgment that all people
from a certain state are a certain kind
of people. I would not say that. uh but
I can say certainly about this
particular professor that that's the
kind of upbringing and and set of
influences that he might have had which
have contributed to him having this
specific worldview that Churchill was a
great man clearly he was a he was a
genocidal monster Churchill despite
whatever great things he may have done
or not for his country that's his
problem for us he was a monster
okay Shirinat hello uh my question is
that what does the west gain in by
regime change in a region where
countries eventually will come to India
because of sheer economic theft
geographical area that we can carry that
we carry. In the case of the Maldives
and Sri Lanka, as a famous saying goes,
the house always wins in a casino. In a
casino, the house always wins. But who
owns the casino? Maybe you can get rid
of the current master of the casino and
have in bring in a new new master of the
house. and that then the house will
always win but the house will now belong
to somebody else. Now
what does the west gain by regime change
in a region where countries will
eventually come to India because of the
sheer size of the economy and so on. But
what if you balconize India?
What if you convert India into a bunch
of small nations?
Tamil Nadu, Telangana, Andra,
Hana, Punjab
uh Kashmir
all of these let's say hypothetically
become separate nations then who will
come to India then these will all
operate independently maybe they will be
they will not cooperate among each other
so the entire potential that this
subcontinent had will evaporate and they
will all be at cross purposes with with
each other how about that for a scenario
so maybe the eventual objective of the
US is to achieve that
and by the time you achieve that you
don't then start working on the other
countries in the region, you first start
working with them,
right? So, so that's why you do regime
change in the easier countries first.
Pakistan, West Pakistan, so easy. Just
pay a few million dollars to the army
chief. Done. Immran Khan gone.
Bangladesh pay a few students to go and
do something and then have somebody else
hijack the whole protest and and get and
then pay the army chief to ou Shik
Hasina give her 45 minutes to leave the
country or else done then do something
in Nepal do something elsewhere then you
can completely ring fence India and then
you get to work on India
so it makes sense it's a very good
long-term strategy
right so the objective could be that the
house may win but what if the house is
broken into ser into 50 pieces then how
will a house win
so that could be the the game plan you
see and that's why India has to be
really really careful very careful
Jen says please talk about the Shakum
valley okay we haven't really opened the
map too much today so let us open the
map
Shakum valley so the Shakum valley is in
northern India here we are.
So you see the Pakistanis they currently
um occupy some parts of Jammu and
Kashmir which is called Pakistan
occupied Kashmir P and Gilgit Paltasan.
So there is this region in the northern
part okay which they have given to the
Chinese
as you can see China occupies Tibet and
and so-called sing over here and there
is this place where there is
a trijunction of India Pakistan Pakistan
Pakistani occupied territory and China
and then the Pakistanis gave up some of
this territory to the Chinese so if I
look Shak
Gum Ali. So it is this region here. As
you can see like I was zooming in this
region. As you can see there you can see
that some of the text is in the Chinese
script over here. Gasher the first. This
is now occupied by China because the
Chinese acquired this from the
Pakistanis. K2 is part of P. It's the
world's second highest mountain K2. and
Gasha Broom the first or one is
currently under Chinese occupation
because the Pakistanis gave it to China
in order to complicate the Kashmir issue
which was created by Shin Nehuji. So
that's why the Pakistanis gave the
seeded the gifted Shakgam Valley to the
Chinese to have China also involved in
the Kashmir conflict. Yeah. So that's
the deal.
Okay. Uh Arun Kumar says Greeks are
descendants of Vic people. Question
mark. Lol. Okay. Now once again we are
coming up with this uh haplo group
business and all that.
Um
tell me something
if you see Turkey today.
Okay let me first read it out. Okay let
me
uh let me read it out. Greeks are
descendants of Vic people. Question
mark. lol laughing out loud. Greek
specific haplo group E1B is found rare
in the whole Indian subcontinent and
modern Greeks show direct continuity
from the ancient Greeks and genetically
distant from Indians fake pride. Okay,
so Arun Kumar is saying that I am a
person with fake pride who is kanging.
What's the word kanging?
Uh so Greeks are genetically descended
from ancient
Greeks.
Okay, if you look at the people of
Turkey, H today's Turkey,
you do the testing, genetic testing,
will they show any affinity with the
Turk tribes of Central Asia,
will you see any genetic affinity with
them? You will see if you do a genetic
survey of Turks, Turkish people, Turkish
citizens today that you will see mostly
you will see mostly
Greek or Armenian ancestry.
You will see no Turk ancestry
whatsoever. And yet the culture and
language and religion is Turkish or
Turk. You go to Syria today. Hm. My
friend Arun Arun Kumar go to Syria
today. Do a genetic survey of the people
there. You will hardly find any trace of
Indian genetics there in Syria.
Syria had the Mitani Empire which was
ruled by Indoarians by Indians who spoke
Sanskrit late Vic Sanskrit. Where did
the genetics disappear? What happened?
It never happened. We have the
archaeological evidence that proves it.
So these genetic studies my dear friend
let me tell you I don't want to be
disrespectful to you even though you
have been loling at me. It's fine.
I would say first of all Arun please
learn a little bit of humility. Don't be
convinced always that you are always
right. You have understood a little bit
of genetics so you have understood
everything.
Understand that there are nuances and
complications in everything. The Mitani
Empire was ruled by Indians.
Where's the tra where are the traces of
Indian genetics there today?
And when it comes to Turkey, another
example, where's the traces of Turk
Turkish genetics there? Turk genetics,
hardly at all. But can you deny that the
people of Turkey are descended from
Turkish invaders?
They are. Was everybody converted? No,
there will be some traces but they they
are no longer visible. So that's how it
goes. Now the question is in case
hypothetically lol Greeks are descended
from Indians when did it happen? You are
saying that there is genetic continuity
between modern Greeks and ancient
Greeks. So the ancient Greeks you're
talking about which ancient Greeks? The
Greek city states that is about 500 BC.
Let's say 1,000 BC. You're talking about
2,000 BC. You're talking about 3,000 BC.
The battle of the 10 kings would have
happened closer to 10 6,000 BC during
the rigidic age
maybe let's say 5,000 BC maybe 4,000 BC
it's before the before the dawn of the
first Greeks
do you understand the time periods
I would say have an open mind and try
and pay attention to what I'm saying
don't have this attitude that I have
understood some genetics so I understand
everything it's not a healthy attitude
You will never learn things if you have
this approach and don't be so
disrespectful and so dismissive of your
own culture and history. That's all I
would say. All right, sir. All the best.
All the best. I wish you the best.
Priya Bharatwaj says, "Thanks for
motivation." Well, you're most welcome,
sir. Got a semiconductor job leading
role with a Taiwan based company. I'll
keep learning for India and help my
fellow sisters and brothers. All the
best, sir. All the best. I wish you the
best. Do very well for yourself, for
your family, in your life and when you
are in the position to help India.
We you are always welcome back. Do well,
sir. All all the best.
AKS says, "What's going to happen in
Venezuela? Is Maduro cooked?" Well, if
the Americans want him cooked, he's
cooked. There's not much he can do.
America, see, there's only a couple of
How many countries do we have in the
Americas that stand up to the US? We
have Venezuela for sure. Let's quickly
take do a survey of the world map and of
the of the map of Latin America and see.
So Mexico does whatever the US says. No
question. Biz of course they'll do what
the US says. Guatemala, El Salvador,
Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Panama,
everybody will say what the US does.
Colombia, they will never go against the
US. Ecuador, no, no chance. Peru, of
course, US. Bolivia, Paraguay, Uruguay,
Argentina, Brazil, Chile, everybody does
what the US tells. French Guyana,
Surinam, Guyana
and Trinidad and Tobago, the the
Caribbean countries, apart from Cuba and
Venezuela, nobody dares to stand up to
the US. Okay. So now, is Maduro cooked?
The US can cook him anytime they want.
So it's a I think it's going to be
entirely in the hands of the US. What do
they want to do? How do they want to
deal with this guy? Do they do a clean
regime change or a dirty regime change
and grab all the oil and then control
the oil that comes from Venezuela? They
can do it. It's not hard for them to do
it. All Trump has to do is give one
order and JD vanil says we'll do
whatever you want. Right. So yeah, it
could h it could happen. Maduro and and
if if the US attempts a regime change or
an invasion, a military or naval
invasion of of of Venezuela,
who's going to stop it?
Even even Saddam Hussein had some form
of military power, Venezuela doesn't
have that. So unfortunately, if the US
decides uh yeah, it's cooked. He's
cooked unfortunately.
Suas says, "If India's oil
fines size of Guyana comes true, are we
capable today of exploiting resources
fascin
if if we discover and you know if this
if we come across an oil find oil
discovery the size of what Guyana has
discovered uh are we capable of
immediately explo exploiting the
resources. We not right now. It'll take
a few years to to build the oil wells to
position them in the in in the right
places above the oil oil disc, the oil
reservoirs and then create the
infrastructure, the super tankers with
that will transport the oil from the oil
rigs to the mainland. Then we're going
to need more processing facilities. So
we may need more oil processing plants
and all that. So it will take maybe
maybe 5 years maybe even 10 years
hopefully not 10 years at least 3 four 5
years it will take to operationalize
this I mean how long does it take to
build an oil rig it'll take a year or
two perhaps I suppose if you have a very
professional company they can do it in a
few months depending on the situation
oil rigs can be built on the deepest of
discoveries so that is not an issue but
do Indian companies have the expertise
or will you have to bring in foreign
companies in which case there's another
complication so all of these things will
have to be looked too. So I think in
case the government of India is
confident that we're going to discover
oil a huge oil discovery then they
should start you know doing the homework
right now for for doing this. The moment
you discover start the process of
operationalizing that.
Okay. Valika says how do people of
prominence withstand relentless
criticism and the pressures of
visibility and what does it reveal about
human resilience? You see people of
prominence don't become people of
prominence unless they have the the
capacity to withstand this sort of
scrutiny and criticism. You simply won't
rise to a level of provenence if you are
thin skinned. If you are visible, if you
are a public figure of any kind, you're
going to going to face criticism of
various kinds and you've got to have the
ability to take the good with the bad,
right? Um,
so it only works if you have a thick
skin. And how do you develop a thick
skin? Either you're born with thick
skin, which means that the attitude that
I don't care what people say. I know
that I'm right. I'm on the right track
and I'll keep doing it. And I welcome
the criticism because it's it shows that
I'm I'm doing something right. So that's
the attitude some people have which is
innate in them. And some people are kind
of vulnerable and then they have to
mentally steal themselves over the years
that okay I it it affects me but I'll
still continue no matter what happens.
But ideally
a person of prominence should be
somebody who it doesn't affect at all
what people say. Uh so if it doesn't
affect you then then there's no pressure
of visibility. You don't care about the
criticism. Right? And what does it
reveal about human resilience? Human
resilience is is is is
you know it's boundless. You can dig
deep inside your psyche inside inside
inside yourself and you'll find a lot of
resilience but it's it's not an easy
process. And I I believe that almost
anyone is capable of tremendous
resilience but it's not the n the nicest
thing to be a to have to dig deep and
and find those reserves of resilience
because that means that you're going
through something painful. Yeah. So
that's how it is. Yeah. All right.
Shatsa, thank you very much sir or
ma'am. Thank you.
Priyak Chawhan says, "Please cover
Rajput's great resistance of 500 years."
Rajput resistance. So I'll tell you
what, the word Rajput did not exist in
700, 800 AD, even 10,000 AD. This term
came into
existence at a later time perhaps during
the Turk occupation era, the Muggal
Empire era of India. Perhaps that time.
Today we call those kingdoms and those
lineages Rajput lineages right. Um it is
said that there are 33 royal clans
ancient royal clans of India and those
are the Rajput clans. So they are
warriors, Khatrias and they are also
ancient rulers lineages and those are
now called Rajputs. I don't think they
called themselves the Rajbuts back in
the day. Now they are the ones who
resisted the initial Arabic and Turk
invasions for centuries. So Muhammadbin
Kasim, he invades the western part of
India. He attempts an invasion of the
western part of India in the 700s AD.
Right? So the the Arabs have overrun
Persia and ruined Persia and now they
are trying to come into Sind western
India and that's the first incursion
into India by the by the Arabs by
Muhammad bin Kasim and uh it was various
dynasties that exist in the region uh
who resisted that and then there were
multiple then then you started seeing
wave after wave of attempted Turkish
invasions Turk invasions into India. The
first part region of India to fall was
Gandhar. Right around 10,000 AD Gandhar
was gone. And there also you had
resistance. You had the Turk Shahis and
the Hindu Shahis who were descendants of
Shwa Hunas, white Huns who had become
Indianized and they defended India from
the Turk invasions. The Turk Shahis and
the Kabul Shahis.
Yeah. And eventually Gandhar fell and it
became Afghanistan.
And then so Afghanistan falls, Gandhar
falls around 1,000 AD. The Turkish
invasion start about 900 or whatever AD.
Yeah. And when Babar the first Muggal
king acquires a small piece of land in
in Delhi or northern India. Which year
was that? Let's look into it. Okay.
Let's look into it. Babar Muggal Empire.
Uh
Babber Babber.
Uh so when did he become the king of
small little kingdom
first battle etc.
He reigned from 1526.
So he became the king of the muggal
kingdom at the time in 1526. Babar okay
1526. When did Gori Gnavi whatever when
did um
when did Prasurat Johan fight the
barbarian from Gori Gaznavi? Whatever
that was at least 400 500 years before
this
Pritara Johan was a contemporary of Shri
Jingist Khan. So it was 1190s
that Pritara Johan fought the Turks
and before Prara Johan many other
Rajbuts many other kingdoms fought the
Turks. Even in 1526 when Babber takes a
small piece of Indian territory, it's
such small piece of Indian territory.
Most of India is still fighting the the
the Turks, it's only until Jalaludin
who be who who creates a vast empire
Akbar that's when the Rajputs start
getting defeated.
So for for what 7 800 years these Indian
kingdoms fought and repulsed the Turks
but not a word will be written about
this in the Indian textbooks because
they want Indians to fight each other.
Maratas and Rajput should keep fighting
each other. Gurjas and Rajput should
keep fighting each other. If somebody
has done something for the country that
should be erased so that you know all
all these problems of of which which
ensue is as as a consequence of
distorting history you know it's all
been artificially engineered for 800
years the people we now call the Rajputs
they fought the Turks
constantly and the sacrifices they made
were horrific immense sacrifices but uh
your history books won't won't teach you
that. So that's a little bit about the
Rajput defense of India for 8 centuries
plus more than eight more than eight
centuries. Sorab says with India's
population in the billions how could a
benevolent dictatorship should be
reinstated in place of a democracy and
how and will it be as effective today? I
shall not go into the mechanics and
dynamics of that sort of thing because I
have no idea.
I don't know. I don't know. create a one
party state two-party state like the US
that itself is a democ is a dictatorship
right the US is a two-party system and
both parties have the same foreign
policy and whatever else so that's
essentially a one one party dictatorship
essentially their domestic policies may
be different but externally they're the
same so replicate the American
experiment in India how about that yeah
there's an idea sir
Ryik yadaweni says shouldn't we have
more appropriate faces on Indian bills
like Bhagat Singh Net Gi and many other
freedom fighters other than Gandhi G.
Well, I
if I were in charge of of that, I would
have Chhatraatishi Maharaj. That's one.
I would Who else would I have? I would
We don't know what Shri Raj Raj Chola
Rajendra Chola looked like. We don't
know what Shri Kaleshki looked like. We
don't know what Chandra Gupta looked
like. We don't have those likenesses
anymore. But we have sculptures and
carvings. So, we could have those. These
are our great kings and emperors. Can we
think of any queens? We I'm sure we have
um that's what I would do.
I would certainly do that. So I I agree
with you. I agree with your sentiment
totally. I think it's time we move past
be past the the transfer of power that
happened in 1947. Right. Enough of that
now.
Okay. What next? We have Valika says,
"Your pursuit of knowledge shows depth
such depth across disciplines. How did
your childhood youth and experiences
shape who you are today?"
Um, look, first of all, I'll tell you
people don't really change. I today I
have gray hair, but I am the same person
that I was when I was 2 years old.
Nothing has really changed. I obviously
I've learned a lot since I was 2 years
old. I have had a lot of experiences and
lived, traveled and whatnot, but I'm
still the same person. So, a lot of it
depends on who you are when you born
with the kind of attributes you were
born with. Secondly, um yeah, I have
pursued a lot of disciplines. I have be
I was born with this curiosity. I wanted
to understand the world and I was
curious about very well all kinds of
things. Everything interested me. So I I
pursued I just pursued my curiosity. How
did my childhood youth experiences?
Well, one of the good things I had as a
child was access to a university
library. And I did not really get the
permission to use it a lot. But whenever
I did, I would well spend a lot of time
there. And back in the day when I was a
kid, little kid, there was no internet.
The only place you could where you could
gain any knowledge was the library
because your school textbooks were
garbage. There was nothing of value in
that. So I I was always gravitating. I
was always drawn towards the library.
And if I was allowed to go to the
library, I would just run loose. I I
would be set loose on the place and I
would read everything possible. I used
to read about crystals. I used to read
about industrial light and magic that's
Hollywood. I used to read about uh
Russia. I used to read about geography,
science, every sort of thing you could
imagine. I used to read biology. I read
uh Will Duran's history of civilization
at the age of what 9 10 whatever uh and
so on. So I was very curious. I was kind
of a nerd. The only saving grace was
that I was well tall boy and good at
sports. So not entirely a nerd and so
on. So I I was I I was very curious. I
was drawn towards knowledge and I I
could read all day and that's u yeah
that's some of the things that have
shaped me and of course I I was the
strongest the strongest attraction was
was towards physics
and uh so that that was yeah that's kind
of shaped who I am but I was always
curious about history and eventually I
realized at some point in my life that
what the hell I because I know history I
now understand geopolitics. I understand
what's happening. The same things have
been happening forever. So eventually,
yeah, I realize that. Yeah.
All right. Pratik Vora says, "Part of
Hutan Prefecture was
part of Hutan Prefecture
was in BR British India. Why we lost?"
Well, you see you we had
we had a visionary magnificent leader as
prime minister and his thinking was a
multiverse ahead of us and we can't
really think understand we can't even
begin to understand the vision he he had
for our country and he took us in the
directions that you know led to his
vision and that's why we are in the
shape and form that we are today his
name was the great magnificent of Shri
Jawal Nehuji
and uh why did we lose whatever? Well, I
suppose we will have to ask Shri Nuji.
Why did we lose all of this? Really,
why?
Dinor Singh says 1666 London fire. Ah,
remodeling of London. You mean a French
man claimed to starting the fire, but
there was proven physically not possible
to be started. Like he said, he was
executed. Well, I'm not aware of this,
but I am aware of misu the pipes. What?
What was his name? Uh, Samuel Pepis
once. Peep. Peep. What was his name?
Give me a second. Let me let me let me
let me Google this. Pipus diary. P YS. P
YS diary.
The diary of Samuel Peepus.
So, he does mention the London fire,
doesn't he? In this, the great plague of
London s second end of the Dutch war.
the great fire of London 1666 which is
years after the Norman conquest and he
also talks about what an execution
execution of Charles the first yeah this
guy was he was a he was a blogger or a
vlogger of the time he he was a
politician and so on so the London fire
that you're talking about a French man
claimed to starting the fire was okay he
was executed well I was not aware of
this this particular aspect of the fire.
But the fire of London was a great
opportunity to completely remodel the
city because so much of the city was
destroyed in the fire. They could create
a new modern
London because so much of the city had
been cleared by the fire and that laid
the foundation of the London that we
have today that that they have today,
right? Um, and this was the age when
British science and architecture and all
of that was taking off because of the
golden uh Elizabethan era.
Elizabeth. Yeah. The daughter of uh of
Henry VIII. Uh, and and she was well a
very uh liberal person who tolerated
science who did not execute people for
believing that science should be a thing
and all. And that's why England kind of
took off during the time. uh
scientifically and technologically and
you had many great architects and other
people who who became prominent around
this time and after the fire of London
they redesigned the city and
reconstructed the city in a completely
modern way. So it was kind of a boon
according to some people for London that
this fire happened and all the old the
old city the old congested horrible city
was was
destroyed and a new London was built.
James says we gave you fine universities
like Xavier but you you ungrateful
Hindus still hate us. Well, you see,
Javier, Javier, it's not Xavier, it's
Javier. Javier was a missionary,
he was a Spanish missionary who lived in
India during a Portuguese occupation of
India. And his greatest achievement is
to bring the Spanish Inquisition to
India.
Because according to Francis Xavier,
this individual, Hindus who had been
converted by force to Christianity were
not practicing Christianity rigorously
enough. You see, they were reverting to
their barbarous hidden polytheistic
idolatrous ways in secret.
And so Francis Xavier said, "Bring the
Spanish Inquisition to India. Let these
cursed Hindus taste
what an oto is. Ottoaf, fire by fire. So
Francis Xavier brought the Spanish
Inquisition to India and he had lots and
why why am I talking about this? Don't
tell showed you know the cardinal rule
in writing. I'm I'm a writer now, right?
I'm I'm a writer. I'm an author. The
cardinal rule in writing is to don't
tell show. So let me show you what this
individual was able to manifest in
India. Let me show you what uh Francis
Xavier.
So let's look at this. You may not have
heard of this term oto
but not just oto. Let's say oto gua.
Now see Goa Inquisition.
Check this out. Otto Dafe Goa procession
clergy. A whole bunch. This is another
one. Oto in Goa.
Uh let's zoom into this. Let me open
this image. Let me let me ambigon.
Let me ambigon this image. Bigify it.
Let's bigify this image.
Okay. Let's let's zoom in. What you will
see is a bunch of
priests and churchmen
uh dancing around a fire and celebrating
and you will see that in the fire there
are Hindus who are burning and you will
see ships at sea the Portuguese ships.
So Francis Xavier brought this thing
into India, the Spanish Inquisition. The
objective was to root out Hinduism root
and stem. Root out Hinduism root and
stem because the Hindus they were
secreting secretly practicing Hinduism
in private and Francis Xavier sniffed
that out. So he brought in the barbaric
port the barbaric Spanish inquisition in
India and they did all kinds of horrific
atrocities to Indians burning Indians
alive because they were practicing
Hinduism chopping people's hands off and
and all kinds of barbarities. The
Spanish were renowned for this. I mean
just look at what they did did in the
Americas. You can see some of my older
videos for that.
So Javier, Francis Kavier, he brought
this barbarity to India. Um and yeah you
have some colleges and today every
school college etc is named after
Francis Kavier because of the
object mental colonization that Indians
labor under today. So yeah that's so
James once once again James I I I
thank you for bringing out these very
fine topics for me to discuss. I
appreciate this is an honest
appreciation. Thank you so much James.
Appreciate it.
Anonymous says followup other than
critical infrastructure what
infrastructure do we need like
observatory okay okay okay that's what
we're talking about maybe labs let's
suppose we are a hyper power then that
then what infra must we have other than
other critical infra such as okay so
let's say we are an established power we
have all the basic stuff done roads
railways train stations airports ports
blah blah blah blah blah All of that is
the basic stuff. We're done with that.
Then we need worldclass universities,
world-class colleges. Every university
must be a research institution, not just
godamn professors boring the hell out of
you by brooding monotonously from a
book. Read open chapter page number 28.
Now let us read together. We don't want
this professors. Put them out to
pasture. We need real professors. We
need real teachers. Teachers who
actually do research. We need every
university to be a research institution.
We need to have research institutes for
all disciplines. Whether it's chemistry,
whether it's materials technology,
material science, whether it is quantum
computing, whether it's AI, whether it
is whatever, whether it is astronomy,
astrophysics, cosmology, whether it is
nuclear physics, whether it is particle
physics, high energy physics, whether it
is technological
pursuits like for example
fusion reactions, Okamax, we need to
have institutions not just one in each
country but one in each state.
One in each state.
So yeah, all of this needs to happen.
All the cutting edge deep research that
needs to happen. We need to have
institutions for that. Beyond that, we
need to have a world yoga standards
institute which will decide what is
yoga, what is not yoga. We can certify
that if someone is doing goat yoga or
yoga that means to end it is not yoga.
We don't consider to be yoga and so on.
We need to have all the all of these
institutions. We need to become a nation
of institutions that are rooted in based
in our country in our culture and we
need to go all in on science and
technology.
It is super important we do that. You
cannot rem afford to remain backward in
science and technology. We were the most
advanced nation in science and
technology in the past before the
foreign occupations of India. We need to
go back to that status.
We keep on moaning about vishua guru
vishwa guru. We are not even visual
student right now. If you want to be
visual guru, you need to have the
institutions like we used to have all
the vishua vidyal, the universities. So
all of that needs to happen, right? All
right. Good question actually. Very
good. Thank you. Godliness says today
it's asking anything. So Mr. Cha, how do
you define love? How strongly do you
believe in romance? Which essential
human attributes are dying in the 21st
century? And what emotions mean to you?
How do I define love?
Well, that's a question that I did not
expect. You're putting me on the spot.
How strongly do you believe in romance?
Romance, love, it's an important
integral part of life. You need to have
that. Every person needs to experience
this. I mean, if you don't experience
this, what are you doing with your with
your life? You can have your
professional pursuits and all, but your
your personal life that also needs to be
complete. So, how do I define love? I
don't know. I don't know how to define
love. I'm not a poet. But it's an
integral part of life and you need you
need to have that. Love is not just
physical attraction or sexual
attraction. Obviously, there's a
component in that al of of that also in
that. But beyond that, it's about it's
about uh it's about compatibility. It's
about loyalty, right? That's very
important. Uh it's not love if if if it
lasts 3 months or 6 months and then you
move on somewhere else, then you move on
somewhere else. Like butterfly going
from flower to flower, that's not love.
That's animal-like behavior. I I think I
think the integral component in love is
honest is not it's it's it's loyalty
and loyalty is a test of your own
character. So I think there is that how
strongly do I believe in romance? Yeah,
it's it should be there everybody. There
should be romance in everyone's life.
It's very important otherwise otherwise
what's the point of life? you need to
experience all of these highs and all
all the tumult of emotions that comes
with all of this. Um, what do emotions
mean to me? Emotions? Well, everybody
has emotions. I also have emotions. I
have very strong emotions, but I'm not
ruled by my emotions. So, emotions are a
barometer.
For me, well, I have a very scientific
way of looking at things. Emotions tell
me the state of being right now. Am I
how am I feeling? How am I feeling? Am I
feeling good? Am I feeling bad? If I
have an emotional reaction, why is it
so? What does it mean? What caused it?
And why has this emotion come? That sort
of thing. So I I'm kind of analytical
about this. But I yeah, I'm also prone
to emotions, but I'm not ruled by at
least I I strive not to be ruled by my
emotions. Because people who are ruled
by their emotions and who get carried
away by emotions, they can be very
easily manipulated.
Very easy to manipulate. If you
understand that a person is emotion
emotional and their emotions get the
better of them that those people are the
easiest to manipulate
but if you can control your emotions and
you can carry on despite whatever
emotions may be happening inside then
people can't manipulate you. So yeah
that that's one way of seeing emotions
right.
Okay. Prashant says um
history teaches border nations end up in
conflicts.
Well, every nation has b every nation
has borders doesn't mean that every
nations have conflicts. No. Uh it's not
necessarily that way.
Um what does history actually teach? It
says when that when two large powers
or equally powerful nations have a
shared border, they can't be friends. It
is best to be a powerful nation
surrounded by smaller nations who will
naturally be dependent on you or or or
subservient to you. That's the Chanakin
worldview, right? So if you have if you
are a major border, if you're a large
nation and you have let's say 12 small
border nations at your border, there's
no need for conflict ever. But if you
are a large nation and if you have
another large equally large nation at
your border, conflict is more or less
inevitable in some shape or form. That's
what history teaches us. Aravsha, thank
you very much. Welcome to new
membership. I never ever ask anybody to
be a member, but some of you still do
it. So, thank you so much. I really
appreciate that. Thank you.
Chinmai says, I greatly admireful. Thank
you so much, sir. Thank you. My question
is, why do North and South Indians
differ so much in appearance and
complexion despite a shared culture? See
in the past
today
today if I feel say let's say tomorrow
morning before I go to sleep let's say I
feel like let me go to Chennai and shop
for something h I can tomorrow morning
take a flight to Chennai and go there
honestly I can go tomorrow morning if I
want to I I'll not get the best seat in
the aircraft but I'll get a seat
somewhere in some aircraft tomorrow
morning I can be on a plane to Chennai
or I can go to Lelay tomorrow I'm sure I
can go to tomorrow I can go anywhere in
the country or anywhere in the world
essentially if I have visa for that
country so today you can travel anywhere
so we look at the world from that
perspective like the world is a very
small place
100 years ago if you were living in
let's say northern India and you wanted
to visit Thirupati Balaji or you wanted
to visit uh um
Mahabalesh
what whatever let's say you wanted to
visit Ram Romeshwaram
it would take you months of travel to go
there.
So people did not travel that much. Only
scholars and and important people would
travel across the subcontinent. Most
people stayed put where they were. They
would have heard of this place and that
place and all but most people rarely
ever traveled very far unless you were
an important government official or
something. So for example, Ashoke,
Emperor Ashoke when he was a young man
when he was a teenager, he was born
probably in Partutra somewhere in in
present day in Mad right but he was the
governor of Gandhar. His his father said
go and and govern Gandhar which is like
2,000 km away. So if you were an
important person you traveled but back
in the day ordinary people did not
travel the state put and that's why you
had
different populations in different parts
of the country which which evolved
differently
and our our
ethnic mix is about 70 80,000 years old
and at that time all these thousands of
tens of thousands of years we did not
mass transportation and that's why
people who lived in the southern part of
India where there's much higher exposure
to the sun and much higher temperatures
they eventually naturally evolved to
grow darker skin and people who lived in
the northern part of northern parts of
India because of somewhat less exposure
to the sun we developed slightly less
dark skin and that's why there's a
difference in in appearance and all that
but today I think it the situation is
that in a few generations there'll be no
difference between north and North
India.
So there we have it. Yeah.
Ryik Yiddangi says, "I in love with
Indian music. I wonder why new classical
and folk rarely emerge and lyrics have
declined. Will this rich heritage fade
despite fusion efforts? It looks like it
because our musicians don't care about
our culture. You I mean look, I'll not
take anyone's names, but what kind of
music emerges from Bollywood? It doesn't
even sound like Indian music.
We have the world's richest, oldest
musical tradition, Raas.
Yesterday I was recommending a book. I
have it here. Give me a second.
See this book is called the Raas of
Northern Indian music. It's by Ana Dany,
French man. No Indian has bothered to
write a book like this. The Raa system
is the most
it's it's the most refined system of
music in the world. It's way way ahead
of anything the west has produced in in
in the west you have scales.
Scales what is what is the scale in
music? It's
CD E F GC.
These are that's a scale. In Indian and
Western music we have seven notes. In
Chinese music, you have five notes. It's
a pentatonic scale. We have a heptatonic
scale. So, we have seven notes that we
can play around with. And in western
music, you have these different uh
scales that they use. We have the Dorian
scale, you have the Lucian scale, you
have the mixelyian scale and so on so
forth. All these different scales of
music that you can play on the guitar.
Uh the pentatonic scale that they use,
the minor pentatonic scale and so on. Um
so, they have scales
in the west in western music. In Indian
music, we have scale. We we have ragas.
A raga is not merely a scale. A ra a raa
is
what's a raga? A raga has an ascending
scale and a descending scale. Ascending
scale means when you go to higher
frequencies from low s to higher sa. And
a descending scale is when you go
downwards in frequency which is from
higher sa to lower sa. So you may have a
certain set of nodes for the ascending
scale and you may have a different set
of notes for the descending scale. And
then you have a sonent note and a
consonant note which is the note that
gets the most highest emphasis and the
second highest emphasis. Then you have
drone notes typically two or three drone
notes for each raa. And when you have
all of these rules together it produces
incredible musical effects. Each raa has
its own personality with its own
character. It's like two different
people. The moment you change the raga
you feel a whole different atmosphere
nuance. Yeah. And ragas have have well
they they are either seasonal or they
are temporal. So you have you have
seasonal ragas like raga mega malhar
which is a monsoon raga. We have we have
temporal ragas like early morning ragas
like raga vibas rahav
rahir behav. You have night ragas like
raga malouse which was earlier called
raga malavoshik. You have afternoon
ragas. You have certain ragas evoke
beautiful emotions, happy emotions.
Raadi is there. Yes. Raavasant is a
beautiful raga. That's that's a seasonal
raga again. And there are some ragas
that are very like they they evoke
sensations of pain and and and sadness.
For example, Ra Jayat is one. Ra Marwa
is there and so on. So these the Indian
system of music is the most evolved
system of music humankind has ever
created and this is a book that speaks
about that it has got you know musical
scales the raas and various in in in
musical notation staff notation and so
on and today we are just completely
ignoring this incredible aspect of our
heritage and just blindly copying
degraded music. It's it's so painful to
see that. So I'm glad Ry that you have
mentioned this and I hope something
otherwise I'll have to do that. I'll
have to go back to my guitar and do
something about it. Yeah, it's been a
while since I've touched the guitar.
I've got like three three guitars
hanging outside
waiting for me to get back to them.
Parag Johan says your response to Nlesh
Oak theory of dating back ma. Do I have
to respond to everything sir? I have no
response sir. I I haven't studied it. I
don't have the time to study everything.
There's only I'm just one person. I I
only have 24 hours in a day and uh so I
I I don't have I I have so many
interests. I want to read everything. I
want to study everything. But I have to
pick and choose. So I haven't studied
Shri Dlesh Oak G's work. So I can't
really comment about it. All right, sir.
Okay.
Okay. AI productivity magnet says please
talk about second world war differences
between Shbashundra Bose and Neu Gandhi.
What would have happened if India fought
alongside Germany and not the allies?
So Shbashundra Bose
was of the opinion that when you have a
foreign occupier who occupying your
country, it is your duty to get rid of
get rid of the occupier
through any means necessary.
It is okay to kill them all if required
because they don't belong in your
country. They do not come into your
country by by through legal means by
asking for visas. They have come and
occupied your country. They're
engineering famines in your country.
They're killing millions of your people.
They are plundering the nation's
resources.
So why should I deal with them by by by
putting handcuffs on my arms on on my
wrists? Why don't I just use every means
at my disposal including the most
violent means if if necessary? Why not
kill them all? So that was what
Subashidra Bos said. I don't believe in
this god damned ainsa
which is nothing but
um a euphemism for cowardice
and a euphemism for collaboration with
the enemy. So he said that if I want to
defeat the British and they occupy every
inch of my country, I'll go outside of
my country and I will seek an alliance
with their enemies who seek to destroy
them and that's how I will liberate my
country. And Suband was not aware of any
any thing that the Germans were doing
wherever. Yeah. Um or the Awitz or
whatever. He was not aware of any of
that. He said that these are my enemies,
the British. They are my people's
enemies. They're my civilization's
enemies. So I will align or ally with
their enemies.
Um and that's why he did what he did and
that's why the the Americans and British
and the whole world still today even
today they portray Subbashandra Bose as
as um as someone who allied himself with
the axis with the Nazis
and that's why Subashandra Bose had to
stay hidden
until 1985 when he died. Uh what would
have happened if India fought alongside
Germany not allies? How could it happen
when we were occupied by the allies?
Please
logically think about it. If we are
under allied occupation,
how do we fight with the with the axis
with Germany? How how is it practically
possible? Please explain
how it's not possible.
Sor Pande says, "Do you still enjoy
coding? Is it and is it worth learning
in today's AIdriven world? I'm starting
my software career. Any advice for
someone like me? Coding can be fun if
you're if you're coding something fun.
Uh I haven't done coding in ages now.
I'm not sure how good my skills are. I'm
sure it's they are very rusty. It's it's
like playing guitar. You may be a good
guitar player, but if you put the guitar
away for 6 months and you pick you know
pick it pick it up again, you'll find
that you've gone rusty. your fingers no
longer move the way they used to move.
But if you don't do don't play the
guitar for 10 years. Well, you go back
to almost beginner status. You may learn
again very fast compared to a beginner.
But when you pick the guitar up again
after 10 years, you're going to be super
rusty. You're going to be almost like a
beginner. And a lot of the concepts you
may have forgotten them. You may have to
revisit them. Similarly with coding. So
um I haven't done coding in quite a
while like more than a decade for sure.
Is it worth learning in today's AIdriven
world? I think you should still learn
it. I don't think AI can replace
everything. Yeah, AI is not magic,
right? Uh AI will be able to automate a
lot of the stuff. But if you are a coder
or a programmer of a certain level, then
you can have AI employees work for you.
But you will have to prepare the
designs,
the design documents, the requirement
documents, and you you'll have to
supervise the AI at every step to ensure
it's implementing your instructions
properly. And if you understand the code
then you will be able to catch bugs
because I believe AI throws up bugs and
sometimes AI is not able to solve
problems. So I think it is still
worthwhile to to learn coding but to be
able to harness the power of AI you'll
have to learn coding at to a higher
level where you can actually um act as a
project manager without any employees
only AI employees. So you'll have to
ascend to that level in in coding. But
yeah, coding is fun. Coding is fun and
uh it gives you immense power. And if
you really know coding well, then then I
suppose if you are in that position
where you really know coding well, then
the real power of of AI becomes
available to you. You really have to be
a master at the craft to be able to
genuinely leverage AI in that craft. If
you are a complete novice, then you
don't know what to tell AI. you don't
even know how to how to explain what you
are trying to do. So you have to learn
it. So I would say yeah it's still
worthwhile learning coding.
Okay.
Kishan Borer says did Pakistan get their
independence in 1947 or they got
dominion status like us? When did the
Pakistan get their independence keeping
Vasalhud aside? So Pakistan got dominion
status on the 14th of August 1947
and India got dominion status on the
15th of August 1947. One day later why
one day later? Because if India had been
given dominant status before Pakistan
then but then then technically Pakistan
would still be part of India and then
India can prevent Pakistan from getting
a separate dominion status. So that's
why they gave Pakistan dominion status
first on the 15th on the 14th of August
and uh India on the 15th of August. So,
so what we call independence day is
actually dominion status day. Fact check
it if you want. It is not independence
day. It's dominion status day. Uh Shri
Neuji was still writing letters to the
to the king of England. Uh referring to
him as his king. Yeah. Allegedly. Uh
when did Pakistan get its independence?
I don't really know. After 47, what
happened? When did they become so
Pakistan once they got dominion status?
They had Muhammad Ali Jina as that
governor general or whatever it was. We
had Mount Batton. We had a foreigner.
They had an they had an Indian. I mean
he was now Pakistani but whatever.
Right. Until 1947 Jana was also Indian,
wasn't he? So they got a native man to
be their governor general.
But we had Mount Batton because white
man better, right? White man better. Yes
sir. Always full support. So that sort
of thing. So I'm not sure when Pakistan
got their actual independence. when they
when the when did they transition from
being a dominion to an actual whatever
they became I'm not sure I've not looked
into it but I'm sure it can be searched
up very quickly okay Jay well thank you
so much Jay appreciate it sir
um Kishin Borer says how are wormholes
created if you are bending the fabric of
space wouldn't it disperse
other objects or am I visualizing the
fabric to be two-dimensional
What is the concept of bending the
fabric to create a shortcut?
Okay, so all these uh analogies we are
given. Let's say you take a sheet of
paper and you poke a hole through it and
then you bend it like this and you
create a shortcut. That's only for
visualizing. That's not how it actually
works. See, why do we use this analogy?
Why do we use the analogy? Let me
explain. I mean, I have written about
this. Maybe I'll find where is it?
uh which book was it? Okay, in case so
you have this question I think I've
closed that but in case you want to read
in detail I'll tell you where you can
find it. I'll tell you exactly where you
can find it.
I have published this new book called
dark stars to black holes. There is the
first book in my series of the black
hole chronicles in which I speak I I
write about these things and I write
about it in a in a way that the public
will understand. People will understand.
It's not full of equations. It's
explaining black holes the way you want
to actually understand black holes. And
wormholes will also will also come into
that. See black holes are the world's
universe's most extreme objects.
And it's it's these are fascinating
objects but you don't get to understand
what these are because it's the concepts
are so complicated. So my what I'm doing
is I am making the concepts accessible
to everybody.
When I'm writing this I'm thinking will
my 12year-old self be able to understand
this? That's how I'm writing it. So the
answer to your question is in the second
book that I've written. So I'm writing
each chapter as a separate volume. I'm
putting it on Amazon Kindle. The links
are in the description in case you want
to read it and the answers will come in
the series. But uh okay. So so that is
that's about the books. Now let me
answer your question. So so that
visualization that we had that we have
of that trampoline like rubber sheet and
you put a bowling ball on that and it
creates a depression and then you put a
marble around it. It spins around and
that's how gravity is explained. That is
a two-dimensional interpretation which
is very valuable to kind of
conceptualize things, visualize what is
unvisisualizable.
But that curvature that has been created
of the sheet, we are using gravity for
it. So you using gravity to to visualize
gravity which is a circular reasoning.
Okay.
The real bending of the fabric is not
it's not a bending of the fabric of
space. It's a bending of the fabric of
spacetime.
Spacetime
not just space even time is being
distorted. Time is being bent. Do you
know why you have gravity on the earth?
It's not of because of the bending of
space. It is because of the bending of
time. Do you know that your head ages
faster than your feet?
Do you know that the GPS satellites if
we did not incorporate time dilation and
relativistic effects they would give you
an error of 11 km every day and every
day it will get get 11 11 km larger. So
the point is it's the the the the
visualization of the paper and the
rubber sheet that's that's not entirely
accurate. So how are wormholes created?
Wormholes are solutions. It's one
particular set of solutions of
Einstein's field equations.
Einstein field equations. Einstein came
discovered or developed these equations
after eight years of incredible mental
torture because he was not a
mathematician and he had to do all this
advanced mathematics which even today
tortures students you know if you do
tensor tensure algebra and all that and
tensor calculus. So the field equations
that he came up with in the year 1915 he
thought it will take decades to solve
them but in 8 weeks a dying man was able
to solve them on the battlefield in the
first world war. His name was Carl
Schwath Stilled and eventually there
were more solutions of the equations
that came up and one of these equa
solutions of the equations is the
wormhole solution. It's called the
Einstein Rosen bridge. So one of the
analogies is that you can poke a hole
through a paper and that's a that's a
shortcut through through space but it's
actually a hole in space and time. So if
we are warping the fabric of spacetime
it will not disgorge other orbit or
other objects. That's not what happens.
Spacetime is the stage on which the
universe exists. We are inside spaceime.
Yeah. So you are kind of visualizing the
fabric to be 2D. you have that analogy
in your mind and I don't blame you for
that because everybody grows up seeing
that. So that's what you have in your
mind but that's not exactly how it is.
What's the concept of bending the fabric
to create a shortcut? That's you can
only explain this through equations but
I'm attempting to explain it um in my in
in the books in the in the in the
volumes. The concept is that
space time. Okay. So if you look at the
Einstein field equations it has two
sides left hand side and right hand
side. The left hand side it tells you
about the warping or bending of spaceime
through the richy tensor richy scaler
all of that. Yeah. On the right hand
side you have a complete tally a
complete census of all the mass and
energy. And if you take the whole
equation it says that matter and energy
tell spacetime how to bend and the
bending of spacetime tells matter and
energy how to move and it's a dance
constant dance. So if I have I'll tell
you something.
So I have a I have a cup of coffee here,
right? Super hot coffee.
Every atom in this cup of coffee is
right now deciding the curvature of
spaceime in the Andromeda galaxy.
That's what Einstein's field equations
tell you. So um that's the concept of
bending the the fabric of space and
time. And one of the solutions is a
shortcut solutions which kind of Yeah.
So that's how it is. But u it's it's not
a hole in space and time. It's just a
different kind of solution. And
wormholes don't stay open. They want to
close shut immediately.
Right? You don't have a stable solutions
of wormholes. They they close shut. They
become two black holes quickly. So if
you want to keep a wormhole open, you
have to introduce something very strange
inside which is either some kind of
exotic matter like negative mass or
negative energy or something even more
exotic like a topological defect like
perhaps a cosmic string or something. So
anyway, that's about it. If you're if
you're curious interested about this,
please check out my books. That's
exactly the kind of answers I'm giving
in in my books. Anyhow, thank you. Great
question. Finally, somebody's asked
something about black holes and and
physics. Thank you. Next question.
Uh anonymous says, "How do you have so
much such memory? How can I develop it?"
One second.
I to be
to be very honest, I don't think I've
I've got a great memory. I forget all
kinds of stuff. Um I just remember
whatever interests me. Everything else I
forget. I forget. Look, if you ask me
what was the Gandhi Irwin pact, somebody
asked me a couple of hours ago, what was
the Gandhi Urban Pact? I had no memory
of what was the details of the pact or
which year it happened. So, I forget
stuff. Things that I don't find
interesting, I forget them. But things
that I am interested in, I can speak
about them for hours because I have I
can recall them the information. Uh how
do you develop it? Just follow your
curiosity. Whatever you find like look I
show you two movies. One movie you find
boring, after a month you will remember
nothing. Another movie you'll find
extremely interesting. You will remember
after even after 20 years all the
details. That's the secret. Okay.
Okay.
Black star says I left my job
a 24
star startup tried three four ideas
didn't work out. Burned all my cash. Now
I'm 25 with 30 days cash left. Trying my
last idea with no intention to do job.
Now I have low confidence and no hope.
Any advice?
My advice to you is be super practical.
Be super practical.
Don't put all your eggs like they say in
the cliche in in the same basket. If you
want to burn cash, don't burn all your
cash. Always keep a backup. Let's say
you got okay hypothetically 1 cr rupees
in your in your kitty. Don't burn the
whole 1 cr rupees.
At least keep 30% aside. You want to
burn, burn 70%, minimum 30%, 40% keep
aside. Don't touch that. Okay? But
anyway, since you've done it, it's okay.
It happens. You're still what? How old
you? You're 25 years old. You're still a
young person. You have a long way ahead
of you. If if something like this
happens, no big deal. No big deal. Um
next time once you have some cash I
would say keep
keep a certain percentage aside. It is
not to be touched under any
circumstances. That's how you do risk
management. So if you want to be play
risky games risk 60%, don't risk the
remaining 40%. That's what you would do
right now. I would say you don't have
any intention to to do a job again. You
have low confidence, no hope. Any
advice? I would say be super practical.
Don't say I will never do a job again.
If you are in a situation where you are
running out of cash, do a job for a
while. What's the big deal? I did a job
for 10 years. Did I enjoy it? Not one
day. But I still learned things from it.
So if required, do a job. Tell yourself
it's temporary. I'll do it for a few
months or few weeks. Oh, whatever few
year or two until I have some cash
again. Then
incorporate the learnings
from the previous experiment and try
again. But don't burn everything this
time. And lastly, never stop believing
in yourself. When you fail,
people will make fun of you. People will
taunt you. People will say you're a
failure. Ignore them because you will
never succeed unless you learn how to
fail multiple times.
Look at the most successful people in
the world and see how many times they
have failed and how much ridicule they
faced at the time. So don't let that
affect you. Okay. All the best sir. Do
well and uh in the future I look forward
to seeing
a different aspect of black star. All
the best sir. Don't give up. Don't stop
believing in yourself. All the best.
Anonymous says how to study a topic for
example Rockefellers. What's the steps
you go through to gain knowledge about a
topic like internet book etc. How do you
sort out which info is correct and which
info is propaganda? How do you uh study
a topic? You just start studying it. You
don't have to study it in a systematic
manner. Initially just dive into it from
whichever angle you want. Be extremely
in discipline in your in your research.
Initially
spend a certain amount of time reading
as much as possible looking into all
sources of information wherever you find
them whatever randomly. Then after some
time the patterns start clicking in your
mind and then you know where where the
gaps of knowledge are and what you need
to look into and then you pursue that
and you do that in a more systematic
manner. After some time when you start
understanding the patterns and the gaps
of knowledge and all how do you make out
which is in which info is correct which
is propaganda. Well there are different
ways of doing it. First of all, if the
information is clearly just opinions
without any solid evidence that backs it
up, it's clearly it could still be true,
but it is less valuable information.
Let's say you have blog post somewhere
in which somebody says blah blah blah
blah blah, but they don't give any
evidence or proof to to back up their
blah blah. See, people say that Chowa,
you speak for two hours on the on the on
the internet on YouTube and you never
get give any sources by I'm speaking
here. How will I pull out sources while
I'm speaking? But when I write I give
you all the sources. Check out my books
on physics. I have published two
volumes. See how many sources I've given
there. So my point is when somebody
gives information in writing there has
to be sources. And if the sources are
not present, it is more likely to be
propaganda. Okay. Um and I I go through
books. I go through internet. Mainly
it's online these days. You can get
almost anything online especially
research papers and whatnot. Then you
need to know how to look for things.
That's that's how I do it. Yeah. And
after many many years, you have a sixth
sense for which info is right, which is
wrong, and where the real thing lies.
It's it's it's a sense you to develop
through a lot of research.
Okay.
Kishan says, "Think tanks of pus did not
consider the scenario where India would
not accept tariffs." Um or why or or
they want other countries to go against
for future. They will have no reason to
take any measure. Drink water please.
I'll drink some coffee. Black coffee.
M black coffee. Tasty. Bitter.
So what was the deal? What happened? Did
they not consider this? I think they
were surprised. They were taken
by surprise. They were caught unawares.
They were stumped by a mile
scratching their head in perplexity.
What on earth happened? They never
expected that India will stand firm.
They did not expect that uh Prime
Minister Modi will will not cave in.
They're very surprised. Yeah, it looks
like they did not anticipate a scenario
where the government of India would
would not accept their demands, their
maximalist positions and all that. Um
and what else they want other countries
to go against for future they will have
no reason to take any measure. See most
countries have given into them. I think
only India stood up. India, China,
Russia are standing up to the US. So now
they're clubbing all three together kind
of. Uh so yeah I think they were caught
unaware. They did not anticipate that
this kind of thing could happen.
Vom what a nice name. Vom Pande a
request. Don't use term south India
language from use language from south.
Uh thank you for the recommendations
sir. Thank you.
Tarun says what is the dynamics in
between cookies and other indigenous
tribes in the hills of Manipur as both
follow Christism? What is the role of
misoram in Manipur? Look in Manipur.
Manipur you have to understand the
fundamentals. Okay since we are doing a
long discussion today let's let's do a
slightly deepish dive in this.
You want to understand the dynamics of
what's happening right now. Right? Um
so first of all let us understand what
is manipur. We have to understand the
fundamentals and basics right before we
discuss the situation. What is Manipur?
Okay. What do we know about Manipur from
far away? We know there is something
called Manipuri language. Yeah. We know
there is something called Manipuri
dance. Yeah. Beyond that we don't know
much. If we do a little bit of research
you will see that Manipur has a list of
kings, history of kings that goes back
more than 2,000 years. Okay. three three
facts we have a Manipuri language a very
famous dance form of India Manipuri
dance and third Manipuri kings that go
back 2,000 years now let us ask
ourselves a simple question
this Manipuri language that exists it's
also more than 2,000 years old h which
ethnic group of Manipur speaks the
Manipuri language in Manipur today you
have three ethnic groups they are called
three ethnic groups one is the mates one
is the naga us. Third is the cookies.
Three ethnic groups. So this language
which is more than 2,000 years old,
Manipuri language, which ethnic group
speaks it? Is it the manip is it the
matees? Is it the nagas or is the is it
the cookies?
Answer is matees. So the matees speak
the manipuri language which is more than
2,000 years old. Not the nagas, not the
cookies. Second, manipuri classical
dance. One of India's great dance forms,
world famous.
Which ethnic group is the originator? Is
it the cookies? Is it the nagas? Is it
the matees? Answer is mate. Not cookies,
not nagas. Okay. So, manipuri language
is a mate language. Manipuri dance is
matey culture. V of culture. Third, the
manipuri list of kings, the Ningoja
dynasty, it has existed for 2,000 plus
years. Which ethnic group did the kings
belong to?
Nagas, cookies or mates? The answer is
mate. So the kings of Manipur were all
matey. The Manipuri language 2,000 plus
years old all matey. The kings are more
than 2,000 years lineage and the manipur
dance is also matey. So who is the
ethnic indigenous people of Manipur?
Answer is mate and nagas. The nagas are
also closely related to the mate people
but they live in the hills and all.
Okay. Historically they've lived far
across Manipur in the kingdom of
Manipur. Mostly in the hills and
forests. The nagas are tribals. The mate
is I don't consider them to be a tribe.
They are people with a very ancient
culture and civilization. You can't call
them tribals. Now who are the cookies?
The cookies are infiltrators who came
from Burma. But they are not even
Burmese.
They don't speak the Burmese language.
They don't respect the Burmese culture.
They are fighting the Burmese
government. The the cookies are not even
Burmese. Forget about Manipuris or
Indians.
And in 1900 if you look at the British
census records of Manipur, there is
hardly any cookies in Manipur. So what
happened in 1891? The Manipuris fought
for independence and the British
defeated them. So Manipur became a
British wasal.
It was annexed by Britain.
And to punish the Matees who fought the
British, the British started pushing
cookies from Burma into into Manipur to
punish the Matees. And to punish the mis
the British confined the mateis in 6% of
the manipur kingdom's territory only 6%
the imal valley and the rest of the land
was given to the cookies and the nagas
nagas anyway are indigenous fine and the
cookies came in like like in incredible
numbers after 1949 when manipur becomes
part of India the Indian government
continued the same British policy
because British white man is the right
man. So after 40 49 more cookies are
allowed by Indian government into into
into Manipur and allowed to settle in
Manipur territory and in the last two
years I don't know how many lakhs have
come in. That is the situation. It's an
invasion by foreigners. The natives of
Manipur are the matees and the Nagas.
The cookies they may have Aadhaar cards.
Some of them may be in government
positions today but they are not
Indians. They don't have any allegiance
to India or India's culture. Understand
that very clearly.
All right.
Manak sorry man Saka says Indians should
back the global left but stay
conservative with respect to India. What
do I think? Clearly pro pro Trump
leanings did not help Indians in the US.
Indians should be pro- India to hell
with the left and the right in the rest
of the world. Whoever is willing to work
with India in a mutually beneficial
manner will work with them. I don't care
if they're left or right. Mu mu
mak France Emanuel M he's left
does it a is it a problem for us I'm
perfectly fine with him
he's his policies are good for us and
for himself for his country as long as
the policies are mutually beneficial
great
Shri Benjamin Netanyahu is right-wing do
I have a problem with that absolutely
not as long as as he is cooperating with
India and and working in a mutually
beneficial Great. I don't care if
somebody is left or right as long as
they are willing to work in a mutually
constructive and beneficial manner.
That's all I'll say. Right? That that
that's as simple as the clarity should
be. Nothing beyond that. Let's not over
complicate things by looking at either
left or right. We don't care. We don't
care. Whoever it is, as long as they are
willing to work with us in a mutually
beneficial way, in a mutually respectful
way, we are perfectly fine with you.
Whoever you are left or right
Sarab Sharma says how can we remove
freebies if any government even tries to
do that the whole country won't go for
it and the other party will take to the
full extent the only way to remove the
freebies is to reform the education
system and teach children from the very
beginning of their life that freebies
are poison
and then in 20 years you may have a
reasonably
literate and educated population. There
is no other way. There is no other way.
There is no shortcut. Nothing. Right
now, if the government ends the freebies
next election, bye-bye.
Bye-bye. Goodbye. Over.
Oh man. Mama. Namaste. Ma'am. Should we
be scared of Israel as Israel is now the
attack doggy that can attack any country
at will and inform the masters leader?
No. Israel is not crazy. Israel has a
lot of strategic convergence with with
India and there's nothing that we should
be scared about.
So no I I don't say it that way. No
don't worry about that. Uh Abinov says
are we heading towards a collapse of the
American empire? The US makes the world
a stable place through its domination.
Is the world ready for it? Look whether
are first of all are we heading towards
the collapse of the US empire? I think
it's is it's a little premature to
anticipate the collapse of the US
empire. It could happen. It could
happen. I'm not saying it could. It I'm
not saying it could not, but I think
it's it's still a little premature to
anticipate a collapse. It will depend on
various factors. First of all, if the
world rejects the dollar, if that is
feasible, then that could have a
significant delterious effect on um on
US interests. Right? So that's that is
indeed the case. But right now it's not
like the world is moving away from the
US dollar. Uh and the US will do its
best not to have make this let this
happen
and they have they are burdened with
this tremendous debt right and the
Russians seem to have given us the the
the plan the Americans have to to
transfer all the debt into crypto and
then devalue the crypto gone.
Um so the US has
answers to many of the problems that
that people are thinking of. Um the US
indeed has made the world a stable place
through its domination. Any empire once
it dominates it makes the world a stable
place through their own rules. The
Ottoman Empire made the world the the
the countries the kingdoms under its
domination a stable place through
Ottoman Turkish rules. The Roman Empire
did the same through Rome through Pax
Pax Romana. Today we used to have Pax
Americana. So that's the situation
always wherever you have a large empire
there's a significant period of
stability in a large part of the world
wherever the empire has it its
domination and once the empire event in
event eventually whenever it it crumbles
and falls there's going to be a period
of destabilization that's a cyclical
process we have seen we have seen
countless times in world history and
eventually it will happen again. So the
question is if the US empire declines
and crumbles will some other empire rise
up take the opportunity and replace it
in that case there could be a shorter
period of destabilization. So is the
world ready for it? The world is never
ready for these events.
Ankur Saraf says
how can Indian talent in fang build
homegrown social media like China to
share freely without relying on western
platforms and agendas. I think you you
take let's say you take 10 talented
programmers
10 talented programmers all in their 20s
okay 10 guys or girls whatever you put
them in a in a bungalow
you give them all the food whatever they
need you give them a salary of 1 cr
rupes a month which is 10 crores a month
which is like what 12 crores a year
nothing Okay? And you give them whatever
they need. They'll build you a Facebook
or whatever. In less than one year,
they'll build you a Facebook plus
something else on Twitter in one year.
The talent is here. You don't need to
find talent from fang companies in the
US who are Indians. It's there. Um it's
it's just a question of of whether we we
have the will to do it. We have so many
big companies with so much money, but
they don't want to invest in all of
these things. they don't care
they just want to you know save money
and whatever so it's an attitudinal
problem among the old old generation
Indians entrepreneurs business people uh
I mean can't Infosys or Vipro or
whatever build it build this thing of
course they can but they don't want to
they don't care
it's not necessarily a criticism it's
their money it's their company they can
do whatever they want with it but you
know that that desire isn't there and
this is not something government of
India will do. It's something the
private company should do. So it can be
done easily. Find 10 hungry, ambitious,
talented programmers, put them in a one
bungalow, give them everything they need
and give them a tremendous salary,
they'll do it happily. Even you give
them a salary of 10 lakhs a month
instead of instead of 1 cr 1 cr a month,
they'll do it. 10 lakhs is like 1/10enth
of a cr. They'll be happy. You give them
a salary of five lakhs a month, they'll
do it,
right?
Ashish Chabaraji, thank you so much.
Right. Um, Harshai says, "Thoughts on
stupid Asia Cup?" What? What is this
Asia Cup? Is it hockey, boxing,
football, cricket? Of course. Is it on?
Uh, I'm not aware of it. I I don't know.
I've kind of lost a lot of interest in
cricket these days. And there's so many
different tournaments, so many different
formats.
Uh I still watch cricket sometimes
especially the the big series India
Australia or whatever India England I
most mostly missed
so um I don't have many thoughts about
the Asia Cup I think there's some
controversy or something whatever is it
Pakistan it must be Pakistan
oh whatever sandy says can you can you
share briefly your personal background
schooling how did you end up being a
YouTuber author Restoring physicist my
personal background what's important
which how is it important look
I've as a kid I was always interested in
physics okay my dad is a physicist
himself physics professor and he's been
around the world so I already had that
that thing that some exposure to physics
my dad had a library in the in the house
full of physics and other books so there
was that and I had access to university
library. So um and um I was just
genuinely c curious as a kid and I had a
decentish intelligence. So I followed my
curiosity and schooling was uh I I had
some schooling abroad in Europe. I had
schooling in India as well. Very
different things and uh that sort of
thing. But eventually I wanted to be
financially independent. So I went into
IT right and uh that's how I spent a
decade in IT and after that
eventually I I just made a video about
Chingish Khan or something yeah Chingan
and that kind of blew up and that's
that's how my foray into YouTube started
right u so I haven't done a tremendous
amount of physics research there's one
theory called the holium theory which I
co-authored which is a theory of dark
matter
you know, primordial black holes, stable
bound states, stable quantum mechanical
bound states or primary black holes
being a candidate particle for dark
matter. Yeah, that that sort of thing.
And now I'm writing books,
a book on black holes, a series. I'm
serializing it the way Charles Dickens
used to serialize his novels. I'm
writing non-fiction. I'm writing u a
book on black holes. So that's what I'm
doing right now. So that's kind of a
very very brief highlights reel so to
say. Okay.
Duryodan Patak Duryodan Patak thank you
so much. Great name. Love it.
Shashwat Jana. Leaving aside tech how
how important is this the quality of
soldiers? Oh very important very
important the quality of the soldiers.
It's it's your soldiers your manpower is
the backbone of the of the military.
Your soldiers need to be very well
trained not just physically but also
mentally right. They need to have the
right values instilled in them. They
need to be patriotic. They need to well
soldiers being a soldier is not an easy
job because the contract is that you may
have to give up your life for the
country. So that that has to be there.
So when the time comes your s the
soldier has actually be has to be
actually willing to do that and so on.
So the quality of the soldier is very
important. You can't degrade that. You
can't adulterate that. You can't do
experiments with with the you know the
composition of your military and all
that which is unfortunately kind of
sometimes being attempted in some
places. So on so soldier quality is very
important.
Nishant Kumar says do the US
billionaires oligarchs think that common
US citizens will let them take over the
cities also is deolarization going to
happen? Okay. Do the US billionaires
think that the US citizens will let them
take over the cities? Well, do the
cities belong to the citizens
citizen may own
a house perhaps or may rent a house.
Does it mean that they they own the
cities.
Whoever can pay in the US owns
everything. Of course, a city is public
land and all, but if you can have a
proper certain a certain kind of
arrangement with the government of the
US or the state government or the
federal government or whatever the hell
you can actually take over a city as a
billionaire. I suppose especially take
over some systems administration or or
some some infrastructure or whatever and
slowly you can expand that and take over
a city. I suppose it can happen. There's
nothing illegal about it. I suppose so.
If it is not illegal, why should the US
citizen stand up to it? That's the way
the that's the kind of country the US
is. That is their social contract,
right? So it may happen and you can
always do creeping takeover. Don't take
over everything in one go. Give it 5 10
years. Make it happen slowly, slowly,
inch by inch, inch by inch, inch by
inch, foot by foot. Nobody will
understand. Nobody will realize. And
sometimes you can do it in very subtle
ways that people don't realize it. So
anything's possible. Is dolization
ddollarization going to happen? Well,
we'll we'll see. I don't know. We'll
see. Uh look, darization will be bad for
the US. The US will resist that with all
its might. Its might is super mighty in
case we are not aware. Super mighty. So
the US will resist it and that's why the
that's why the Trump administration
especially the man himself they he is so
against bricks right so yeah they will
do their best to prevent any sort of
dolorization from happening.
Okay, Shardul Desh Pande, are mind
sweepers useless as Indian Navy has
zero? Well, it depends. You see, mind
sweepers can be extremely valuable in
choke points. And if you have an
adversary who has the ability to deploy
thousands of miles along your coastline,
then a mind sweeper sweeper becomes
invaluable. But because of the kind of
coastline we have, it's almost
impossible for for an adversary to come
and deploy mines.
So which is why mind sweepers are maybe
perhaps a lower priority for India. I'm
not sure what the actual number is.
You're saying it's zero. Maybe it's
right. Maybe it's true. I have not seen
but maybe it's a lower priority for
India because of the kind of
geographical advantages we have. You see
Arian says thoughts on an algorithm to
engineer a more powerful powerhouse
than that that of the American deep
state of worried Nepalese citizen. All
right. One second.
Look, power doesn't come from
algorithms. Algorithms can help you
control
aspects of a platform. So let's say you
have a social media platform and you
want to modulate
the behavior on the platform. You can
use the algorithm for that. Let's say
you want to suppress the voices of
people who who have a certain kind of
belief. So the algorithm can make that
happen. You look at what the people have
been saying and you find instances of
certain words in that or certain phrases
and if you see a pattern of that
happening
uh you can blacklist the person and and
significantly reduce the kind of
visibility they have. So you can do that
very easily through an algorithm. So
algorithms can help you modulate and
control behavior on social media
networks and maybe in other places also.
But power doesn't come from algorithms.
Algorithms can can help you control
things and and create narratives and
push certain narratives and and destroy
other narratives and so on. But power
comes from
power. Power comes from
like the crudest way of putting it is
what Maetung said, power flows from
power flows from the barrel of a gun.
So why is the US all powerful? because
it has the most firepower of any nation
in the world. It has more firepower than
the other nations put together. Only in
nuclear firepower is it lacking compared
to Russia but just slightly.
The US has the four largest air forces
in the world or at least three largest
air forces. The US Air Force, the Marine
Air Force and the Naval Air Force.
These are the three largest air forces
in the world and
they have more than six 700 extra
territorial military bases. They have
nuclear missiles aimed everywhere.
That's their power.
Now try and counter that. Algorithms
can't counter that. Of course, if you
have certain kinds of technologies, then
they can make all this power worthless
if you can have something that's more
powerful than that. Right? So until that
happens,
the US is going to remain all powerful.
Um
yeah, so I understand people are
worried, people in India are worried,
people in in our neighborhood are
worried, our friendly nations and all.
And yeah, when you when you have an
imperial power, there is reason to worry
because they're going to interfere in
your in your internal affairs and use
you for their own purposes which will
eventually
cause you to suffer in some way. Right.
So yeah, I understand the worry.
Being enlight says you decode world
power so well. Thank you, sir. What
lessons from power and strategy can help
a man struggling in dating dynamics? You
must be great. I strongly believe dating
dynamics. I have never thought of
applying power and strategy to dating
dynamics.
Okay. Let's say you are a person who's
struggling in dating dynamics.
Ah power does is is strategy. I can
think of power. See dating dynamics the
the male female interaction that that's
how I see dating. I don't see any that
that's maybe I'm old fashion. I only see
male female dynamics and dating
dynamics.
That's not is is there an element of
power? Maybe there is to some extent. A
man who doesn't who doesn't appear
powerful in some way is obviously not
going to be seen perceived as
attractive. Um doesn't have to be
physical power always. You can have some
other qualities that are powerful in
their own way. U so you need to have
some kind of power in some sense. And
strategy well strategy
it depends. If you want to have a string
of relationships, then you may need a
strategy. But if you just want one
partner for the rest of your life, you
don't need a strategy. You need to find
the right right compatible person. So, I
don't know. I've not really applied this
to I've never thought of applying. I'm
sure there are applications. There are
all these, you know, dating coaches and
whatnot. And there is a there's a weird
community called pickup artists who use
all kinds of kinds of nefarious
techniques in this. But the Yeah, that
that's something that never has never
appealed to me. So I I've never thought
about this. Yeah, I'm not in the dating
dating game. I don't need that. So I've
never thought about it. So I I
apologize. I don't have the answer to
this. It's never thought of it. Never
once in my life. So if you if you've
thought of it even 10 years ago, then I
could I could give you some kind of
answer. But I don't have any answer
right now.
Sorry.
Okay. Rishit Singh says, "The new Nepal
leader seems to be pro- India. my
thoughts. I don't have any thoughts
right now. I'm going to wait and watch
at least a week. I am not prone to
giving knee-jerk reactions. So, I'm not
saying I'm I don't want to answer you.
I'm just saying that wait for a while. I
when the time is right, when I've seen
enough, when I've discerned some
patterns, then I'll think that I when
when I think that I have some
understanding now, that's when I'll say
something about it. See, this lady, I
don't know her.
I don't know her in any depth at all, in
any any way. What's her background? She
is she was a Supreme Court justice
apparently in Nepal. That's what I know.
I know that she's married to a
politician who hijacked an aircraft in
the 19 1900s.
An aircraft that had the Indian actress
Malasina.
And that's all I know about her. I don't
know anything beyond that. So, I'm going
to wait and watch. It's too early for me
to make a statement to give a reaction.
It's not advisable to always have a
reaction ready when whenever required.
You don't do that knee-jerk nonsense.
Wait and watch. Be patient. I'm sure
there are all kinds of influencers and
ex analysts and experts who are giving
their opinion right now. Let them do it.
I'll wait. So, I don't have an answer
right now. Sorry. Matrix says Shri
Datria is shown in human form with dogs
around him, but humans and dogs came
later in evolution. Did Bhagwan exist
before? How should I say this? I have no
idea. Humans and dogs came later in
evolution.
Uh um yeah this is a question that's
beyond my un my my capabilities of
answering. Shatraa is shown in human
form with dogs and humans came later in
um
yeah see I'm I'm a
this is this is not my expertise. This
is not my forte. Ask me about black
holes I'll answer. Uh this this is
beyond me. I'm so sorry. I don't have
the answer. I apologize. Sorry.
Okay.
Safe heavens considering current chaos
South Asia.
Not sure what your question is Anub G.
Safe heavens considering current chaos
in South Asia. We don't have chaos as I
mean chaos chaos right now. We may have
a gathering storm perhaps, but it's not
a storm yet.
So what's a safe heaven? Not sure. You
mean countries where there'll be peace?
Is that what you're asking? No, no, no.
There's no safety guaranteed any
anywhere. Maybe you can go to
I don't know New Zealand
or I have no idea. Yeah. Can't say.
Rywick says on Manipur, I found that
good YouTubers like Hush Sham Sharma,
Bijit Ayat all said cookies are
outsiders, but a German YouTuber said
that cookies are our people. What's
their agenda? Look, I don't know which I
mean I I I think I know who you're
referring to. Look, without naming
anyone, there are YouTubers who
potentially could hypothetically be on
the payroll of foreign governments and
whose agenda may not be the agenda that
is that of the national interest of
India. That's all I'll say about this.
Okay. So, I'm I'm glad that other people
are sensible and they at least are not
lying. I mean, why would Sham Sharma
Abijit Mitra lie? Nitish, I'm not sure
about him. I I mean, I've heard the
name, but I've not watched the video, so
I don't know about him in in in any
detail, but I'm glad that he's also
telling the truth. A German YouTuber or
whatever. Well,
no comments, but no surprise. Okay,
satellite. Thank you so much. Very nice
of you. Thank you. Shardul Desh Pande,
how was your experiment?
How was your experiment with Maharashtra
CM Devendra Fernis?
I did not have any experiment with him.
I have met him once. Um I met him during
that special one day event of the Jaipur
dialogues in Pune early this year. So he
very nicely came to me and he said that
he has uh what read my article on the
Arian invasion myth and he has watched
some of the videos and he just we just
had a brief interaction like like a
couple of minutes that's all. So I was
very pleased and he's a very nice
gentleman, very nice to speak to him and
yeah it was a very nice very pleasant
interaction, very nice gentleman and
very kind of him to come up to me and
speak to me. Yeah. After after his uh
event on the stage so it was I really
enjoyed that. That's all I Yeah, that's
that's the that's the recollection.
Uh VK says who was June of Ark? Was she
a warrior or saint? Jean D. That's was
her name in French and she was a young
girl of 16 when she became a warrior.
So this was during the time probably of
the 100 days 100 years war between the
British and the French. I think that was
the time period. And this girl she was
from the city of Orlon Orleans.
And at that time I think Orleans was
under British occupation and uh France
wasn't doing too great. And this girl
I think she's associated with Orleans in
some way whe whether she was from there
or or she met her end there or something
like that. I don't remember all the
details but uh she went to the DOA of
France that is the the crown prince of
France and she said that um I want to
serve the country or something and uh
she was very charismatic and people
followed her. She's a 16-year-old kid a
girl and seasoned soldiers came and
followed her and she led the army into
battle and she defeated the British in
some some military action. So people
started seeing her as some kind of saint
or something, somebody who was touched
with by divinity and eventually she was
captured by the British and they burned
her alive at the stake for being a
witch.
Such nice people the British, right?
They burned a 16-year-old girl alive
girl alive because she was
extraordinary.
So she must obviously be a witch, right?
Women with any special talent, we would
burn them. That's what the British what
it was not
limited to the British. Even the French
and the other Europeans did that from
time to time. Burning women for having
special abilities and qualities.
Rohan Allen says more red meat eating is
culturally invasive and hostile society.
I'm not sure about that.
I've not thought along those lines. So
can't say red meat eating means more
invasive.
Maybe there's a pattern. I'm not really
sure but interesting hypothesis.
Interesting.
Okay. Wen Muri says how to build
discipline and focus in life by taking
action.
By taking action. So let's say you want
to build discipline. You want to start a
new habit. Let's say you want to do you
want to get stronger and fitter. But for
that you need discipline, right? But
you're not disciplined. Then what do you
do? The only way to build discipline and
focus is by taking action. Get down
right now and do two push-ups. Just
start with two push-ups. Any anybody can
do two push-ups. Yes, do two push-ups.
Tomorrow again, do two push-ups every
time. Every day, let's say 7:00 p.m. you
do two push-up or 7:00 a.m. you do two
push-ups. After a week, you have a habit
of doing two push-ups at 7:00 a.m. every
day. And you were able to maintain the
habit. Well, congratulate yourself. Now
you say that I'll do five now. So next
one week you just do five push-ups at
7:00 a.m. very feasible. Then slowly
slowly you gradually in increase the
number of push-ups and you don't stop
the momentum. You keep doing it every
day. That's how you build discipline and
focus in anything. And once you start
doing this and and you don't break the
habit, don't break the momentum. Then
you start gaining confidence and you
start gaining selfrespect that I am able
to do something that's not that easy now
anymore because now it's no longer five
push-ups. That's 25 push-ups, right? 25
push-ups is is not a joke. Okay? Even if
it's just 25, eventually you'll be able
to do hundreds in a day. But you even 25
I think it's it's not that easy for
ordinary people. So start doing
difficult things like this gradually
slowly. That's how you build discipline
and focus by taking action. Sitting and
thinking will do nothing. The only thing
only way to achieve anything is by
taking action. Barat Bidori says why
rise
hate against India trans shooter guns
said nuke India yeah it's all online
social media propaganda and there's a
whole narrative being created created
against India and Indians and that's why
you're seeing this rise of hatred in
India towards India and Indians across
the western world
okay Nandanda Kishor Rao says do you
think it's a good idea to pursue
mathematics degree for
to pursue mathematics degree being an IT
computer science degree professional.
What paths will it open for me further?
Well, it depends what you want to
achieve in life, right?
See, you don't the way to approach this
question is you to first ask yourself
what do I want to achieve in my life?
So once you have that clarity of what
you want to achieve and not what do I
want to achieve someday what do I want
to achieve in the next 3 years
ask yourself that or or in the next 5
years or let's say next 10 years in 10
years what do I want to achieve then you
ask yourself okay now I have this
objective what is the optimal path
towards that objective does it involve a
mathematics degree or can I do without a
mathematics degree can I still reach
that path that objective without
mathematics degree then if you can reach
the objective without a math degree then
why do it
but imagine that it's not but imagine
that you love math and it'll it'll
you'll find that it will make it make
the path easier then you can go through
a mathematics degree so that's the
approach mental approach towards it
beyond that I have no idea because I
don't know you I don't know your your
objectives your goals your background so
I can't say for every person it'll I I
I'll have a different answer depending
who on who that person is what their
background is, what their goals are,
what their objectives are, what their
strengths and weaknesses are. So, all
right, that's that's how you approach
this question.
Today, PM Modi visited Manipur. What's
the result? I have no idea. Maybe the
visit happened while we were doing this
live stream. I have no idea. We'll I
I'll see tomorrow. What will be the
result? some
some ribbon cutting, some some ceremony,
some foundation stone laying, maybe a
speech here and there. Yeah, he's
visiting Chur he visited Churachanpur
and Infal. Uh beyond that, I have no
idea. I have not seen I've been here
right since 4 p.m. What's the time now?
Let me see. It's 10:52 like 7 hours
done. Would you believe it? So, if I'm
doing 7 hours live stream, how will I
know what Mr. Modi did? So, no idea. No
idea. And anyway, there's no outcome of
it. The outcome if you want an outcome
is get rid of all the foreigners. That's
the outcome that we need. Nothing else.
Rishi Barat says longtime listener.
Thank you very first time asking
question. Well welcome and thank you so
much for being a long time listener.
Thank you. See thank you sir. Uh I want
to ask how and when did the Mauist
movement started in India? It's
something that dates back to the 20th
century. Probably the 1950s60s. I I may
be wrong about that. Okay. I've not
studied the history of the maist
movement but it's been this red
corridor. Satisgund
um Madhya Pradesh uh Maharashtra this
entire red corridor
and uh I think the roots of the movement
lie it all started in a place called
Nakalbar or something that's why it's
called the Nakalite movement
when was it was it 15s 60s7s I don't
remember because I've never studied this
movement never interested me but it was
yeah very damaging to India very
problematic there was a time And
a large part of central India was not
under under the control of the
government of India. Would you believe
it? When was that? Dr. Manm Singh's time
like 20 30% of India I don't know how
what the percentage was maybe 20 maybe
at least 10%. Was not under the control
of the government of India. That's the
kind of situation you had right. Um how
and when I don't remember the story. I
have not studied the movement but
clearly it had foreign funding. It had
it had support from various political
certain political factions in India and
uh it had support from various academics
in India. I mean I personally have known
people who believed that the naxelite
movement was good
and those were not bad people
those people were not evil but they
genuinely believed the nalite movement
was good and it should be supported. So
that's the kind of brainwashing the
education system does to people to good
people
you see. So that was a deal. So I don't
know when it started sometime in the
20th century and uh the objective was to
destabilize India obviously. So who was
behind it? There could be at least two
countries I can think of.
Okay. Prashant says some tips on how to
be effective in multitasking. I am the
last person to ask how to be a
multitasker.
I can't multitask.
I cannot multitask.
I am incapable of multitasking.
My brain is so small. I can only do one
thing at a time.
Yeah. Uh what's the what's the best I
can do? Perhaps the best I can do is
this. You know, while talking, see this.
Maybe that's the best multitasking I can
do.
No, honestly I can't multitask. I am the
last person who should ask this. I can
focus on one thing for 7 8 hours but
only one thing.
I think multitasking is a myth. Maybe
I'm wrong. Maybe I'm just too
smallrained but yeah doesn't work for me
at all. Never ever.
Uh Nandanda Kishor Rao says opinion on
government facilitating safe
prostitution and cannabis consumption
and bringing them under tax ambit. Pros
outweighs the cons in my opinion. Old
profession. I have not heard about this.
I don't have any idea about this thing.
Safe prostitution.
[Music]
Yeah. I I don't know.
Look, cannabis consumption is a
different story. Cannabis has been part
of Indian culture and tradition. It's
not like I'm saying everybody should do
it. No, no, no. Don't do it. But there
are
certain festivals on which some people
they do a token consumption of cannabis
right bhang on shivatri or that sort of
thing it doesn't mean that you should do
it every day no please please please
don't but it's it's a herb it obviously
causes these mental effects and all so
it's not something that is advisable but
but in our culture and tradition some
people chose to do it on certain festive
occasions like once a year or one night
or whatever I don't think there's any
there should be any restrictions on that
sort of thing and
apart from that if you allow people to
smoke tobacco then you might as well
allow them to smoke a different weed
right so I think
I think the country should be more
liberal towards its own cultural
practices that's that's all I'm saying
as long as it doesn't result in criminal
behavior or antisocial behavior as long
as it doesn't victimize anybody so
smoking it can still victimize people
through passive smoking Right? But you
still allow it. So if somebody wants to
smoke cannabis or or consume bhang or
whatever whichever way it is done, if if
it doesn't hurt anyone, let them do it.
That's all I'll say. Prostitution, I
have no idea. Okay. So that's not a
topic that I'm any in any way familiar
with. Um so yeah,
Mandep. Well, thank you very much. So
thank you.
Life is sus says
brilliant student. I only watch podcast
whenever you come. Well, thank you so
much.
Brilliant student
studies may I was not that brilliant.
How do you quantify or measure
brilliance in studies? Marks, right?
Marks. I never got super brilliant
marks. I think when I was in
very when I was very young like Junior
KG, senior kg, first standard, second
standard that time I used to be always
topper in the class always. But
I think it was in the I think even in
the in the in the primary school I used
to be a topper usually I mean
effortlessly but I kind of lost interest
to a certain extent in studies because
of the horrific nature of the Indian
education system during my my high
school days. So those days I did not
really do super well. I did okay in
studies because you know I just had no
interest in this and during college also
I did okay but then last year of college
I don't know what the hell happened and
I got like 86% in the last year of
college that sort of thing so I was kind
of a student that did did not always
perform to my potential because
performing to my potential means
lowering standards and studying all the
garbage and which was extremely painful
to me mentally uh that sort of thing but
I used to read a And I used to I mean
whatever I whatever I enjoyed
I used to read a lot of that.
Uh D banner says why Chingish Khan
refused to invade India. Watch my video.
Watch the video that is pinned to the
channel on the videos tab. I have
explained that in detail. It takes 23
minutes to explain that. Uh I can't
explain that here in like 2 minutes but
watch the video. It tells you exactly
why Chinghan refused to invade India.
All right sir.
Pranjul Mishra says, "I read South
Africa used to have nukes once. Have you
heard of the VA incident?" Okay. Uh, so
how did they lose it? Also, how do you
see their position on the modern day
geopolitical chess board?
South Africa and Israel apparently were
developing nukes together. And Google or
or whatever you do it these days, Google
the VA incident. Let me do it for you.
the VA satellites they even helped
people theoretical physicists discover
gamma ray bursts but I'll I'll I'll go
here okay so let us Google the VA
incident 1979 here we have it an
unidentified double flash which is a
signature of a nuclear explosion VA
hotel satellite near the South African
territory of Prince Edward Islands in
the Indian Ocean roughly mid midway
between Africa and Antarctica
So most independent independent
researchers believe that the flash was
caused by a nuclear explosion and an
undeclared ocean surface nuclear test of
an Israeli device carried out by jointly
by South Africa and Israel. Okay.
So that is the VA incident and u South
Africa I think they they voluntarily
decided to end their program. I think
they were given some incentives by the
US to end the program maybe some kind of
security guarantees or whatever. So the
South Africans ended their program. The
Israelis did not.
What is South Africa's position on the
modern day geopolitical transport?
Nothing significant unfortunately.
Aravasha says is it's all it's it's
often portrayed by colonial people that
foreign countries gave us crops and so
on. I want to know the truth behind this
crops. So everything comes from foreign
countries. The rose plant came from
Persia because Indians did not have
roses. Uh the lion came from Persia
claims. No no no no no. Alexander the
great brought lions to India because
India had no lions. You see the Sarasati
Hindu pottery with lions and tigers is
is is fictitious.
So Romeula Tapar says lions were brought
by Alexander Greek. Um then there there
are some other people who say that you
know India did not have gold coins
before the Kushans introduced them into
India. So everything of any value was
introduced into India by foreigners. Our
Brahi script was actually a derivative
of the Aramaic script because we were so
backward. We do not have a writing
system of our own. Everything has come
from outside apparently.
I mean how do you want me to to react to
this
nonsense? Utter nonsense. Okay.
Uh Mohit Vijay says any idea to start
brand export for China or Russia? I am I
have no idea. Sorry. Sorry. No idea.
Abida Singh says AC sir if I were to
conduct a podcast or just a conversation
with a couple of astrology behav
creator of an app called Jaganath Hurah.
Will you be willing to spend a couple of
hours?
You see sir, I have zero understanding
of astrology. Zero. I have not read a
single word of an astrology book in my
entire life. I would be
a worthless addition to that podcast. I
will provide no value whatsoever.
I if I'm not providing value then there
is no use for me for being there. You
see? So astrology podcast that's that's
not my cup of tea sir. It's like asking
me to you know it's it's it's it's like
asking Mike Tyson to play chess or it's
like asking Vishnatan to to go and box
you know fish out of water. That sort of
thing not not the thing for me but but
thank you for the suggestion. Thank you.
Um what two or three advice will you
give to your son for great life? two or
three advice to my son for great life.
Always believe in yourself. Always work
super hard. Always work super smart.
Right. Three things. Believe in
yourself. Work as hard as you can. And
work smart. Don't be stupid. And work
hard on the wrong things. Okay.
Aravsha says, "I want to know the truth
about the Sufi movement. I have no idea
about Sufi movement. I am not someone
who has studied Islam.
I am the last person you should ask
about this. I don't know. I don't know
anything about Islam. All right. So, I
am not competent to answer this. Sorry.
Okay. Maz says, "I read about a breed of
cow in Russia and Mongolia having sweat
glands indicating evolution from zebu
cattle. Indicator of out of India
perhaps."
Um, if fit is descended from zebu
cattle, it is an indication that its
ancestors were in India. Zebu cattle
first appeared
in West Asia
about 5,000 years ago and they appeared
in Egypt about 4,000 years ago. Zebu
cattle which means that Indians were in
West Asia and Egypt about 4 5,000 years
ago because cattle don't don't decide
okay hey cattle come on now let's go for
a walk we'll migrate to West Asia cattle
don't do that cattle are domestic
animals wherever they go they go with
their human masters okay and today many
of the cattle in Africa across Africa
even West Africa are descendants of zebu
cattle interbred with u with local
domesticated African cattle so there was
an integr in progression of of Indian
zebu cattle genetics into Africa
about 4 5,000 years ago. So that is out
of India clearly and if the same
situation has happened in Mongolia and
and Russia well that's something that
also needs to be investigated. So when
did that happen? When did the
integration of Indian zebu cattle
genetics happen in Mongolian and Russia?
So has there any research been done in
that? In case there is then I would be
very interested to see that. So
interesting question. Thank you. Sedhart
says, "Whatever I have given about
Indian Iranian DNA are headed by
Iranians. I fact checked universal SNP
databases matching PCA plots distant
from South Asians done on Iranians in
Iranian soil, not immigrants. Nature
play. What do what? Why?
Okay. Okay. I'll I'll check it out, sir.
I'll check it out. Um, see, I I'm not
here to argue with you. I'm sure that
you are making good points. Um once this
live stream is done, please do me a
favor, Sedat. Um in my description of
the video, there is an email id. Please
email that paper to me. I will check it
out. Okay, I'm I'm I'll check it out
honestly. Or you can just put it in the
comments below this video. When when
when the when the live stream is over, I
will check it out. All right. Thank you
very much. I appreciate it. I'll check
it out.
So Chin Kumar says, "How do you see
advances in AI influencing geopolitics
over the next decade especially in
non-western countries?" Okay, AI and
geopolitics.
So AI like any technology is a force
multiplier and how much of a force
multiplier it is that is the indication
of its impact in any domain. So when it
comes to AI and geopolitics, AI can be
useful in multiple ways. First of all in
the military sphere geopolitics and the
military sphere military domain go hand
in hand. One of the aspects in
geopolitics is military expansion and
military activities. So if you can have
if you can augment your military
capabilities through through AI for
example have AI enabled drones have AI
enabled drone swarms have AI enabled
robotic dogs with the rifles on their
head um and and so much other things you
can do. Then when it comes to for
example
if you if you have surveillance
satellites and you are tracking the
deployments and movements of the enemy
on their territory or whichever
territory then you can feed the the
movement patterns to AI the past 6
months and AI will tell you exactly
what's happening what they're going to
what they're planning to do and
especially when you integrate that with
other information and they can AI can
tell you exactly what what the the their
their intentions are what their plans
are and it can predict their moves and
when it comes comes to for example
gamification, game theory. I mean game
theory is is something that you can do
for simple situations Nash equilibrium
and all that but when it comes to
complicated things like you know an arms
race or military deployments it's very
hard to use game theory uh methods
because uh the situations are so complex
but AI I suppose can gify it and give
you predictions so there's so many ways
in which AI can be involved in
geopolitics especially in the military
domain and also in the economic domain
you can you can forecast you can do
economic forecasts about nations GDPs
and nation strategies and all. So that's
how that's how AI can be used in in a
huge multiplicity of ways. Generally
about non-vein nations look how many
non-veest nations actually have proper
AI systems high quality AI systems only
China has it. So then China has an
advantage then right?
Okay.
Test user says will time travel forward
and backward ever happen. The only way
you can do time travel is if you can tra
if you have if you can have a
traversible wormhole and you can travel
through it. In that case you will
actually end up in a different time and
spa time and place. Not just it is not
just travel in in in space but also also
travel in time. You can
theoretically
have time travel if you use wormholes.
But wormholes
are theoretical objects. Nobody has seen
them. But the Einstein field equations
predict them. So you will have to create
a wormhole that is traversible because
wormholes won't snapshot. So time travel
is theoretically possible if you use
wormholes otherwise it can't happen.
Okay. ISX777
says isn't capitalism the only way we
can have innovation to extract resources
from the space then maybe find
technology which is more planet friendly
than like hydrogen powered cars so will
it destroy the planet very interesting
question sir I really like this question
because you have changed the paradigm
here
so I said in my criticism of capitalism
a while ago I said that it is far
superior to socialism and communism but
capitalism has one fatal flaw and that
fatal flaw is that capitalism capitalism
demands quarter upon quarter never
ending infinite profits on a finite
planet which will end up destroying the
planet. But what if we are no longer
plundering the planet? Maybe we are
plundering Mars now or maybe we are
plundering the moon or maybe we have
gone to some asteroid and we are mining
it, strip mining it for whatever.
Sure, it won't destroy our planet. It
will destroy that resource. Eventually,
you will run out of real estate to
plunder. Right? Let's say that we
destroy we decide that we will stop
destroying our planet. We'll move to to
the moon. So maybe in a 100 years when
you look out at the night sky you will
see moon full of lights and you have
mining equipment everywhere and they're
they're digging holes across the moon.
Maybe that will happen.
Maybe in 200 years we will be done with
the moon. Everything extracted nothing
of value left. Then we move to Mars and
in a thousand years we consume Mars.
Then where do we go? You see the same
problem once again applies. If you want
to treat everything as a resource then
whatever resource you have let's say you
capture a whole new planet even that
will be exhausted eventually.
So the best thing is not to plunder and
extract and strip mine everything. Don't
treat it as a resource to be extracted
and utilized. Treat it as a home to live
in.
But yeah so that that's the flaw with
capitalism you know but of course you
will say that you know 200 days is a
long time it is a long time so enjoy
while while it lasts see the plundering
of the planet has been happening for the
past 500 years but now we are reaching a
point where we have microplastics
everywhere and all kinds of other issues
takes time 200 years is a long time 500
years is long is a long time but the
time will pass and you will eventually
reach a situation where you have
degraded whatever resource you had do we
really want to keep on doing that. I
mean that's sort of an parasitic
extractive species. I think that's the
worst form of human nature coming to the
four. Right.
Uh MK says why didn't the US try to
install a puppet in France to fully
vaselize by interfering in elections
like 2024 India or color revolution?
Interesting question.
Why hasn't the US tried this
to look the US doesn't need to vaselize
France?
I'll tell you why.
France is a member of NATO. France is
also a member of the EU.
If you are a member of NATO, it means
that your military comes under NATO
command, not French command. In NATO
command is generally a non-French man.
So the France the French military or at
least significant part of it at various
points in time comes under foreign
command.
There goes your military sovereignty.
France is a member of NATO is not
entirely military militarily sovereign.
Number one second France is a member of
the EU which is why France has open
borders. It does not have territorial
sovereignty
as a member of the EU. France doesn't
even have its own currency. They have to
use the euro which is a rebranded
deutsch mark
and that is controlled by Brussels not
by Paris. So there goes your economic
sovereignty. Then the laws and the
policies that are applied in French
territory are not decided by from Paris.
They decided from Brussels. So there
goes your legislative sovereignty. So
France doesn't have full military
sovereignty. It doesn't have economic
sovereignty. It doesn't have territorial
sovereignty. It doesn't have legislative
sovereignty. Why why do you need to
vaselize that nation? Tell me why
[Laughter]
Duv thank you very much. Shri Trump
thank you
Shindai says what's left right exactly
mean in the India in India and the west.
Left and right very simply put forward
right means more patriotic more
nationalistic more conservative more
traditional. Left means
less conservative, less traditional,
more experimental,
more
more non-nationalistic, more
non-patriotic,
etc. Okay, that's the deal.
Bat Knight says, "While reading Hawking,
I wondered, does do modern cosmologies
shifts echo ancient Bharat's ideas of
creation, dissolution, and cycles?
Look, so if you look at modern
cosmology,
we have the evolution of the universe.
Well, it all started with uh with what
we call the big bang, which was not an
explosion. It was an expansion. And
space time has been expanding ever
since. And what's the eventual fate of
the universe? We're not quite sure,
right? Is are we going to have a big
are we going to have a big rip? Will
theorous era end? Are we going to have
complete darkness eventually? Will it be
a big rip or or are we going to have the
heat death of the universe or uh are we
actually in a in a cyclical universe
where eventually the universe is
expanding? Expansion stops. It starts
contracting after god knows how much
time and then there's a big crunch. Um
what exactly is the deal? We don't quite
sure right. Um so Bat's ideas are that
of creation, dissolution and cycles.
That's a cyclical cosmology that we
have. But modern cosmology doesn't give
you the answer right now as of now.
Whether the universe will will once
again contract after a certain period of
time and you know have that sort of
thing. Do we have two universes one
universe and another anti-universe
created from the big bang that also we
don't know. So there are so many
questions that modern cosmology
currently doesn't answer because we
don't have the data. We don't have
sufficient data to to formulate a proper
answer.
So uh but if you look at Indian
cosmology, Hindu cosmology, it's the
closest that we have to the lambda CDM
model so to say big bang cosmology. It's
the closest that we have.
Rushi Jooshi says namaste. Well, namaste
sir. Uh you mentioned that Ukraine is on
the Russian border so it joining NATO is
a current issue but even Finland borders
Russia has recently joined NATO. Is this
not an issue for Russia? Yeah, very good
question, very good comparison. That's
how you give counterpoints. Really
intelligent counterpoint. Okay, look.
Um,
let's very good question. Let's go to
the map. We shall um let's let me pull
out the map. All right. All right. Okay.
So, let's look at it systematically.
Yes.
So, here is the map. Now, we go to uh
the region we're talking about. So see
if you go to the north of Russia we have
Murmansk which is very close to the the
border with Finland. It's a significant
city Murmansk
and as you can see uh there we have
essentially a trijunction between
Norway, Finland and Russia.
Uh
and Finland is a nation that has a
significant border with Russia like you
rightly say and it has recently joined
NATO.
So why doesn't Russia consider Finland
to be its red line? And why different
treatment for Ukraine? Because you see
Ukraine is not Finland. Wow. What a
brilliant thing to say. Ukraine
was historically Russian territory. Do
you know the the history of the Roose
people? What was the first capital of
the Roose people?
It was Kiev. It wasn't Moscow. Moscow
comes much later. The original capital
of the Roose people, the Russian people
was Kiev.
Ukraine the name Ukraine. What does it
mean? It means Ukraine in Russian. What
does Ukraine mean in Russian? It means
the borderlands. The borderlands of
what? The borderlands of Russia. Ukraine
is Russian territory. If you look at
history from a historical perspective,
not from a, you know, not from an
ideological perspective. If you look at
a historical perspective, this was
Russia
and the Ukrainian people are a Slavic
people. The lang Ukrainian language is
very similar to Russian. How come
Russians and Ukrainians can speak to
each other? Because it's almost the same
language. It's like han Punjabi that
sort of thing, right? So Ukraine is a
totally different situation. The Finnish
people are not Slavic people. They have
nothing in common essentially with the
Russians and Finland is a different
territory. It's not that you see even
the geography matters. Finland is frozen
land and NATO cannot really weaponize it
that much against Russia. Russia has an
advantage when it comes to Ukraine.
Ukraine can be significantly weaponized
against Russia. So there are so many
aspects to this because Ukraine oversees
the Black Sea, right? Ukraine has a
there are all these factors that that
have to be taken into consideration. So
that's why Ukraine is a red line for
Russia. Finland is not right.
Okay.
Okay. We have reached 7 hours 21
minutes. I will do this for 20 minutes
more. 20 minutes more. That's sorry 40
minutes more until we complete 8 hours.
Anonymous says how should one progress
in the direction of inventions and
discoveries? For example, the there was
physics. Then someone thought further
and quantum physics emerged. Similarly,
2D to 3D video
to AR, VR came.
How should one progress in the direction
of innovations and discoveries? Well,
always ask yourself what can you do
that's to improve the current situation
and you need to have an imagination and
you need to have a vision. And in
physics, in physics you have open
questions. You have open problems. So
it's not like you have to think further
to come up with quantum mechanics. There
were questions that you couldn't answer.
That's why quantum mechanics emerge from
that. You see,
for example, if you heat
a rod of metal,
okay, you you take a iron rod and you
heat it. Why does it progress along a
certain range of colors? It starts with
dull red then becomes bright red then it
becomes yellowish then whitish then
bluish. Why why this particular sequence
of colors and what does the wavelength
or frequency of the of the light have to
do with the temperature and all these
things you could not answer it using
Newton's physics. So eventually quantum
mechanics was inevitable because of
these open questions also the discovery
of X-rays radioactivity all of that. So
that's how quantum physics emerged
because there were open questions that
nobody could answer. So you had to find
a solution when it comes to discoveries
and in when it comes to inventions.
Well, you have to think out out of the
box. You know, you had the Blackberry,
you know, mobile phone thing. So why why
did BlackBerry die? Because Steve Jobs
decided he he looked at things
differently. He said, why do you need 50
different buttons to to, you know, type
things? Why can't you use the entire
screen as something you can use to type?
And that's why we have these these
phones today, smartphones and blackberry
became obsolete. So you have to look at
things from outside of the box to to
invent things. Discoveries come out of
necessity because there are problems
that are open problems and uh you need
solutions to that otherwise you don't
understand the universe well. So
different different ways of thinking.
Anonymous says, "How are Israel China
relations historically? Allegedly,
Israel gave plans for the Lavi fighter
jet to China and AS uh yeah advanced
electronics ASAR radar technology to
China which became the J10. Do you did
you know it's the US Jewish tradition to
eat Chinese food and Christmas? I am not
aware of this tradition of eating
Chinese food on Christmas. I Christmas.
Okay. Thanksgiving is the turkey, right?
Uh, chi Chinese food on Christmas. Okay.
Jewish American Jewish tradition to eat
Chinese food on Christmas. That's
interesting. I have no idea.
Okay. I learned something different
something new today. Israel China
relations. Israel wanted great relations
with China. Israel wanted to sell
sell whatever it could to China
including weapons, whatever technology.
The Lavi fighter jet, you know what the
Lavi fighter jet is? It's an Israeli
version of the F-16. The American F-16.
Would you like to look at it? Let's look
at it. The Lavi fighter is an Israeli
version of the American F-16. Okay.
Let's go to Let's go to
Google. Okay. Isra is
lavi fighter.
So this thing, the Israeli live fighter
jet is a derivative of the F-16. And
there you see the Chinese plane that
came out as a result. So the Israelis
gave the Chinese u you know some kind of
technology or or blueprints or whatever
transfer. Yeah. So the Israelis gave the
Chinese the ability to develop an
aircraft like the like the Lavi fighter
jet and the maybe the ASA radar attack.
So the Israelis wanted to have the kind
of relationship with China that they now
have with India and even bigger probably
even more than what they have with India
but the Americans stopped it they told
Israel look we are your number one
supporters but this is something we
don't want so you need to stop it so
then Israel stopped stopped the stuff
with China and then we have the India
Israel relationship as a consequence
okay says did Spain and Portugal really
divide A world equal to rule. Yes.
Treaty of toes.
Would you like to look at it? Let's look
at it.
Treaty of Toria.
1494. An agreement between Spain and
Portugal to divide newly discovered
lands outside of Europe. Europe along a
merid meridian 370 leagues west of the
Cape Verde Islands. So this was the
division. Can you see this?
On the west everything belongs to Spain.
On the east everything belongs to
Portugal. That was the deal.
So they divided up the world into two
halves. Half Spain will take half
Portugal will take so that there is no
conflict between the two. Which is why
the Portuguese came and tried to
colonize India. You understand now why?
That's why
explore world says if God is world why
can't humans if God is one why can't
humans be one to achieve I have no idea
sir I have no idea sorry no idea
whatsoever nilastam says what's your
comments on the new fascinating theory
of 3D time coordinates given by ketchka
how can this theory be proven I haven't
looked into it yet I haven't interesting
that time has three dimensions yeah
That's the kind of uh theory that has
appeared. I haven't looked into it yet
so I can't really comment at this point
in time but yeah interesting question
and finally a physics question.
Yeah. Uh unknown user says 24 CPG unimp
24 computer science postgraduates
unemployed have nar emo available mother
and grandfather. My duty towards them as
son but I hate them a lot. I wasted my
potential. Jack of master all master of
none. How? Where to start? How to
change? What to do with his life?
You're 24 years old, computer science,
post-graduate, unemployed.
Have nar emo available mother and
grandfather.
My duty towards them as son, but I hate
them a lot.
Okay. Jack of all, master of none. Where
where to start, how to change, what to
do with this life. You have to find a
purpose. You have to find a purpose. You
have to find a direction that you want
to go towards. You have to find a goal
for yourself. And then you have to find
a way to move to school. See, life is a
challenge. Sometimes things happen that
you know that force you to go into
completely unexpected directions. Uh but
you're 24 years old, so you're a pretty
young person.
Life is long.
So don't get the feeling that life is
wasted and it's it's all over. No, no,
no. You're just starting off. There is
no life without challenges. There is no
person in that exists in the world today
who doesn't have problems and
challenges. Some are bigger problems,
some are smaller problems and so on.
What you need to do is simple.
U you need to figure out exactly what is
it that you want to have achieved by the
age of 30.
Take a piece of paper, write it down.
Whatever comes to your mind, whatever is
is is is is you know, whatever your
deepest desires are, write it down. This
is what I want to achieve. This this
this by the by the age of 30. Then ask
yourself, how do I achieve it? How do I
reach that thing? Reverse engineer. If
you have already achieved it, how would
how would I have done it? And then
figure out the way way to do it. And
then find a way. Find a way. No one's
going to help you to find the way.
You'll have to find it yourself. We have
to move heaven and earth if required.
But that's how you do it sir. That's how
you do it. So you have to understand two
things. Remember two things. First of
all, always be positive. Have a positive
attitude. Always trust yourself. Believe
in yourself and work very hard but also
work smart. All right. That's the best I
can say sir. Okay. I wish you all the
best. Be positive and succeed. All
right.
Vare says you deny the Arian invasion
theory. Which Indian institute also has
the same opinion? Are all western in
institutions uh biased against it? That
can't be true with love. You deny the
Arian invasion theory. Indian institutes
also have the same opinion. Are all
western institutions biased against it?
That can't be true. Why can't it be
true, sir? Why can't it be true?
You are saying your your argument is
that because a bunch of experts
all say that the invasion theory is
true. That's why I must be wrong.
In 1905,
everybody said atoms can't exist.
In 195 everybody, every expert said
there's no such thing as atoms.
Einstein said you're all wrong. And who
was right? Einstein was right.
So
please don't go by people's opinions.
Just look at the hard facts. If you are
going to be like this with this attitude
that 50 people say something then it
must be true and one person is saying
it's not true. He must be wrong. Then
sir you are a sheep not not a leader in
life. Please change this mindset. All
right? Just because everybody is saying
something doesn't mean it is true. I
will show you so many examples for from
history where the majority has been
wrong. and they have been proven wrong.
All right. Einstein said black holes
can't exist. He spent 30 years of his
life trying to prove that black holes
cannot form. Einstein himself
who proved everybody wrong about black
about atoms. He himself was later trying
to deny the existence of the possibility
that black holes could form.
a man of Einstein's stature.
In 1939, Oppenheimer
and Snider published a paper saying that
black hole collapse will continue. It
will not stop. But Einstein that year
published a paper saying that it
collapse will never happen. And people
ignored Oppenheimer and Snider. Well,
who came who turned out to be true? So
sir, I would say please don't have this
sheep mentality that 78 white people are
saying that in theory is true. So me
brown person must be wrong. Please don't
have that defeatist attitude that
inferiority complex. All right sir all
the best.
Nishan Singh says what's your view
regarding SSC exam where there are
several problems regarding this
examination. Government are not taking
it seriously that leads to antagonized
aspirants opposition may get traction.
SSC exam is the 10th standard exam. H
misery.
Several problems regarding this
examination. Government not taking it. I
am not aware of the specific details of
which SSC exam which state or is it is
it nationwide? What is it? I I I don't
know what problems exist. There are
different boards across the nation.
Every state has its own state board.
There are some central boards and god
knows how many boards and things. So I
don't know where the problems exist.
Problems plague the Indian education
system and I don't know what's been done
to resolve them. So my my my
overall perspective is that the entire
education system needs a overhole
and first of all you need you need to
end all the all the commercialization of
education all the corruption in the
education all the vested interests and
so much more.
All of this needs to be fixed otherwise
India is not not going to be fixed.
Okay. Dijoni says many now see global
dynamics openly. Is this exposure
intentional or are these narratives
themselves a strategy?
So many people know Israel's control
over the US. Are they failing to keep it
secret?
Look, there are two perspectives that I
keep seeing. Half the people say Israel
controls the US. The other half says no,
the US controls Israel. Which is which?
Um
many see global dynamics openly. So
yeah, there are so many things that
should should that would have been kept
secret in the past which are now open.
Many things are now now flaunted openly.
No one cares, right? Um it's not like
they are failing to keep it secret. It's
impossible to keep certain things secret
in today's age of social media. And you
know
the US is the kind of nation that they
will even flaunt the atrocities they've
done. They genocided the Native
Americans, right?
Instead of hiding that, they glorify
that in their in their cowboy movies,
the western movies. They glorify that.
They nuked, they tested nuclear weapons,
two nuclear weapons on Japan. They make
movies about it. They have this horrific
violence culture, culture of violence,
people shooting each other all the time.
They make movies and series about it.
The Americans are that sort of people.
They won't hide the dark side. They will
glorify it and they'll they'll turn that
into something fancy. and Indians will
start copying it. So, so there is this
culture, right? This this criminal
culture, rap culture. Now, Indians start
rapping.
Indians think rap music is cool. It is
very cool, sir. What's cool about rap
music? There's nothing cool about it. I
don't see that as music music at all.
But whatever the Americans do, Indians
ape them. So, yeah, they're not failing
to keep them something secret. They they
they're happy to openly flaunt it.
James is back. You boast of grand ideas,
but never forget our empire built the
railways, the courts, the order you walk
upon. We still hold the re you tug.
You see the railways, the railways you
built
were the infrastructure of extraction,
the infrastructure of occupation and
extraction. Uh you did not build the
railways. Okay. You and Indians build
the railways using Indian resources and
money extracted out of India. And you
built the railways as the infrastructure
of occupation and extraction.
Whenever you engineered famines in
India, did you employ these said
railways for famine relief? You did not.
The railways were oneway traffic
extraction out of India. So if you
really built the railways for our
benefit well did the railways not serve
any purpose during the famines you you
engineered across India, right? the
courts, you know the kind of court
system you had, it was a two-t tire
court system. When when a British person
when a British occupier of India
approached the judiciary, the British
judiciary in India, the court case would
be dealt with
with lightning
fast speed. When an Indian person
approached the courts, they would be
they would have to pay bribes and the
court pro the legal procedure would take
months or years. So it was a two-tier
system, an aparthide system, a
discriminatory system
and so much more. So I'm I'm I'm once
again grateful to James once again.
Thank you so much, sir, for for
highlighting these things that I need to
talk about. Thank you very much. I
appreciate what you're doing, sir.
Richard. Richard says recent stray dog
protest was also probably a way of
bringing instability in India. This was
majorly orchestrated by the so-called
liberals. Well, uh I haven't looked into
this in detail in any any kind of detail
but okay interesting. So that that's
another strategy that could possibly
being you be used to destabilize India.
Interesting. Interesting.
AKS BGA says right are right right
Taiwan lobby is much more stronger than
Israeli lobby in the US
and is it possible that the Israeli F-35
evaded the Patriots and THA the th8 in
Qatar?
Okay. I am not aware of the Taiwan lobby
being stronger than the Israeli lobby in
the US. Okay. I'm not aware of that.
The Israeli F-35 which bombed some a
certain location in in Doha in Qatar,
did it evade the Patriot missiles and
the terminal high altitude air defense
system? Had did it?
Well, what I heard is that
a British air refueling tanker aircraft
took off from an air base in Qatar.
It refueled the Israeli jets after they
bombed Duha and then the Israeli jets
went back.
So you have an aircraft that that took
off from Qatar. It refueled the Israeli
aircraft that did a strike on Qatar. The
Israeli aircraft went back and then the
refueling aircraft goes back to its base
in Qatar.
What sort of fixed match is this? So if
it is a fixed match as it looks like
then do you think the F-35 was ever
under any pressure from the THA or
Patriot missiles or whatever.
Okay.
Arun Kumar says I never meant to
disrespect anyone sir but actually 20
30%age of modern day Turks carry Turk
ancestry but Greek one BHS nothing to do
with Indian subcontia.
All right sir thank you very much. Thank
you for the information and do um do
leave be do do uh leave behind that that
uh the p the the link to the paper I
I'll check it out. Okay sir. Thank you.
Nilvastam says my POV on Shiva impactor
theory of cretaceious age the real
dinosaur killing asteroid they created
500 km wide crater near Mumbai. There is
something called the Shiva crater near
Mumbai and it's a teardropshaped crater.
It's not your standard impact crater
which is genuine which is typically
circular
or or mostly circular in nature.
Sometimes you have concentrate rings
like you have with a chikchulub impactor
and this shiva crater is like like about
500 km wide. The chikchulub impact
crater is about 200 km wide. So this one
is much much larger. The thing is that
there is doubt
whether it's a genuine impact event
created or whether it is something else.
I'm not very sure. I have not looked
into the details. So some people some
researchers geologists say that it is a
natural formation. It's not an impact
event because that would have been a
glancing impact which would create more
than a teardrop shaped thing perhaps.
But maybe it is an impact event thing.
I'm not 100% sure. So I don't know. It
seems to have formed during the
Cretaceous age around the time
potentially that the dinosaurs were
wiped out, the non-avian dinosaurs. So
maybe there is some connection. Maybe
there is not there see still seems to be
some kind of uh u dispute about this. So
that's all I know about it. I haven't
looked into this in detail. All right.
LR, thank you. Well, thank you so much.
Thank you yourself. Thank you.
Abhishek Ja says
sir's understanding America is Chinese B
r i om shanti we'll see about that you
know you can't have too many projects
you work on at the same time uh
understanding America will obviously
have a life of its own at some point in
time right now it is kind of in cold
storage for now cuz I am working on
other projects which right now are much
more important to me my writing projects
and also So doing doing this stuff,
right? So there's only so much one
person can do and you you got to
prioritize things in the right order.
Yeah, but we'll see about that.
Okay. I ba says, "Have you ever been
contacted by foreign agencies?"
That's quite a question you're asking,
sir. Not by foreign agencies. I haven't
been contacted by foreign by contacted
by foreign agencies. I've been invited
to visit this country that that country
u and I may have taken up some of that
but
see for example I went to Hong Kong okay
to participate in an event
uh that was last year I put out one
photograph from Hong Kong on my
Instagram. So that was an event and it
was kind of semiofficial Chinese
government thing to in Hong Kong not in
not in mainland China to uh with uh the
delegations were there was an Indian
delegation there was a European EU
delegation and there was a Chinese
delegation so it was a trilateral kind
of thing to to try and understand each
other it was a two-day event and yeah so
I I went for that and that happened
under the cham house rules which means
that you can speak about what happened
but you can't reveal who was there and
that was the agreement. Uh was there
some agency involved in that? There's
always the possibility of that. So you
always have to be cognizant of that and
and I have been invited by some other
governments also to come and visit their
country. Some I I haven't taken up. So I
am sure I am potentially on the radar
of certain countries but India's
interest is always the top priority and
the only priority for me that you can be
assured of.
Uh Sharma says Buddhists helped bin
Kasam and ethnically cleansed Hindus
from Sri Lanka and the Lord Champas and
Bhutan. They think Vic gods are slaves
of Buddha.
Uh well,
do you think Vic gods are slaves of
Buddha?
Well, it is what it is. If it if if that
is the case,
the way I see it,
both the Dharma is just another branch,
another path of dharma itself.
And if some see Buddhism
itself has so many different paths today
there are so many this vajayana there
there is
how many yanas there vajayana
mahayana Buddhism
there and there are other paths as well
there's tantric Buddhism and there is
other Buddhism there so many different
scriptures and all so maybe some of
these paths see it that way possibly
okay but the buddhi the Buddhist bikus
bikes and monks and all that I've met in
in my life I have never sensed any sort
of animosity or hostility or any such
attitude from from them from them ever
so from personal experience which is not
universal experience I'm sure but I
personally have never felt felt it that
way it is possible that there may be
certain parts of Buddhism that that see
things in that manner u
so yeah The world is complicated. The
world is complicated. Uh it is possible
that there was
help given to the Turk invaders of of
Gandhar.
We know that what was it the Guris the
Gurids were originally Buddhists who
converted right and then they then
became one of the worst Muhammad Guri.
he became one of the worst uh you know
tyrants to brutalize India and so on. So
the history is complicated
but you can't deny what you're saying to
to a very large extent. Yes.
Uh Mr. Saka says big fan. Thank you sir.
Thank you very much. If all of Europe is
considered to be the west the Gulf
countries are the Middle East then what
is the center or the middle?
It depends where you are sitting.
Look why do we say Middle East?
From whose perspective is is it the
Middle East? It's from the western
perspective because from there there is
the far from the west there is the far
east there is the Middle East and
there's the near east. The near east is
Turkey. The Middle East is uh the Gulf
region the Arabian nations in the far
east is is is China and all of that.
That is if you are sitting in Paris or
London that's how you see it. So all
this terminology that we are used to we
accustomed to to employing it is all a
euroentric terminology it's an
accidental terminology it's not from our
perspective
the center or the middle is wherever you
are okay so the the Chinese said that
China is the center of the world fine
from their perspective it is from my
perspective where I am is center of the
world this is entirely subjective okay
there is no hard and fast rule
Vishal Ro says, "I know you don't answer
live news, but air raid sirens currently
in Poland after drones in Poland and
Romania." Interesting. I'll check it out
after this is over. Thank you for
letting me know, sir. Thank you, Vishal.
Okay. Shir Shir Shandhu Pande, thank you
very much, sir. Thank you.
AKS Buga says, "Did you see Epstein's
pick with the Saudi crown prince?" What?
I haven't seen that.
I haven't seen that. I will we'll look
it up.
Very interesting. Very interesting.
Yeah.
Okay. JT says, "I want to be the Dharaj
like Yudeshir Nashok for Bharatwash in
the future. Please explain in detail how
to prepare for it. How to learn Rajantra
and war." Yeah. Well,
how to learn Rajantra and war? To learn
something, you have to do something. If
you want to learn coding, you have to do
coding. You can't learn by reading
books. If you want to learn martial
arts, do you think that you will read 20
books of martial arts and become an
expert? No. You go and practice. So if
you want to learn Rajantra and war, you
do get involved in politics and warfare.
That's the only way you learn. You don't
learn by sitting at the feet of a
teacher and listening to lectures. No,
the only way to learn is by doing. Okay?
Okay. So that's what I would recommend.
Learn it by doing.
All right.
Let's take the next question.
U says Poland is so much family ccentric
and welcoming. I am following an
Indo-Pish couple on YouTube. Very nice.
Okay. But Japan is not familycentric at
all compared as compared how I think
Poland is a very good place to relocate.
All right. Japan what happened? Japan
has become work obsessed. See, Japan is
under foreign occupation. Please
understand one thing, my dear friends.
When a country is under foreign
occupation, it can its society can no
longer function the way it was supposed
to function. There is something that
they will never teach you because they
don't want you to realize this thing.
When a country is under foreign
occupation, its society and culture get
distorted and its society can no longer
function the way it was originally
supposed to function. The way it had
evolved over centuries or thousands of
years to function.
Japan also underwent something called
the major restoration in the 19th
century which also caused you know
caused distortions of Japanese culture.
They tried to overthrow Dharmic culture
from Japan. The Miji emperor said that
we will now eat beef and he was the
first to eat beef and then every all
Japanese people slowly adopted eating
beef. For a thousand years, eating beef
was taboo in Japan. So Japanese society
has changed a lot in the past 150 years.
A lot of it because of the foreign
occupation of Japan. And the Japanese
have been worked to death.
The Japanese
work culture today is insane.
It's insane. There's no happiness in
life. All you do is work, work, work,
work, work. So that's and if you have
that sort of culture in the country, how
can you have families? That's why the
the birth rates have have declined
abysmally.
So yeah, it may not be that
familycentric anymore, Japan, compared
to what it was before the major
restoration. I can assure you in 1840
Japan would have been way more
familycentric than it is today but
things change. Ammon George says been
watching your show since 2022. Thank you
very much sir. Thank you. The current
development of AI is rapidly
progressing. So as a new architect in
India what will the future be like? What
can I do to be relevant? You are a new
architect
and what can you do to be relevant? Well
India needs good architecture. Trust,
believe you me, India needs good
architecture. India's architecture is
ugly.
It is a pale imitation of the Soviet
brutalist style. I suppose you will know
what brutalism is in architecture. India
needs aesthetic beauty.
So if you can provide that aesthetic
beauty not a a watered down imitation of
whatever is currently the in vogue in
the west but something entirely Indian
which will be unique in the world then I
suppose then you will do well of course
if there are buyers for that but you
know that's also an issue because most
Indians are mentally colonized and they
want something that copies the west not
something that's indigenous. So I think
look you've got to have clients you've
got to have an income.
Uh so I suppose you have to do whatever
the the client wants. The customer wants
the customer is the king. Um
can you incorporate AI into
architecture? I suppose it should be
possible, right? AI can come up with
ideas and you can then pick a design
that you like and then you can adapt it
or something like that. I'm not sure. Um
what will the future be like for
architects? I think there's a tremendous
amount of scope for architects but I
don't know what kind of architects they
need just just functional buildings or
do we need aesthetic buildings? I would
be I would love to have aesthetic
buildings in India but I'm not sure
about that. What can you do to be
relevant? You have to stand out to be
relevant in any profession. You have to
be super competent first of all. You
have to be different in some superior
way from from uh the average architect.
You have to be super professional and
you have to deliver results, right? So
you have to stand out in some way. You
have to develop your unique style or
voice. Not voice in architecture, style
in architecture, right? That's what you
have to do. So you have to find a way to
differentiate yourself while maintaining
the highest standards. Um that's how you
stand out as an architect. And of course
you need clients. So ensure you get
clients.
All the best sir. Okay, we are almost at
8 hours. So I'm going to have to stop
this end this soon. I still have a
mountain of super chats.
So please stop taking super chats now
please. I cannot do beyond way beyond 8
hours. It's incredible that I've done 8
hours. Then says there's a theory going
on that we are behind regime regime
change in Nepal because our PM
congratulated Nepal PM but he said
nothing during the Bangladesh crisis.
It's a theory I read. I hope I won't
make you angry. Why should it make me
angry sir? Why? Please let's talk about
things. Let's discuss things. There's a
there's a theory going on that we India
is behind regime change. You know people
will come up with all kinds of theories.
The moment the wind changes direction
from here to here new theory will come
up. That's the deal in social media.
That's the deal with the influencers.
They have to be relevant in some way. So
they have to come up with theories. Uh
so uh I am absolutely not angry sir and
uh I don't believe that we are we are
behind this regime change operation. We
are not. Okay. Karan says Athena is
Adidi claim was actually from India in
Greece book by Edward Pokeok uh it also
had okay okay okay oh yeah I've read
that book I have that book I may have
recommended it sometime it's an
interesting book to explore different
ideas
right if I if I recommend RC Majunar am
I also recommending the Arian invasion
theory that's embedded in it no you
should read because you should explore
different ideas uh it also had pseudo
connections like Buddha became backers
pandova became Pandandy and Himbal has
became the yeah well all that I
obviously cannot agree to right okay
spade says there is this uh our
politician who's ready to say sell his
country uh can we as corn people do
something to protect our sovereignty
from such r look I don't discuss
domestic politics okay and overall
unless you are in politics you can't
really do much to counter politics
unless you start a mass movement or you
you start um a strong narrative on
social media. So there are things people
can do overall to create a narrative or
to counter various narratives but at the
end of the day to counter politicians
you have to be in politics.
Atarva says greetings can you brief
about your holium research? Holium
theory is the theory okay look there's a
big open problem in physics in
astrophysics in cosmology dark matter if
you look at the mass energy composition
of the universe about 4% is visible
matter everything you can see in the sky
all the stars planets galaxies quazars
everything nebula all the visible matter
it's just 4% of the mass energy
composition of the universe about 70%
roughly is dark energy and about 25%
26% is dark matter. What is dark matter?
We don't know. So the theory holium
theory is that the there is a very high
likelihood that an overabundance of
primordial microscopic primordial black
holes were formed during various epochs
in the early history of the universe
like uh like for example the
pre-inflationary period, the
post-inflationary period, the re
reheating period and so on. So you had
possible overabundance
of production of of primordial black
holes, microscopic black holes in the
early universe. And what if they formed
stable quantum mechanical stable bound
states?
What if that's the case? In that case,
if those bound states are stable, then
they will not disintegrate through whole
through Hawking radiation and they could
form an important component of of dark
matter. So that's the research. Okay,
that's the theory.
Uh Kl Mundal says, "Are you familiar
with the MBTI personality based on Carl
Jung's work? Curious if you have typed
yourself and what's your type, if I may
ask?" INTP.
I am I NTP. That's my type. Yeah, I mean
I every single
M MTI test I've taken on whichever
website, it's a long tedious test. Okay.
First of all, it takes half an hour.
Every single time I'm taken, it's always
been INTP. So yeah, I I I supposedly I
am am an INTP.
Okay. Tanish says, "Evening, evening,
sir. Big fan of." Thank you so much. Uh
please elaborate on Singapore's
geopolitical stance historically in the
current scenario in the coming future.
Singapore
Singapore's geopolitical stance. Well,
Singapore is uh
it's an important nation economically in
our neighborhood.
um geopolitical stance. Look, when you
are just a city state, your geopolitical
stance doesn't really uh isn't that
impactful. It's important economically
and financially. It's important because
it occupies an an important position in
the Mala region. It's got major port
facilities where the Americans can dock
aircraft carriers and it's been part of
the western world Singapore just like
Japan is part of the west and South
Korea is part of the west
not physically not geographically but
politically that way Singapore is also
part of the west and that's been its
geopolitical scenario
uh and uh in the coming future we'll see
I think Singapore will remain
significantly
uh significantly significant. Yeah.
Economically, financially
um but see the geopolitical perspective
is a multi-dimensional perspective. It's
economy, it's it's diplomacy and it's
the military aspect and the
technological aspect. So when it comes
to those aspects, diplomatically,
Singapore is is excellent. It's got lot
of diplomats, high quality diplomats. U
economically it's it's a major economic
center. Excellent. Um technologically
I'm not sure where Singapore is and
militarily well Singapore has a decent
enough military to take care of its uh
national security but nothing beyond
that and it's it's part of the overall
western world. So that is the situation
and that's probably how it it will
continue in the coming future.
Shir Shendu Pande says please consider
one live session per week in Hindi. Two
as others of family can understand may
improve channel growth as potentially
one half country can benefit. Okay, I'll
I'll consider that. Thank you. Thank you
sir.
Being enlight says sir you are great at
power. I bet girls loved it. 25 tips for
me. I look
I I was not that sort of person who was
you know what you may perhaps imagine.
Um
so tips for you I I don't know be the
best version I my only tip for everybody
is be the best version of yourself right
be at the peak of your physical and
mental prowess that's what I would say
and that makes any person attractive in
all ways right
uh CR says Modi today Manipur speech
praised the young people of Nepal can be
seen working hard to clean and paint the
roads of Nepal I have seen their
pictures as well any role in India any
Indian role in this regime change? I
don't think so. I don't think so. Uh
this is merely encouragement to the
people of Nepal. Uh that's all I can
read into that. I haven't seen the
speech myself because it must have
happened while I was doing this live
stream and we have reached 8 hours. I
have been sitting here for 8 hours and
speaking. I don't think I have in my
entire life spoken for 8 hours at a at a
stretch.
Okay. Uh so I don't think there is any
Indian rule in the region operation.
Okay. All right, I'm going to have to
end this soon. I got a hundred more
super chats. Please stop taking super
chats. Uh, should we show inhumane
nature when thinking of national
interest?
Well, all I would say is read the ara
shastra.
Yeah,
shastra. The ara shastra will give you
the answer. Essentially
you do whatever it takes to prioritize
your national interest because your
enemy will do whatever it takes to
prioritize his national nation's
interest including the inhumane aspects
you are discussing here.
So in when it comes to things matters of
national security a everything is
allowed
you can cheat you can break the rules as
long as you are on the right side of
dhmalites essentially
aniket says currently a US student I
have a Muslim friend saying that
Hinduism is not valid and all Hindus
will go to hell
why so much hate how to handle it I have
no idea I have no understanding of this
this world this particular religion
And I don't comment about these topics.
So I have no idea sir. I'm not the right
person to ask this. I can answer
geopolitic history or science these
religious matters. Well, what can I say?
I have no idea. Sorry. Uh Spade says in
today's world what skills and
capabilities would be required for a
person to be leader like Chaparati
Shwaji, Yingis Khan or Vikram Madita.
leadership qualities. A tremendous
amount of persistence, tremendous amount
of willingness to work hard, tremendous
vision, intelligence, the leadership
qualities, the abilities you need to
handle people, different kinds of people
and make them work together,
organizational abilities, tremendous
courage,
willingness to sacrifice everything. All
these qualities are needed. Only then
can you reach that level.
Shinmai Gosavi says, "Is antimatter
dangerous?" very very very dangerous.
It's lethal.
Antimatter is lethal. The moment it
comes into contact with ordinary matter,
it annihilates itself and the ordinary
matter in an explosion of pure energy.
It's lethally dangerous.
One microgram of of antimatter can blow
up an entire room or maybe more than
that. I have what was the calculation?
It's been a very long time since I've
done these calculations.
Uh the basis of the calculation is
calculating the energy output in mess
mega electron volts and then translating
that into jewels and then into kilo
kilotons of TNT.
And the basis of the of the calculation
is the simple equation E= MC²
very dangerous super dangerous
cause and effect. This is all
speculation but do you think there was
an eastern channel of the Sarasati
river? I kind of think the story of
Bhagat could be related. I have
absolutely no idea. I've never thought
about it. I have only looked at the
Saraspati as this great river in the in
western India an eastern channel of the
Saraspati. The thought has never crossed
my mind. So yeah, I don't know. Do I
think there was one? Well, have we found
any evidence of any paleo channel dating
back to those times?
in case we have found evidence there
would be talk about it but I have never
heard anyone speak about it so it looks
like the likelihood seems to be low and
I personally have not thought about it
so that's all I can say
yav thank you very much sir thank youi
says flamingco looks oddly similar to
katak did the romani people who had
Indian roots take it with them and give
it a different name they were outside of
India for 800 years so so clearly it has
Indian roots the you know the hand
movements the hand movements and all
that it's very Indian so flamco is very
similar to katak it's functionally the
same dance form with different music and
but it's functionally the same thing so
obviously because of the romani people
and their Indian roots flamco is a
romani dance and flamco music is romani
music
uh so it's called flamco I'm not sure
how the name evolved but it's it's roots
lie in India
Hesh Kumarov says, "Is Europe really a
continent?" Look at the map.
Good question. Now, this is first
principles thinking. Look at the map. Is
it a separate continent? Is it is it a
separate landmass? It's not. It's a
fictional continent. The real continent
is Eurasia.
AKS BA says, "Do you think geopolitical
analysts before besides yourself are
very delusional are riddled with pride?
For example, Jaipur diaries with fake
false rational. Look, I will not offer
any comments or criticism about other
people. All I can say is in general the
quality of the geopolitical analysis in
India is is is not good. It's not it's
not good. It's uh
yeah that's all I'll say. I will I will
not comment about anybody in specific.
Um
yeah, but overall the quality of
discourse in India is is is very poor.
very poor very surface level analysis
very wrong analysis very often but I I
will not take anyone by name
says what is happening in Dhastala
dakanda I have absolutely zero idea sir
I'm very sorry I have no idea
okay Srishti says you're an well thank
you ma'am thank you so much for the kind
words uh I want to research ancient
Indian lost history should I pursue it
through a formal academic background or
conduct my own independent research
Look, I'll tell you what. If you pursue
it through a formal academic background,
it means that you have to spend a
significant portion of your life and
career doing it because that's now the
path you have chosen academically and
those degree certificates you have.
We'll say that.
So, in that case, you will also have to
gain employment through those academic
qualifications. Is that something you
are willing to do or is that something
you would like to do? Is that a path
that appeals to you? I mean, a long-term
path. If it does appeal to you, then by
all means do it through formal academic
uh qualifications.
But if it's something that is not
something you want to do in your
full-time, you're curious and you may
want to do research on it, but it should
not it's not something you want to make
your career, then I would say don't do
it through academic research. Do it
through independent research. You can
gain the same expertise without an
academic degree. Right? So let's say you
want to have a career in so and so field
which is not this. Then I would say
don't get an academic degree in that.
Don't waste two three years of your life
in that. All right. All the best ma'am.
Hunter Kenway says, "What are your
thoughts on the relevance of the rimland
and sea power theories in today's
geopolitics since both the US and China
are strategically implementing them in
some form to gain or maintain power?
What are my thoughts?
Look, it's one way of looking at the
world with the rimland theory, the the
the world ocean theory. Uh that's that's
Mackander's theory, right? That's that's
a theory that was formulated about 100
or so years ago. And there is some merit
to this theory is whoever controls the
heartland of of the world island which
is Eurasia, the heartland of Eurasia
essentially controls the world and and
and for the west the the pathway to the
heartland is through Ukraine by the way.
So the US is operationalizing that they
they are definitely following that
theory for sure at least to some extent.
Uh China is a rimland power. It it is
also a heartland power because it it
controls a significant portion of
eastern and central Asia. So China is a
heartland power. Russia is very much a
heartland power. India is a rimland
power. India has not made any inclusions
into the heartland. So the relevance is
kind of there. The US does believe in
this theory and which is why they're
going after Ukraine as you can see
right. Yep.
Okay. Shashank Wangari says market
leaders Germany 1400 India 62. Okay, I'm
sure
Germany 1400, India 62.
What are these numbers?
Market leaders.
Yeah, I'm not sure exactly what these
numbers represent. If you could give
some context, maybe I would understand
more.
Germany 1400, India 62. Uh I I
apologize, but I'm not able to
understand. Maybe brain is not braining
too much.
Hunter Kenway says, "Why doesn't India
give rimland and sea power much practice
despite having an ancient entire ocean
at it at its fingertips with great
success in the past like the Chulas?"
Well, I have been saying this, India
needs to become a great maritime power
again. We've always been a maritime
civilization.
We need to develop a powerful navy, a
navy with distributed lethality. And
always remember that quantity has a
quality of its own. India needs to do
that. So maybe we need to invest not
maybe we definitely need to invest more
in the naval naval aspect of our
military.
I agree
Madara says why isn't it possible to
Charlie Kulk
antiational CM uh sir we should not sir
I would request you not to ask such
questions it is not appropriate at all
sir. All right thank you.
CA aan reddi ventula says good evening
well thank you sir I am a maraharashan
readyi from varangal and curious about
the origins and history of the readyi
people well I am so sorry sir I have not
researched this I I don't know sir very
sorry I have no idea there's so many uh
there are so many very interesting
histories in India of various
communities and I get questions about
these but my my research and my study
has been of history globally
I have not done
a deep research into all all these
Indian histories which are fascinating
but there's only so much you can read
and and historically I'll tell you why
as a kid I disliked Indian history
because it I saw it as a history of
defeats a history of sadness and pain
which is why I stayed away from Indian
history and I read world history and
only later did I enter the realm of
Indian history but I have not researched
all of these aspect. So I'm I'm very
sorry sir but uh I'm glad that you're
curious about your ancestry and
heritage.
Curious RC says big fan never miss
video. Thank you so much sir. How does
the entire gambit of current works? Who
decides the value of currency? Our GDP
is increasing but when does the value of
currency actually increase and how
uh how does the entire gamut of currency
work? Who decides the value of currency?
exchange rates, GDP is increasing, but
why does the value of currency actually
increase and how? Very interesting
story, very interesting question. And I
am not sure that I have the answer right
now at my fingertips.
Right? We I understand how GDP works,
gross domestic product also GMP which is
related to that. I also understand how
the purchasing power parity thing works
against the other one. How how does the
value of currency work? The exchange
rate I think it's if in a free floating
market it depends kind of on the kind of
demand a currency has.
So I think in a free floating market it
depends the exchange rates depend on ho
how much people are willing to buy and
sell a currency for that's the basic
understanding I have and beyond that I
may not be able to answer in detail at
this point in time because I yeah I
haven't thought of this question for the
longest time I think in a free floating
see
some nations they decide what the rate
is going to be for the currency exchange
rates with versus with various
currencies so in the past India had
India used to decide the exchange rate
and sometimes you would hear in the
duration news when I was a kid India has
devalued the currency by so and so the
government of India would decide the
exchange rate but today the rupee is a
free floating currency which means the
market decides the rate of the rupee
that's the best I can tell you
okay susant baraj says souls are of two
kinds new ones are still learning so
they run after pleasures wealth old ones
live wiser with meaning and purpose.
Dharma says that when two people come
together a new soul is formed. Well,
that is profound and that maybe
makes a lot of sense what you're saying
sir. Yeah. Uh new ones, new souls.
So, new souls can be formed when you
have the evolution of a soul from a
lower realm to a higher realm.
And uh
yeah, new souls will run after material
pleasures. Bold ones have gone through
the cycle multiple times and they are
wiser and they will live with more
meaning and purpose. Make makes a lot of
sense. Very interesting. Thank you sir.
Dshot
[Music]
recently saw a Russian official
explaining how the UK US is planning to
remove its debt through stable coins at
the expense of the world by devaluing
the coins. There is a park angle. Please
explain the process. Please explain the
process and physibility. very
interesting theory coming out from
Russia. It makes a lot of sense. So the
US is is saddled with this tremendous
debt right and it obviously it needs to
remove the debt. So what it will do is
it will transfer all the debt to these
cryptocurrencies stable coins and once
all the debt is transferred so you you
make cryptocurrency a thing you bring
the crypto cryptocurrency on par with
the US dollar for a few years and you
offload all your debt national debt into
cryptocurrency
and then
eventually you devalue the
cryptocurrency and the debt disappears
evaporates
just a magic trick. Pakistani angle.
Pakistan has a cryptocurrency sector now
and the Trump empire is investing in
that stable coins. Yeah. So that's the
deal. Feasibility very feasible.
Uh Dorji says small thank you from Nagar
and hope you visit us. I would love to.
I would love to. Thank you so much sir.
Thank you.
Uh Kathan Varma says OMG CN versus Cap
James is China. Ian versus gap James is
bety
his funny
okay if you say so sir I didn't
understand but thank you dush low birth
rates in India thoughts not good uh
alarm bells because that will cause
population collapse eventually if we
don't have to deal with it our kids will
have to deal with it right not good for
Indian nation I would I agree that the
population is too high we need to bring
it down to about 330 400 million right
now it's 1.4 4 billion. That process of
bringing the population down should take
a couple of centuries. Centuries should
be global. If you try to make it happen
fast, it's going to cause cause
demographic collapse. And that is not
good for civilization for the country.
So yeah, it's it's alarming.
Vishuvendra Singh says what's the
relationship between the US and Brazil?
Why was the same 50% tariff as India
imposed on them? Because they were kind
of uncooperative in some way. because
they have also joined a breaks but
overall Brazil cannot really go against
the US dictats. Yeah. And if they are if
they are trying to be a little bit
independent then the US will punish them
with the tariffs and so on. Right.
Hersh Rati says why resistance of kanjs
not taught in history? I'm not sure. I
myself am not aware of this. I myself am
not aware. Kikan jats. Interesting. I'll
look it up sir. I'll look it up. Thank
you.
uh a Rahul says what is systems why is
systems thinking not taught in our
schools our schools teach you surface
level stuff
and stuff some stuff they teaches very
advanced which even gods don't know
but these important things they will not
teach you system level thinking systems
thinking critical thinking first
principles thinking these are the
fundamentals
of of of constructing a competent person
who can adapt to new situations right
mental models systems all of that it's
not taught because they don't want you
to they don't want you to be competent
they want Indian people to remain like
sheep
slaveminded so that's why okay being
enlight well thank you sir ma'am whoever
you are ma'am thank you thank you sir
saited thank you for your selflessness
service to the nation thank you very
much sir thank
Danosh says, "Is there any proof of
Abrahamic religions?" Asking because I
grew up abroad and in history class they
taught the Abrahamic history is real and
I was shocked.
Well, the Abrahamic religions are indeed
a thing and the root of the Abrahamic
religions is Judaism
and one of their prophets was Abraham.
Right? the who are their major prophets?
Moses or Musa and Abraham or Ibraim? And
Moses is the is the prophet who
apparently, you know, brought them out
of exile and slavery in Egypt, of which
we have no archaeological evidence, but
whatever. And the other is Abraham,
prophet Abraham.
Um, so
what proof the Abrahamic religions do
exist? The oldest proof of Judaism goes
back about 900 BC or thereabouts. Uh you
have uh King Solomon, King Saul. I'm
sure they existed and that sort of
thing. So the religions are indeed real.
Did Abraham, prophet Abraham, prophet
Moses exist? Well, they are convinced.
They are certain that they existed even
though there may not be evidence which
is you know what absence of evidence is
not the evidence of absence. So indeed
it may be true. Uh okay. Riti Kedwani
says these are there are movies about
Shivaji Maharaj and many other Indian
empires and things but never about ohms
and lit Borpukan. Ask Bollywood why
we have no dirt. We have no shortage of
great heroes
in India
but they won't make movies about the
Aomes about Lachit Book and there are so
many more they won't do it. Especially
Bollywood used to earlier invite
Pakistani actors and actresses and
singers because cultural exchange. Why
did they never have a nasame singer or a
Nepalese singer or or or or a singer
from Odisa Odisha?
Why in Bollywood? Why only these people?
Why not a singer from Thailand or an
actor or actress from Thailand or
Myanmar or Indonesia or whatever? Why
always Pakistan? That's a problem with
Bollywood, right?
A Rahul says, "I have recently uh
started reading philosophical texts of
Ad Van, the Kashmir, Shaism, Ashtavakra
Gita, etc. Why aren't they popular?
They're beautiful.
They'll be popular if they more people
are exposed to them and the best way to
do it is through the education system by
giving some level of exposure which will
then induce the intelligent kids and the
kids with curiosity to pursue it more.
But we simply don't even teach the
existence of these philosophical texts
in our education system. That's why they
aren't popular. No one knows about them
and people aren't the education system
kills your curiosity. So then once you
grow up, once you're out of the
education system, you will never in be
inclined to read a single word again in
any book. You see that's why Rahul says
literally the first page of the Ashtap
ashtavakraita completely rejects cast
chhatta.
Why do people cite manusmitti but not
see text but not texts like these?
Because it's called cherrypicking.
Cherry-picking.
Find one one text out of thousands which
has something that looks like what we
can weaponize and that's it. Just keep
on harping on that. There is a clear
agenda to portray Hinduism as as evil,
regressive, patriarchal, cast, blah blah
blah blah blah and to convince Hindus
themselves that their religion is like
that and there's a whole ecosystem and a
whole industry built around that. So
they have found something in somewhere
and then they will keep on harping about
that. We have so many like like what
you're saying the first page of Vikra
Gita completely rejects the these
concepts. But you see even if you say it
the the the the academics who have who
have a strangled hold on the education
system they will never publish a word of
that and people will look up to
authority right these are the authority
these people are the authorities in in
history and education. So that's why
these the truth gets whitewashed.
Jugnaf Vignesh says love your work sir.
Thank you. Could not tune in today. No
problem. Maybe I'll watch this on the
weekend. High earning vaansrit.
High earning vaanskrit. Well I I
do watch on on a weekday. I have no idea
about the high earning vans but all
right and thank you so much. I really
appreciate your view your viewership and
support. So thank you. Anerud Prattab
Singh says can you tell us about sundial
bomb? I don't know what there is.
Sundial bomb
I can't remember what it is. I'm sorry.
Danush says any ideas how to end north
south divide and language supremacy wars
in India. It seems so deeply embedded
where people put trivial things over the
nation. The solution there is no
shortcut. The solution is to reform the
education system. There is no other
solution.
After people grow up, you can't change
their minds. The only way the only time
to put the correct ideas in their mind
is when they are children, when they are
learning. The only solution is to reform
the education system. There is no other
solution.
Ritiku says guest recommendation Nlesh
Oak would be a banger. Well, thank you
for the recommendation, sir. Right now
I'm not doing podcast as you as you must
be knowing but whenever I do it I will
certainly consider that. Thank you sir.
Okay. Uh Velika says sorry if it's a
basic question. No issues. Um is Obama
actually a part of the deep state? Yes
of course he is.
He is. If so why is Trump able to speak
against him so freely? You see when you
when you want to control a nation
let's say you have a nation with two
sides.
You want to fully control the nation,
then you control both sides and you
create these fake divisions and fights.
But behind the scen, it's it's like a
WWE match. In the WWE matches, you have
fixed matches. They're all rehearsed and
choreographed. So, in front of the
crowd, these two guys are enemies and
they hate each other. They'll bash each
other up. Once the crowds are gone and
they are back in the hotel, they'll have
dinner together.
Okay, ma'am.
Uh, Sarak Dala Beher says, "Why did the
holy church support the Nazi party deep
state?" I I don't know about that. I
haven't looked into that part of
history. Not sure, sir. But yeah, the
Pope did support the Nazi party. Yes, I
suppose. That's what I've heard. Yeah.
Uh, Bas says it's been it's been 7
hours. Forget food. You haven't even
taken a Luke Luke break. Please admit
you're from Mars. It's but obvious. It's
been 8 hours and 25 minutes now and I've
been sitting here talking. I better stop
now. But I've got all these uh super
chats that people have taken. Please
stop taking super chats. I cannot keep
answering questions now. I got to stop.
I'll make this fast. Rohan says, "Why
not US tried to vaselize Mongolia to
counter Russia and China?" Because
Mongolia was already vasalized by the
USSR. That's why the USSR got there
first.
Wun says I reached the pashon genetics
to prove my friend was of Indian detail
but PCA blood so Afridi butans and up
are genetically genetically very
dissident from north Indians and
Pakistani Punjabis. All right sir. All
right. What can I say about this? If you
say so.
Okay. Priyanka says tips to train our
brain to be consistent like you.
Daily repetition,
small steps in the beginning and just
keep on doing it. Form habits and keep
on doing the same habit over and over
again with over time greater intensity
but slowly. Don't do too much too fast,
right? And if you want to make a habit,
you stick to it no matter what happens.
And that will tremendously increase your
confidence, willpower and so many
things. Tremendous positive improvement
in your life in your life.
Uh Shuban Kumar says, "Did you see the
capitalist post of IIT Bombay?" I saw
it. Am I surprised? I am not surprised.
This came from one of the humanities
departments in IIT Bombay. Why do we
have humanities departments in IIT
Bombay or in any IIT? What does IIT
stand for? IIT.
IIT. Indian Institute of what?
Technology. So if you have an Indian
Institute of Technology, why are they
teaching humanities there?
Why do you have sociology?
Why do you have other other such
disciplines? End this now.
What is the government of India doing?
Why are you funding these snake pits
in the name of science funding?
Unacceptable. Look at the kind of
research that come out comes out of
these humanities departments. All
anti-India research. All of it. I just
don't get what the government is doing.
Krishna Kumar says Russian delegation
will be visiting Hrol to discuss Sukoy
57 production India. My thoughts if we
choose will be a major irritant in India
US relations. What more major irritants
do we need in India India US relations?
What now? What hasn't Trump done enough
to spoil India US relations? What more
needs to be spoiled now? There is zero
strategic trust now between India and
the US. India doesn't trust the US one
bit
and if the US wants to be upset, they
can be upset. India should do whatever
is in it in its national interest.
That's it.
Uh but I hear that we are going with the
Rafal Rafal. I'm not sure. I'll have to
look into it. Uh but if the Russian
delegation is coming here and if they're
offering a good deal on a fifth
generation fighter plane, even if it's
an okayish fighter plane, I think we
should go for it. All right.
Naven Ry says, "It's my first super chat
ever. Thank you so much, sir. Privilege
and you deserve all the love from this
community." Thank you once again, sir.
You inspired me to dedicate more time.
Need to see your pen trick, sir. My
pentric?
Oh, yeah. It's a it's a habit I've I
developed during school and college
days. I'm sitting and thinking and my my
my hands are my fingers are twirling the
pen this way. All right.
Yeah, that's an old habit I have.
Twirling the pen in my fingers.
Thank you very much, Navi. Thank you so
much. Rahul says, "What are your
thoughts on US missile bounce off an
UFO?" Very interesting. Yes, is very
interesting. I saw that I saw that black
and white greenish video. Very
interesting. I think this UFO technology
is mostly Loheed Martin or whatever
technology some American company that
has come up with that has devised very
advanced technology. I don't think it's
alien or extraterrestrial aircraft. I
don't I don't believe that but who knows
anything's possible.
Pret says make a video on chat control
EU online and online safety act. U I'll
have to look into it. I am not sure what
it is. Okay. I I'll consider the
situation. Thank you sir.
Mohit bud says what was the Tamil
insurgency in Sri Lanka impact on global
geopolitics? What could the Indian
leadership at the time have done
differently to manage it? The Tamil
insurgency in Sri Lanka. Look ah that's
a very well
the roots of that go back to the British
occupation of the subcontinent and the
British colonized Sri Lanka also. It was
part of the British Raj and the British
see north of Sri Lanka you have Tamil
Nad we know that right? So the British
made they they they brought a lot of
Tamil speaking people and settled them
in north in the northern part of Sri
Lanka
just like the British took a lot of
Indians and settled them in Burma. That
sort of thing. The British did this all
the time. They they took they started
the process of settling cookies into
Manipur as a punishment for the
Manipuris and that sort of thing. The
British brought in a lot of Tamils and
settled them in northern Sri Lanka. And
obviously there were very ancient
connections between Tamil Nadu and other
other Indian kingdoms and empires and
the kingdoms and kingdoms of Lanka, very
old people-to-people relations. The
people of Lanka are obviously of Indian
origin, right? So anyway um the British
created the situation to to a large
extent and after the independence of Sri
Lanka u
I think there was oppression of the
Tamils by the Sinhalis various Sinhali
governments and that eventually was
weaponized by the west in creating this
this insurgency the LT liberation tigers
of Tamil Ilam and it is it is said that
the LT was a Hindu organization position
but their leadership was always
Christian. Prahakaran and his family you
know top leaders all Christian all
controlled from certain Scandinavian
countries and Scandinavian countries are
vas of the US. You see the connection
there and
impact on global. No, it was about
containing India. It was about
containing India always. And it it cost
India a former prime minister, right?
What could the and that former prime
minister sent the the IPKF to Sri Lanka
which was what
such a bad wrong move. What could the
Indian leadership at the time have done
differently to manage it? what could
they
what could we have done differently? I
think the IPKF was not needed
and uh
yeah I suppose we could have used
diplomatic means or other means to end
the problem. Um we are a much larger and
much more powerful nation. We have the
resources to end this. We have to look
at both sides what they want and u I am
sure we could have used diplomacy to to
end the issue. you know and instead of
that we send the IPKF with without any
clear uh goals.
Okay. Hush says does pursuing a
permanent seat in UN security council
really benefit? No, it does not or is
better to stay away and be independent?
Look the UN security council is cap
captured by the countries there.
Pursuing that status is is a waste of
time. India should instead focus on
pursuing economic and military growth.
That's all we should focus on.
become so powerful that this you know UN
security council seats become completely
immaterial. That's what India needs to
do. Indians are obsessed with status and
that's why they want this this status of
permanent member of the UN security
council to hell with status. Pursue
power.
Kishan Borer says I thought think
tonight in your dreams you'll be seeing
questions being scolded.
Okay. Okay. Thank you. Thank you so much
very much. Yeah, it's been 8 and a half
hours now. Good God. Susan Bhardwad says
souls are of two kinds. New ones are
still learning. So they learn run after
pleasures and wealth. Old ones live
wiser with meaning and purpose. Dharma
says when two people come together a new
soul is formed. Yes sir. I I think I
took this question earlier also. So yeah
very profound statement you're making
sir. Very interesting statement and yeah
it makes sense philosophically from the
philosophical perspective of our
civilization. So thank you sir. Um
Elshin Luhi well thank you so much thank
you thank you okay R says AI can't scale
to human intel because orc o please
elaborate human intelligence
indeterministic which makes machines
inherently in unintelligent orc o
um
or o isn't that u penrose and
hammerhov's theory
penrose and hammerhof have theory,
right? Is it Is that Orc O R? Let me
just quickly Google it.
O R C H O R. That's Yeah. Penrose and
hammer off. Yeah. Yeah. That's that
quantum that that consciousness uh
arises from quantum uh computations
occurring within the brain's
microtubules. Uh what does that have to
do with AI? I'm not really sure. uh but
there are multiple theories that say
that AI can't really scale to human
level intelligence or actually become
self-aware or conscious and Dr. Dr.
Subbash Kak himself has done significant
research on that. He has a paper on that
that came out in the last one or two
years. Uh elaborate about it. Uh I don't
have the details with me right now. I'll
have to once again refresh my memory and
read the at least at least at minimum
the abstracts of the two papers to be
able to tell you. So unfortunately I
can't answer this question in detail
right now. But yeah, very interesting
perspective that you're bringing out.
I'm glad that people are are pursuing
these angles of investigation.
Thoughts on clubbing, culture,
nightlife, etc. Not for me. Not for me.
I've never enjoyed that sort of thing.
Even when I was a what, in my 20s, I
I never visited a nightclub. I never
visited a disco or whatever. It's not
for me. I think it's a waste of human
energy
and all kinds of weird things happen
there, which is well, not something that
I am fond of.
uh sesh kena escape velocity of aging.
Have you been reading my my short story?
So in case you all are not aware of okay
let me remind you before I end this
I am writing a series of short stories
called the mirrors of maya. The mirrors
of maya in which I have
concepts like these. So the first story
is called borrowed time. The link is in
the description. Okay. So, it's about
bringing Indian mythology into the
present day um modern world. We had all
these mythic mythological figures. Who
was Lord Kuber? He was the guardian of
money. He was the he was the the the the
the financer of the gods. It is said.
But what category of divine being was
in? Was he Lord Kubir? He was a yaka.
What is a yaka? Have you completely
forgotten what yaka? What yaka? What the
yakas were? Do they still exist? The
yakas. Who are the Gandharvas? They were
pilots who transported souls between the
inner spaces. Where are the Gandhas
today? What if they are still around us?
Yeah. So that's the kind of imagination
I'm employing and this is the first
story that I've published in it in this
series. It's called borrowed time and it
involves Indian mythology
in the modern era right and the m the uh
the link is in the description and apart
from that I am finally writing books on
black holes I'm serializing
my first book on black holes so two
volumes are out one is dark stars to
black holes the other is the happiest
thought and it is black holes made
accessible to everybody. No scientific
mumbo jumbo, simple explanations
and black holes are fascinating. The
most extreme objects in the universe. So
in case you're interested, please check
it out. The dis the u
the links are in the description. All
right. Saint Crocodile says, "What do
you think is more likely by 2047? We
being a global power, major global
power, or at the mercy of the hands of a
particular community which by then would
have majority. It all depends on the
leadership.
Whatever happens to India by 2047 will
all depend on the kind of leadership we
have between today and 2047.
So I can't say depending on the kind of
people you all elect we all elect this
could happen that could happen anything
could happen. I I can't see the future.
I am not one of those one of those great
geniuses who says okay this is going to
happen in the next two years five years
whatever I can give you probabilistic
estimates of what could happen based on
my best understanding but uh I am
hopeful that we will be a great power by
2047 that's what I would say
difference says which books would you
refer to for Indian history nothing but
if you want me to refer something I
would say read Arsi Mjuddar but very
carefully and with the caveat that these
books were written almost a century ago
and he believes in the colonial
worldview of India the Arian invasion
theory and all that but still great
source of information RC Majunar.
Okay. Tweeting data says wish me happy
birthday Kash. Well Kashish I wish you a
very happy birthday. All the very best
and many happy returns of the day. Thank
you. An thank you very much sir.
Antarana
says it turns out step people like
Santashta did not even have tin bronze
to make swords. They claimed that they
had swords but no physical evidence.
Interesting tin was mined in central
Asia or India. Where was it? I don't
remember right now. Okay. The so the
step people like Sasha did not have tin
bronze to made make swords.
Yeah. So if you claim they had swords
provide the evidence keep quiet, right?
It's as simple as that. Lot of these
these claims that are being made by
so-called experts. They are based on
scholarly consensus which is a group of
people who are shaking hands.
Okay. Without evidence. If you make a
claim, you have to provide evidence
otherwise you have to keep quiet. But
there's no evidence.
So you're right sir. An says your
thoughts on NHS Oak dating Rig to 20,000
plus BC. I don't know sir. I haven't
read his research. See there's I have
limited time and I would like to read so
much and learn so much but I haven't
since I'm I'm right now engaged in
writing which takes so much of my time
and before that I was doing other
things. I simply haven't had the time to
read so much of this research that has
come out of late. So I haven't see I
will not comment on a claim until I read
it in detail the the the the logic the
justification the calculations that went
into it without that who am I to make
make uh pass any judgment so I haven't
read his research so I can't really say
anything about it without doing
without see if you don't read the
details but you pass judgment you are
being super disrespectful and that is
not a good thing. So I would I would
never do that.
Kajor Bathon says Sid Gupta's question.
How did Putin free Russia after it was
broken, compromised and turned into a
western puppet? See, Russia was broken
and compromised
in the 1990s.
First of all, the USSR disintegrated.
Gorbachov
did a Pizza Hut or something ad after
that.
And then we have Yelson, Boris Yelson,
the drunk guy, he sold off the Russian
economy to various oligarchs.
So the USSR was a totalitarian and
collectivist nation, which means that
the entire savings of many generations
of Russians were in the hands of the
USSR's government because there was no
private property. So all the savings of
70 80 years of the hard work of the
people was in the hands of the Russian
government after the break up of the
USSR and Boris Yelson gave it away to
oligarchs to fitter it away and waste
it. He destroyed Russia's 80 years of
savings. Boris Yelson he was a western
stoogge. So Russia was broken by the
time Putin came to came to power and
Putin step by step year by year through
hard work has rebuilt everything.
It's still not at the level of the USSR
not even close but today Russia is is
Russia matters. 20 years ago Russia was
nowhere. So that is what Putin has
achieved. Okay I need to end this. U
Russia invaded Ukraine illegally. So how
you invade country legally?
There is no legal or illegal invasion.
There's no legalities in war. War is
totally you're putting laws aside.
That's where war is that
there is no legality or illegality of
invasion or in in war. Okay. So these
laws and all they don't apply. Okay. I
will I will go to war with you legally.
Let us first go to I mean is that how it
works? Has any war happened legally or
has any invasion happened legally? It
doesn't happen like that. The dark
knight says I took a nap and woke up.
obviously going on. Salute to you. Well,
thank you so much, sir. I'm going to end
in the next 5 minutes. Thank you, sir.
Shankar is a new member. Thank you very
much, sir. I really appreciate that.
Thank you. Okay. Project Smiling Buddha,
huge respect. Well, thank you so much. I
really appreciate that, sir. Vs says,
"Net subashindra Bose and Leewan, you
were political pragmatists despite their
political leanings. How does this
political pragmatism work? By being
realistic,
by not being
overly attached to one way of doing
things, by being attached to the
objectives and goals, not the process.
The Chinese have a proverb.
It does not matter whether the cat is
black or white as long as it catches
mice. That is called pragmatism. All
right.
Roshi Jooshi says hello again. Well,
thank you. Hello. What's the best
strategy to hide our capabilities and b
our time especially in the current
scenario versus the US with respect to
the US? Just keep your mouth shut.
That's it. We have ministers who like to
boast
that we negotiated hard with that nation
and we showed them that we are a greater
power. Why boast of this?
Keep quiet.
No big statements.
Stay humble to humility.
Don't talk about how wonderful we are,
how great we are. You can talk about
that in the historical domain. When
you're discussing history when we're
talking about the nation's growth and
progress, you keep quiet. You don't make
big statements. You just keep on doing
the work. That is the meaning of hiding
your capabilities and biting your time.
Don't start flaunting everything and
dancing from the rooftop and doing ba
that we have four trillion dollar
economy. Keep quiet. It's not 40, it's
four. Quiet.
Okay.
Wish Kalam says number one superpower by
2047 sir. Not just a great power. Well
upshak like they say. Okay. Thank you. I
really appreciate that and I hope that
what you say comes true.
Ladies and gentlemen, I have run out of
super chats. I am done for today. 8
hours 45 minutes. I think for me it's a
world record. Okay. So I'm going to end
it here now. I I had my intention was to
stop at 8 hours. I have taken it 8 hours
45 minutes. I have to stop now otherwise
tomorrow I won't have any voice left. So
thank you everybody. Thank you so much
for being on the live stream. I
appreciate all of you. You have no idea
how much I do and I look forward to
seeing you in the next live stream.
Thank you so much everyone. Have a good
day, good night, wherever you are. And
I'll see you soon. Take care. Bye-bye.